(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.2",
"generated_at": "2026-09-09T23:01:21.582609",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.6-flash",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
あ、開けた！開けた開けた！
Ah, it opened! Opened it, opened it!
開けた開けた！開いた！よし！
Opened it, opened it! It opened! Sweet!
今開けた！今開けた！今開けた！今開けた！
I just opened it! I opened it just now!
何？その開け方…
What is with that way of opening it...?
服作ったけど… ぬるっ
I made clothes, but... so smooth.
ぬるって開けたやん
It opened so smoothly!
スイッ… スイッと
Swiftly... swiftly.
じゃあーの！
Now then!
はい！
Yes!
朝の前に集合！集合！
Gather before the morning meeting! Gather!
はい！はい！
Yes! Yes!
集合しました！集合しました！
We've gathered! We've gathered!
よーし、じゃこれから朝礼を始めます！
All right, let me start the morning meeting now!
はい！お願いします！
Yes! Go ahead, please!
おはようございます！
Good morning!
昨日も一晩お疲れ様でした！
Thank you for all your hard work overnight yesterday too!
お疲れ様でしたー！
Good job everyone!
今日はですね、ちょっと昨日は至らなかったんですけど、ちょっと「やることリスト」なるものを作らせていただきましたので、
Today, though I wasn't able to get to it yesterday, I prepared a "To-Do List"...
おー！素晴らしい！
Ooh! Wonderful!
役割を振りつつ、頑張っていきたいと思います！
So I'd like us to hand out roles and do our best!
よろしくお願いします！
We're counting on you!
抜け自由、体調悪かったら配信落ちて大丈夫、みんな勝手なんで。タムスクや今書ー？
Feel free to leave whenever or drop off if you feel unwell, everyone is free to do as they wish.
はい！
Yes!
おーい！おーい！
Hey! Hey!
これよ、これよ！
This, this!
デイリー報酬？これなに？
Daily rewards? What's this?
開けてくださいよ！リーダー！
Open it up, Leader!
樽を密閉されています。長押しで樽を…開け、はい。
The barrel is sealed. Press and hold to... open the barrel, okay.
はい。
Okay.
マインドワイプトニック…
Mindwipe Tonic...
は？何それ？
Huh? What's that?
すげーカタコトだったな今ｗ
That sounded so broken just now, lol.
ね、長押しで開封。
Yeah, hold to unseal.
なに？
What is it?
うわ！こっち左側ですね、職人レベルの…
Whoa! Over here on the left, it's Journeyman tier...
うん。ギリ…ギロ系装備が入ってる！
Yeah. Ghillie... Ghillie gear is inside!
おー！ギリ！
Ooh! Ghillie!
欲しかった欲しかった！
I wanted this so bad!
ユニコーンを見つけてね、テイムして欲しいなと。
I'd like someone to find a unicorn and tame it.
ギリズボンもある！ギリズボンあります！
There are Ghillie leggings too! Ghillie leggings!
なんでじゃここかな？
So maybe over here?
あ、これ皆さん開けられますよね？解封はしたから開けられる…
Ah, everyone can open this, right? Since I unsealed it...
たぶん開けられる。あ、開けられる開けられる！おー！
Probably. Ah, we can open it! Ooh!
おー！これじゃあみんなこれを今日着てやっていく感じになるかなと思います。
Ooh! So I think everyone will wear this for today's work.
はーい！
Yeees!
どれやどれや？
Which one, which one?
うしょ！ギリ！うしょー！ギリ！
No way! Ghillie! No way, Ghillie!
ガントレット！靴！頭！
Gauntlets! Boots! Helmet!
マインドなんちゃらってやつは、なんかステ振りができるアイテムらしいので、
The Mind-whatever item is for resetting stat points,
入って右奥のロッカーの中に入れておきます。なんか紫色の粉みたいなやつです。
so I'll put it in the locker in the far right. It looks like purple powder or something.
はーい！
Okay!
全身ヤバい！全身ヤバい！みんなゴミ箱感やで！
Full body looks crazy! Everyone looks like a trash bin!
私は木！ゴミ箱感ｗｗ
I'm a tree! Trash bin look, lol.
ゴミ箱感だー！本当だー！可愛いー！
Total trash bin look! It really is! Cute!
ゴミ箱感だー！可愛いか…？
Trash bin look! Is that cute...?
割り振りなどをちょっと発表ドラゴンさせてください！
Let me make a Dragon Announcement for the role assignments!
はい、お願いします！
Yes, please!
発表ドラゴンが～
The Announcement Dragon is~
本日はですね…えっとですね、
Today... well,
さっき個別で、個別というかグループチャットに送った「片付けできるもん.exe」みたいなやつを開いてもらったら、大体やりたいことみんな書いてもらったんで、
if you open that "cleanup-dekirumon.exe" file I sent in the group chat, everyone wrote down what they wanted to do,
まず、えっと…原油集めチームミッションをやる方！と、
so first, those on the crude oil collection team mission! And,
昨日アルゲンをテイム出来たので、キチン・ケラチンを大量に集めていただき、サドルを作る方！
since we tamed an Argentavis yesterday, those who will gather tons of chitin/keratin and craft saddles!
はい！
Yes!
と、あとはちょっと恐竜が多くなってきたので、あのカリカリ拠点に石の恐竜ビッグキャッスルを建てる方！
And, since we have many dinosaurs now, those who will build a big stone dino castle at the temporary base!
はい！はい！
Yes! Yes!
と、プラスそこの方は…えっと、なんだっけ、ブリーディングをやりつつ、ちょっとアルゲンを増やしたいと思っております！
Plus, those over there... um, doing breeding while trying to breed more Argentavis!
はい！
Yes!
はいはい！
Okay, okay!
えーっと、一旦仮拠点とブリーディング、アルゲン無限編は、ござるとイナ先輩で請け負います！
Umm, for now, the temporary base, breeding, and infinite Argentavis arc will be handled by Gozaru and Ina-senpai!
はい！
Yes!
キチン・ケラチンの場所が分かるのがフブキ先輩！
Fubuki-senpai knows where to find Chitin and Keratin!
はい、じゃあ、ボイチャについていきます。
Okay, then I'll follow the voice chat.
はい、しろいくぞ。
Okay, let's follow Shiro.
そしたら、トワ先輩が昨日、なんかやりたいって言ってた、何でしたっけ？原油？
So Towa-senpai mentioned yesterday she wanted to do something... what was it again? Crude oil?
原油じゃないな、なんだっけ？あ、常闇はね、真珠と原油ポンプ担当いたしますよ。
Not crude oil, what was it? Ah, Tokoyami will handle pearls and crude oil pumps!
あ、お願いします。確か、ぺこちゃんがいっぱい荷物持てるって聞いて。
Oh, please do! I heard Pekora-chan can carry a lot of items...
そう、ぺこちゃんが持てるんだ。いってきますよ、もういいですか？
Yeah, Pekora-chan can carry them. We're heading off, is everyone ready?
じゃあ、各々ボイチャ...
So, everyone in voice chat...
本日、よろしくお願いします！
Thank you for today!
よろしくお願いします！
Thank you!
じゃあ、ボイチャ2に行くか。
Should we move to voice chat 2?
ボイチャ2ね。じゃ、イナ先輩、このままで、こっちに一緒に行きましょう。
Voice chat 2, right. Then Ina-senpai, let me follow you over here.
はい。
Okay.
よし。あ、トワだ、トワだったけど、まあ...
Alright. Ah, it was Towa, but well...
トワ先輩も無事そこに仲間に入れてくれるのであれば...
If Towa-senpai welcomes us over there...
ゴザル、鮮度が怖くてギリースーツを置いていく人です。
Gozaru is scared of how realistic it looks, so she leaves her ghillie suit behind.
そうですね！
That's true!
こ、怖い！怖すぎる！
I-It's scary! Way too scary!
わたしも、なん、安全な場所に来よう...
I should also move to a safe place...
怖いですよね、あれ。
That's scary, isn't it?
よし、じゃあちょっと、昨日のあれ...
Alright, then about yesterday's...
え、で、なんかイナ先輩、どうやらアルゲンを... あ、待って、もう一回テレポートします。すみません、えーっと...
So, Ina-senpai, apparently the Argent... Ah wait, I'll teleport one more time. Sorry, um...
アルゲンを、昨日捕まえたんじゃないですか？
Didn't you capture an Argent yesterday?
はい。
Yes.
それをね、増やしつつ、なんかアルゲンを5体倒すっていうミッションがあるらしくて...
While breeding it, apparently there's a mission to defeat 5 Argents...
もしかして、うちのアルゲンを...
Don't tell me... our Argent...
ま、産んで... 殺せばすむ話じゃないか...
Well... couldn't we just breed and kill them?
じゃないかな？
Right?
うちでやってしまえば...
If we just do it ourselves...
1体でいいからって...
"Since we only need one..."
って思って、なんで今日なんですけど...
I thought. So for today...
はい。
Yes.
一番最初に、昨日みたいにあそこでアルゲンを、テイムしつつ...
First, like yesterday, while taming Argents over there...
あっちでアルゲンのブリーディングを同時にしようと思って。
I thought we could do Argent breeding over there at the same time.
あー、いいですね！
Ah, that sounds good!
ね、なんで昨日で言うと...
Yeah, so speaking of yesterday...
待って、プテラはまだ今手元にありますか？
Wait, do you still have the Pteranodon on hand?
えーっと...
Um...
あのー、ここですし、よ、ね？たぶん昨日入れた... あれ？
Um, it's here, right? Maybe I put it in yesterday... Huh?
あ、そうそうそう。昨日入れたのはね、ここだと思う。
Ah, yes yes yes. I think I put it here yesterday.
左のところ...
The spot on the left...
なんか居ます？このハウス...
Is there something inside this house?
ここに...
In here...
アルジェント入れてない？もしかして。
Wait, didn't you put the Argent in? Could it be?
ないです。
No, I didn't.
あ、じゃあ、じゃあ...
Ah, then, then...
これ何だっけ？
What was this again?
まだ誰かが持ってログアウトしてる気が...
I feel like someone is still logged out holding it...
あー、なるほど。
Ah, I see.
可能性ありなので...
That's a possibility, so...
これはアンキロか。あ、じゃあこれだ。
Is this an Ankylo? Ah, then it's this one.
じゃ、これに、今日はイナ先輩に...
Then on this one, today I'll have Ina-senpai...
アタックZEROに乗ってもらって...
Ride Attack ZERO...
アタックZEROに乗ってもらって、昨日みたいにやりつつ...
Ride Attack ZERO, and while doing things like yesterday...
はい！
Yes!
向こうでブリーディングもしよう。
Let's also do breeding over there.
はい！
Yes!
なんでちょっとだけ木とかが必要なのかな？石の土台とか作りたいな。
So maybe we need a little bit of wood? I'd like to build stone foundations.
ちょっとお待ちください。石、石...
Please wait a moment. Stone, stone...
これも整理しなきゃな。
I need to organize this too.
ギリちょっと怖いので、ここに... 入れておくかな。
The ghillie suit is a bit scary, so I'll put it in here.
確かに。いや、分かる、めっちゃ怖いですよね、あれね。
Indeed. No, I get it, that's super scary, right?
じゃ、ここ... これに... 着替えて...
So, here... into this... I'll change...
では... イナのギリはここに...
Now then... Ina's ghillie suit goes here...
えーっと、スッタックを半分に分けて...
Um, split the stack in half...
はい。
Okay.
はい！そしたら...
Yes! Then...
これ作っちゃ... 行きましょう！この...
I'll craft this... Let me go! On this...
アタックZEROに乗ってもらっていいですか？
Could you ride Attack ZERO?
はい！
Yes!
で、今日先輩たちが、おそらくアルゲンを捕まえてきてくれるので...
And today, our senpais will probably capture Argents for us...
アルゲンね、アルゲンのサドル用に...
For the Argent, for the Argent's saddle...
はい。
Yes.
きちんキチン、ケラチンを... それを使って色々やりましょう。
Chitin and keratin... Let me use those and do various things.
よいせ、よいせ。
Yoisho, yoisho.
え、私が走っても大丈夫ですよ。
Eh, it's fine even if I run.
全然全然！ゴザルの場所を覚えてるから... ただクマ居るから気をつけて。
No, not at all! I remember Gozaru's location... but watch out, there are bears.
あった、あった。
There it is, there it is.
え、待って、なんか近くにでっかい... あ、でもあれ草食か？あれ草食だな。
Wait, there's a huge... ah, but is that a herbivore? That's a herbivore.
あ、でっかい。
Ah, it's huge.
なんか... お魚っぽい。
Looks like... kind of like a fish.
お魚っぽい？確かに。平、平たい。
Fish-like? True. It's flat, flat-shaped.
じゃ、ここで...
So, over here...
臣民を...
the followers...
卵をまず生まなきゃいけないから
First, they have to lay eggs,
ちょっとブリーディング用の簡易施設を作りたくて、まず
so I want to build a simple breeding facility first.
はい
Yes.
石の壁...
Stone walls...
石の土台...
Stone foundations...
でもめっちゃ気のいいイナ先輩が取ってくれたから、素材はウチは今のところ潤沢に、あ、あるはず
But super kind Ina-senpai gathered materials for me, so we should have plenty for now.
必要だったらいきますので
If you need anything, I can go get it!
助かるー！
That helps so much!
え、じゃ、焚き火作っ...焚き...あ、たいまつだっけ？焚き火、焚き火作ってもらっていいですか？
Um, could you make a campfire for me?
焚き火？
A campfire?
焚き火。はい、キャンプファイアっていう...
Campfire. Yes, the one called "Campfire"...
あー
Ah...
英語がザコくてごめん...
Sorry my English is so bad...
あ、なんか
Ah, wait...
え、なんか気絶...あ、ヤバい、また水が...
Wait, knocked out?! Oh no, my water again...
大丈夫？
Are you okay?
お水飲んでなくて気絶しちゃった
I passed out because I didn't drink water...
ああ、大丈夫ですか！？大丈夫、大丈夫...
Ah, are you okay?! Don't worry, don't worry...
倒れ...倒れ...倒れ伏せば...
If I... if I collapse...
あ、なんかそのうち起きて起きて
Ah, I'll wake up eventually... wake up, wake up...
意外と...
Surprisingly...
あとご飯入れとかなきゃ
Also, I need to put food in.
水筒いっぱい作んなきゃ...え、イナ先輩この中にね
I need to make lots of waterskins... Ah, Ina-senpai, inside here...
はい
Yes.
このご飯をパック半分にして入れとくんで、これ今日のご飯として...
I'll split this food in half and put it in, so for today's food...
あ、ご飯はいっぱい...あ、いや、もう...
Ah, food, I have plenty... Ah, no, already...
多分腐っちゃったんじゃないかな
Maybe it got spoiled?
腐っ...
Spoiled...
かも...
maybe...
腐った...
Spoiled...
かも？
maybe?
あ、なんか、ちょっと戻って、水と...あの、木と、ちょっと持って来ます。
Ah, I'll go back for a bit and bring water and wood.
確かに水筒を持ってきてもらえると大変助かります！
It would be super helpful if you could bring waterskins!
じゃあ、行ってきます！
Alright, I'll be right back!
はーい、じゃ、こっちで今ブリーディング施設を作りますね、これから。
Okay~ Then I'll start building the breeding facility over here now.
天井、天井...まず...
Ceilings, ceilings... First...
人間は脆い
Humans are fragile.
人間だ...体が弱すぎる...
Humans... Their bodies are way too weak...
あまりにも...
So fragile...
ですよね！
Right?!
こいつらの体が弱い！
Their bodies are so weak!
水筒みたいなのね、水筒にしか頼れないからな。
Things like waterskins... we can only rely on waterskins.
人は脆い...
Humans are fragile...
おいしゃ、おいしゃ
Up we go, up we go.
天井って4つで1個なの？
Are ceilings 1 set for 4?
あ、ここにありました、あの、キャリー...
Ah, it was here, the carry...
あ、いた！
Ah, found it!
はい
Yes.
誰かが入れてありました
Someone put it in.
連れてきて致...うちのアタック、アタックゼロ...
Bringing them over... Our Attack, Attack Zero...
アタックゼロと、キバ...
Attack Zero and Kiba...
アタックゼロ何卒よろしくお願いします
Please take good care of Attack Zero.
あ、いっぱい...
Ah, so much...
ちょっとあまりにも牢獄みたいな見た目してるけど大丈夫かなこれ？
It looks way too much like a prison, is this okay?
大丈夫ですよ！
It's totally fine!
行けるから...すごい牢獄みたいな見た目になっちゃった！
We can make it work... It ended up looking like a total prison!
あまりにもちょっと...
It's just a bit...
さすがにバッドか...さすがにダメか、これ...
Is this really bad...? Is this no good...?
全然大丈夫ですよ
It's totally fine!
だよね...
Right...?
ちょっと...
A bit...
性能重視...じゃない
Performance focused... right?
見ためじゃない、性能なんだ！
It's not about looks, it's about functionality!
見ためじゃないですよね、イナ先輩！
It's not about looks, right, Ina-senpai?
そうそうそう
Yeah, yeah, yeah!
よかった、イナ先輩...
Thank goodness, Ina-senpai...
心が広い人だ、助かる。
You're so open-minded, that helps!
よし、じゃ、これで焚き火を...
Alright, now with this, the campfire...
え、え、え、何何何何？
Eh, eh, eh, what, what, what, what?
何何何？ 中居る？
What, what, what? Is something inside?
なんかめちゃでかいやつが...
Something super huge is...
え、え、え？
Eh, eh, eh?
逃げて逃げて逃げて！
Run, run, run!
大丈夫？
Are you okay?
あ、アタックゼロが！
Ah, Attack Zero is...!
戦っちゃった？
Did it start fighting?
フォロー、フォロー、フォロー！
Follow, follow, follow!
フォロー！
Follow!
大丈夫？
Are you okay?
大丈夫かな...
Is it gonna be okay...?
どこから来た... いていていて！
Where did it come from...? Ouch, ouch, ouch!
アタックゼロどこ？ マジで。
Where is Attack Zero, seriously?
あんたは何をやって...
What are you doing...
いていていて！
Ouch, ouch, ouch!
あーー！
Aaah!
うわ、やっべ！
Wow, oh crap!
見えなかった！
I couldn't see it!
どこから来た...
Where did it come from...
アタックゼロどこ？
Where is Attack Zero?
ちょっと飛んだ感... え、ここどこ？
Feels like I was blown far... Wait, where is this?
あ、なんか...
Ah, well...
アタックゼロ多分回収でき...
Attack Zero can probably be retrieved...
大丈夫ですか？
Are you okay?
え、ここどこ？
Eh, where is this?
やばい、ヨシドンが戦っちゃってんな、これ。ちょっと待って。
Oh no, Yoshidon is fighting right now. Hold on a second.
ヨシドン！ ちょ、ちょ、ちょ...
Yoshidon! Wait, wait, wait...
あれ？ ちょっとこっち来て、こっち。
Huh? Come over here, this way.
ヨシドン！
Yoshidon!
来てー。
Come here~
待って。
Wait.
ちょっと待って。
Hold on a second.
あれ？ ヨシドンどこ行ったあいつ？ あ、居った。
Huh? Where did Yoshidon go? Ah, there he is.
ちょ、ちょ、ちょ、ヨシドン来て。
Wait, wait, wait, Yoshidon, come here.
居た、居た、居た、居た！
There he is, there he is!
ヨシドンおいで。よし。
Yoshidon, come here. Alright.
めっちゃ遠い場所に...
To such a far away place...
いや、アタックゼロがどこ行ったか分からないけど、ヨシドンを保護します。
I don't know where Attack Zero went, but I'll protect Yoshidon.
あれ？
Huh?
拠点がおそ... 襲われてしまった...
The base was... was attacked...
ちょっと待って。
Hold on a second.
ヨシドン、着地してー。
Yoshidon, land please~
何で2回...
Why twice...
ここどこーー？
Where is this place--?
大丈夫ーー？
Are you okay--?
めっちゃ遠い場所に...
To such a far away place...
あ、周会場に戻って来てくれたら...
Ah, if you can make it back to the assembly area...
行ける... 行けるかどうか分からない。
I don't know... I don't know if I can make it or not.
何？ ちょっと待って。
What? Hold on a second.
いや、ここで死んでもさ、あの... アイテムは...
Even if I die here, um... the items...
まだ死んだ場所にあるんですよね？
are still at the place I died, right?
そうそうそう、あるある。けどね、ドラゴンくらいかな。やばい、ここやばいな。
Yeah, yeah, yeah, they're there. But maybe about Dragon... Oh man, this place is bad.
じゃあ死んでもいいかも。なんか別の...
Then maybe it's fine to die. Like a different...
島に...
island...
別の島に居る！ やばい、ちょっと待って、こいつを...
I'm on a different island! Oh no, wait, this guy...
じゃあ...
Then...
引き離しチーム！
Distraction team!
おらぁ！
Oraah!
あ、綺麗に4人が...
Ah, all four are nicely...
チェイスしてくれてる。
chasing me.
よしよしよし、これで...
Alright, alright, with this...
え、誰か死んだ？
Eh, did someone die?
あ、ござるござる。え、でも全然平気。これね、ちょっと...
Ah, Gozaru, Gozaru. Eh, but I'm totally fine. This...
ベッドでリスポーンして...
respawn at a bed...
戻って来ちゃった？
Did they come back?
うわー！
Uwaaa!
旋盤がー！
The lathe...!
ちょっと待って、壊されちゃった...
Wait a second, it got destroyed...
あ、ここか。
Ah, here?
シンプルベッド...
Simple bed...
旋盤が... 旋盤が...
The lathe... The lathe...
あ、シンプルベッドで... ああ、良かった！
Ah, at the simple bed... Ah, thank goodness!
なんか別のところに居させられて...
I was put somewhere else...
あ、良かった。
Ah, thank goodness.
じゃあ、ちょっと1回旋盤が壊れちゃったんで...
Well, since the lathe got destroyed once...
ちょっと下に行って来ますね。 / はい。
I'll go down below for a bit. / Okay.
え、あそこって... 誰かめっちゃ戦ってる？
Eh, over there... is someone fighting like crazy?
え、アイテムどこかな？ この辺...
Eh, where are the items? Around here...
だと思うけど...
I think, but...
あ、いや、こっちじゃない。
Ah, no, not here.
あ、これか！
Ah, this one!
あー良かった！
Ah, thank goodness!
良かったー。
Thank goodness~
やー、怖い。
Man, that's scary.
お、戦ってる。
Oh, they're fighting.
えっと
Um...
あー！ なー！
Ah! No!
大丈夫かな… 戦う？
I wonder if it's okay... Will it fight?
え、見ないで！ 私見ないで！ 頼むから！
Don't look! Don't look at me! I'm begging you!
見た？ 見たー！
Did it see? It saw!
なんでー！
Why?!
戦ってる…
They're fighting...
怖い… 怖いよ… 怖いよ…
Scary... I'm scared... I'm scared...
どうする… 手伝う？
What should I do... help out?
I am... I am... I am tree... 怖い…
I am... I am... I am tree... Scary...
大丈夫かな…
I wonder if it's okay...
イナ先輩！ 大丈夫？ 拠点大ピンチすぎて…
Ina-senpai! Are you okay? Our base is in a huge pinch...
今ね 全力で拠点からあのでけぇやつを離そうと頑張ってる最中です
Right now, I'm trying my absolute best to lure that huge thing away from our base.
はい 私も… みんなで… 奴 だいぶ飛んでるで…
Yes, me too... Everyone together... That guy is flying quite far away...
ね 飛んでった？
Yeah, did it fly away?
じゃ OK！
Then, okay!
行こう！
Let's go!
やばい これ草食動物に逸れてんのか これ？
Oh no, is it getting distracted by herbivores?
アムム こっち来てくれ！
Amumu, come over here!
てつくレ… なんか違うやつ来た！
Give me... Wait, a different one came!
お前じゃないねん！
You're not the one!
テラバーキ来ちゃったー！
Terabaki came!
あ でもだいぶ行ったか？
Ah, but did it go quite far?
大丈夫ですか？
Are you okay?
今違うね 弱い弱い動物をこう餌に連れてきてみたんだけど…
Right now, I tried bringing weak animals as bait, but...
違うの連れちゃった… シンプルベットに…
I ended up pulling the wrong one... to the simple bed...
誰やねーん！
Who the heck are you?!
大丈夫ですかね？
I wonder if it's okay?
大丈夫か… あ でも結構上まで連れてってくれた！ - よかったー！
Is it okay... Ah, but it pulled it pretty far up! - Thank goodness!
本当びっくりした なんか… - びっくりしたよね 流石に
I was really surprised... - Yeah, that really surprised us, for real.
結構上まで連れてってくれたっぽいな
Looks like it took it pretty far up for us.
これ旋盤の中身とか消えた？ - あ 旋盤の中身はですね…
Did the items in the fabricator disappear? - Ah, as for the items in the fabricator...
左の1個だけ孤立してるチェストに入れておきます - あ ありがたい！ 了解！
I'll put them in that isolated chest on the left. - Ah, thank you! Got it!
入り切る分が一旦入ってます そこに - あ 了解！ お願いします！ - はいよ！
Whatever fits is in there for now. - Got it! Please do! - Sure thing!
よし じゃあこれで ちょっとプテラを1匹失ったんですけど…
Alright, so with this, we lost one Pteranodon, but...
その代わりにプテラ さっき1匹保護できたので… - はい
Instead, we were able to rescue one Pteranodon earlier, so... - Yes.
そいつを使ってやりましょう
Let's use that one.
そしたら イナ先輩 歩きでめっちゃ申し訳ないんですけど さっきのところ戻って…
So, Ina-senpai, I'm really sorry you have to walk, but if you could head back to where we were earlier...
なんかプテラ乗ってんのか？
Is someone riding a Pteranodon?
私のプテラ使ってください！
Please use my Pteranodon!
あ、痛い痛い痛い！
Ah, ouch, ouch, ouch!
あとね、もう1匹ね、プテラなんか多分その辺で捕まえれば大丈夫です。
Also, for another Pteranodon, we can probably just catch one around here.
1匹、生きてる...元気？その子、その子が元気だったら一番...
If one is alive... is it okay? If that one is doing fine, then...
その子が元気なのが一番助かります。
It helps the most if that one is doing fine.
はい。
Okay.
よし、じゃあさっきのところ、ちょっと集合で。
Alright, let's gather at that spot from earlier.
何が必要だっけ？えっと...
What did I need again? Let's see...
でも良かった、イナ先輩のプテラが見つかったのナイッスです。
But I'm glad Ina-senpai's Pteranodon was found, nice!
はい。
Yes!
いや、びっくりした！
Man, that scared me!
いや、びっくりした！マジでびっ...あ？
I know, right! I was really sca-- Huh?
なんか平和で...
It's so peaceful...
待って待って、なんかいる。
Wait, wait, there's something there.
何だろう？
What is it?
わ！キチン、ケラチンだ！お前、キチン、ケラチンだろ！
Wow, chitin and keratin! You've got chitin and keratin!
え？
Huh?
なんか恐竜出したいんだけど...あ、来た来た来た。
I want to pull out a dino... Ah, here it comes.
来た！キチン、ケラチン発見！
Got it! Chitin and keratin, found!
おー！
Ooh!
飛んできた、キチン、ケラチンが。
They flew right to me, the chitin and keratin.
ケラチン飛んできた、嬉しい！
Keratin flew right over, I'm so happy!
おー！
Wow!
追いてけ！追いてけ追いてけ...
Leave them behind! Leave them behind...
大丈夫か？
Are you okay?
あ、なんとか！あの、拠点の近くにでかいやつの肉食が来ちゃって...
Ah, somehow! A huge carnivore came near our base...
めちゃくちゃいるや、あいつどうする？
There are so many of them, what do we do about that guy?
どうします？
What should we do?
あ、ちょっとおっぱらうわ。ちょっと待っててね。
Ah, wait, I'll drive it away. Wait a sec.
うん、なんかでかい罠作ってはめてもいいかなって思ってた。
Yeah, I was thinking maybe we could build a big trap and catch it.
大丈夫、トワがね、引き寄せておくわ。
Don't worry, Towa will lure it away.
ありがとうございます。
Thank you so much!
じゃあイナ先輩、こっちでやりましょう。で、ミッション...
So Ina-senpai, let's do it over here. And, the mission...
来た来た来た来た！
Here it comes, here it comes!
149か、虫がいたら刈ったらいい。
Level 149, huh? If there are bugs, we should kill them.
おーい、こっちこーい！
Hey, come over here!
で、ここで...
And here...
おーい！
Hey!
来た来た来た来た！
Here it comes, here it comes!
え、何？2匹いて草！
Wait, what? There are two of them, lol!
2匹いて草！
There are two of them, lol!
やばすぎ！
That's crazy!
命大事にね。
Value your life, okay?
2匹笑った！
Two of them is hilarious!
なんや2匹って！
What do you mean two?!
じゃん！
Ta-da!
いや3匹ー！すっごい、狩り拠点が出来まして...
Wait, THREE of them?! Wow, we made a hunting base...
あの早くこっち...あ、こっち来て。こいつ...
Um, come over here quickly... Ah, come over here. This guy...
この虫がケラチンなの？
Does this bug give keratin?
あ、そう！虫殺すとケラチン...
Ah, yeah! If you kill bugs, you get keratin...
いらんでこいつら、ふざけんなこいつら！
We don't need these guys, don't mess with me!
ね、なんか、え？ねぇねぇねぇ、イナ先輩、イナ先輩！
Hey, wait, what? Hey, Ina-senpai, Ina-senpai!
なになに？
What is it?
あそこあそこあそこ！あそこなんかアルゲンいる！あ、あいついっぺん捕まえたって良くない、あれ？
Over there, over there! There's an Argentavis over there! Wouldn't it be good if we caught that one?
ですね！
True!
行きます？
Shall we go?
レッツチェイス、レッツチェイス！
Let's chase, let's chase!
オッケーオッケーオッケー！
Okay, okay, okay!
おーい！
Hoooy!
じゃ、レッツゴーレッツゴー！行きまーす！
Alright, let's go, let's go! / Here I go!
あーい！
Aaay!
来よー！
Come on!
あーい！
Aaay!
お前が挟まるんかい！くそ、こいつ邪魔すぎる！
Why are YOU getting stuck?! Damn, this guy is so in the way!
なんでやねん！今トワが罠作ったのにー！もうなんでだー！
Why?! Towa made a trap just now! Why is this happening?!
行きます！
Here I go!
レッツゴーレッツゴー！カモンカモン！
Let's go, let's go! Come on, come on!
おーおーおー！
Oh, oh, oh!
レッツゴー！
Let's go!
本当にすごいとこだ、ここ！
This place is really amazing!
ナイスー！
Nice--!
ま、ちょっと離れたからもういいでしょう。
Well, we've gotten some distance, so it should be fine now.
ありがとうございます！
Thank you so much!
ま、ちょっとだけね。また来たらおっぱらうわ。
Well, just a bit. If it comes again, I'll chase it off.
助かります。
That helps a lot.
で、私のは...えっと...
And as for me... um...
顔見て！
Look at its face!
こっち見て！
Look over here!
ここ見て！
Look here!
顔！
Face!
やったー、ナイッス！
Yay, nice!
ご飯...
Food...
ナイッス！
Nice!
よし。
All right.
オッケーオッケー。そしたら、この...あ！
Okay, okay. So then, this... Ah!
あ、お！こいつこいつこいつ！これこれこれ！斧でこうやってやるとね...
Ah, this one, this one! If you hit it with an axe like this...
弱い、こいつは。
This guy is weak.
で、これで...あれ？
And with this... Huh?
待って、旋盤ってどこ行った？
Wait, where did the fabricator go?
旋盤が破壊されたんです、奴に！
The fabricator was destroyed by that beast!
オッケー。
Okay.
そうなんです...悲しみ...
Yes... How sad...
あ、で、中身は左の倉庫っていうか、チェストに全部入れてあります。
Ah, and the contents are all in the left storage, in the chest.
オッケー。
Okay.
苦しい...ごめんなさい...
It hurts... I'm sorry...
守れなくて...
I couldn't protect it...
こいつと、水晶、原油...
This, crystal, crude oil...
ここインゴットとセメント...
Here are the ingots and cement...
なるほど
I see.
すっごい...
Wow...
えっと... すっご...
Let's see... Wow...
よし、来た！交配レッツゴー！
Alright, it's here! Let's go with breeding!
おお！
Woah!
おお！卵！卵来た！え、それを回収して...
Woah! An egg! An egg came out! Wait, collect that...
拾った... あ、そうそう！このモヤモヤのやつ！イナ先輩、これ拾ってきて...
Picked it up... Ah, right, right! The glowing one! Ina-senpai, pick that up...
はい
Okay.
で、これで... この、ちょっと一酸化炭素中毒になりそうな場所すぎるんですけど...
And with this... this place seems a bit too likely to cause carbon monoxide poisoning, but...
ここで...
Here...
あ、はいはいはいはい
Ah, right, right, right, right.
え、狭いか？もしかして狭い？
Wait, is it too narrow? Maybe it's too cramped?
多分この中に入れたら多分... この中どっか適当にポンって置いたら...
If we put it in here, maybe... if we just pop it down somewhere in here...
あったかくなるんじゃないかな...
I think it'll warm up...
ここでドロップ...
Drop it here...
あ、ドロップ
Ah, drop.
おお！
Woah!
おおー！
Woah~!
卵燃えてる！見た目的に！
The egg is on fire! Visually!
なんか美味しい匂いが... ん？
It smells kind of delicious... Huh?
美味しい匂いが... え、熱いって言われた
Smells delicious... Wait, it says "too hot".
嫌だー！
Oh no!
え、待って...
Wait, hold on...
熱いって言われた、ちょっと待って
It says "too hot", wait a second.
この中ならだけでいいのでは？ひょっとして
Shouldn't it be fine just being inside here? Maybe?
受精卵これだ。これを...
Here's the fertilized egg. This one...
ドロップ
Drop.
どうですか？
How is it?
え、なんかやばいやつが来たかも...
Huh, maybe something dangerous came...
え？
Huh?
やばいやつだねー
It's a dangerous one, isn't it~
あれ誘導するか？
Should we lure that thing away?
します？ちょっと...
Shall we? Let me...
遠い場所に...
To a distant place...
どうしてこんなに...
Why is it so...
お、戦ってる？
Oh, are they fighting?
戦ってる！逃げていいかも、ぜんぜん
They're fighting! It might be totally fine to escape.
テイムが...
The taming is...
あ、ねえ
Ah, look.
お！
Oh!
ビルゲも回収しとこう
Let's retrieve Birgen too.
こいつがはよテイム終われ
Hurry up and finish taming this guy.
あ、でもなんか向こうに行きましたね
Ah, but it seems it went over there.
向こう行った
It went over there.
拠点の方戻るとでもちょっと...
Going back to base might be a bit...
危ないかも
Dangerous maybe.
そうですね...
True...
怖いー
Scared~
ねー
Yeah~
あ、戻った！戻った戻った！
Ah, it's back! It's back, it's back!
戻ってきた、つっつくで...
It came back, it's pecking...
イナ先輩、シンプルなベッドって作れますか？
Ina-senpai, can you craft a simple bed?
なんかテイム完了しました。名前どうします？
Taming is complete. What should we name it?
あ、オッケー
Ah, okay.
あ、名前決めちゃっていいですよ
Ah, you can go ahead and decide the name!
アルジェン1...
Argenti 1...
アルジェン...
Argenti...
あ、やばい
Ah, uh oh.
これ拾えるかな、まだ？
Can we still gather this?
あ、拾える
Ah, we can.
え？どうしよう
Eh? What should we do?
どうしよう、どんな感じ？
What should we do, how does it look?
あ、でもまあまあまあ... 今のところ大丈夫っぽいですけど...
Ah, but well... it seems fine for now, but...
ちょっと近い、またやばいやつが...
It's a bit close, another dangerous one...
なんかアルゲンの子供いて草
Lol, there's an Argentavis baby.
こっち
Over here.
うん、オッケーオッケー
Yep, okay, okay.
連れてきた、連れてきた、連れてきた。よかった
I brought it over, brought it over, brought it over. Thank goodness.
えほ、えほ
Yoho, yoho.
で...
And...
あれ？
Huh?
オッケー、ナイス、ナイス、ナイス！
Okay, nice, nice, nice!
オッケー、オッケー
Okay, okay.
よし、ブリーディング頑張りましょう、こいつの。
Alright, let's do our best breeding this one.
こいつ...
This one...
気候、どうしてあげたらいいんだ？
What should I do about the climate for it?
なんか、ちょうどよくしてあげないと...
If I don't adjust it properly...
なんか、卵が孵化らないみたいで...
It seems like the egg won't hatch...
あー
Ah...
この子、で今...
This one, and right now...
ちょっと熱いみたい。
It seems a bit too hot.
え？熱すぎる？
Eh? Too hot?
そう、熱いみたいだから...
Yeah, it seems too hot, so...
ちょっと涼しいところに連れていかないといけない...
We need to take it somewhere cooler...
あ、じゃあ、あの山のところ...
Ah, then over near that mountain...
あ、確か...え、ちょっと...
Ah, true... Wait, a bit...
危なさそうだな...
Looks kinda dangerous...
ですよね...
Right...
一緒に行くか？
Shall we go together?
え、ちょっと、レッツゴー、レッツゴー！
Wait, let's go, let's go!
うわあ！
Whoa!
見つかった！
We got spotted!
やばい、見つかった！
Oh no, we were spotted!
逃げろ！
Run!
あ、私達もちょっと...
Ah, we should also...
やばい、我々が見つかった！
Oh no, we're the ones who got spotted!
逃げて！飛んで、飛んで、飛んで！
Run! Fly, fly, fly!
飛んでる、どこ行った？
They're flying, where did they go?
飛んでる、飛んでる、ちょっとカプセルに...
It's flying, it's flying, let me put it in a capsule...
入ったんじゃない？ワンチャン。
Didn't it go in? Maybe...
あ、入った、待って！いって！
Ah, it went in! Wait! Ouch!
これドア閉めればいける。
We can make it if we close this door.
え、なんか別のやつが...
Wait, something else...
いっちゃった...
came after us...
いやあ！
Oh no!
入れ直してみた...
I tried putting it in...
気絶しないかな、ワンチャン。
I wonder if it'll knock out, maybe...
麻酔矢、持ってますか？
Do you have tranquilizer arrows?
持ってます。
I do.
でも、別のやつに...別のやつに...
But another one... another one...
あ、オッケーオッケー
Ah, okay okay.
うわあ！
Aaah!
やばい、死ぬ死ぬ死ぬ！あー、死んだ！
Oh no, I'm gonna die, I'm gonna die! Ah, I died!
あー、オーマイガー！
Ah, oh my god!
やばい...
Oh no...
あ、飛んでる、飛んでるのか？なるほど。
Ah, flying, is it flying? I see.
飛んでる、飛んでるんですね。
It's flying, so it is flying.
飛んでる、飛んでないです！あの、カプセルに入っていました。
Flying... No, it's not flying! Um, it was in the capsule.
カプセル...はい。
Capsule... right.
待って、違う、違う。
Wait, no, no.
めんどくせー
Such a pain...
え、でも走って戻れる？多分。
But can you run back? Probably.
えーっと、シンプル...
Um, simple...
いや、やばいところ...
Man, what a bad spot...
やっべ、バレっぴ！
Crap, I got spotted!
バレた！
Spotted!
バレたんですか？やばい！
You got spotted? Oh no!
バレちゃった...
I got spotted...
いやあ...
Oh no...
カルノタウルスにバレた。
I got spotted by a Carnotaurus.
ま、でもシンプルベッドで...
Well, but with the simple bed...
クマ、クマがいる。
A bear, there's a bear.
ま、実質ダメージゼロ！
Well, practically zero damage!
オッケーじゃなかった...
That was not okay...
いやあ！
Aah!
虫、虫も！ここやばい！
Bugs, bugs too! It's terrible here!
この辺一帯、ちょっとレベルが強いですよね。
The enemies around this whole area are pretty strong, aren't they?
原油ポンプ、設置完了しました。
Oil pump setup is complete.
ありがとうございます！
Thank you very much!
アクシデントが発生しまして...
An accident occurred...
うん
Yeah.
アルゲンの罠にユウティラが入ってしまって、今麻酔矢打ったらワンチャン気絶してテイムができます。
A Yutyrannus got into the Argentavis trap, so if we shoot tranq arrows now, we might knock it out and tame it!
いいよいいよ、良判断！そっち合流しようか！
Good, good, nice judgment! Should I join up with you over there?
ちょっと来てもらえますか？
Could you come over here for a second?
はい、今...
Yes, right now...
アルゲン T1っていう名前がついた、この近くにいます。
There's one named "Argen T1" near here.
オッケー、オッケー、行くわ。
Okay, okay, I'm heading over.
カルノがめっちゃ近くに1匹...
There's a Carno super close, one of them...
え？
Eh?
カルノもいて、実は...なかなかやばくて...
There's also a Carno, actually... it's pretty dangerous...
もう消えたかな...
Did it disappear already...
まだ、まだいます。
It's still... it's still here.
なんか麻酔銃ある？
Do you have a tranq gun?
飛べる、飛べる人がいれば、こいつを誘導して...
If someone can fly, we can lure it away...
飛べる！
I can fly!
あと...
Also...
麻酔矢かな、麻酔矢があると助かる。
Tranq arrows, having tranq arrows would help.
私、持ってます！
I have some!
よ、よし！
A-Alright!
じゃあ、飛んで...
Then fly...
麻酔矢ね？
Tranq arrows, right?
うん、麻酔矢が欲しいです。
Yeah, I want tranq arrows.
オッケー。
Okay.
麻酔矢ね、ちょっと作るわ。
Tranq arrows, right, I'll craft some.
お前、飛びすぎ！飛びすぎ！
Hey, you're flying too high! Too high!
こいつ寝かせたらいいんですか？
Is it fine if I knock this guy out?
あ、誰かな？あ...
Ah, who is that? Ah...
なんかいる。
There's something there.
飛べる？
Can you fly?
なぜこんなにいるのか...
Why are there so many here...
何だっけな？やべ、作り方忘れちゃったな。
What was it again? Crap, I forgot how to craft it.
いな先輩！
Ina-senpai!
はい！
Yes!
39本で足りるか？
Will 39 be enough?
石を持ってきてくれませんか？
Could you bring me some stone?
石？
Stone?
うん、拠点から。
Yeah, from the base.
え、5個？
Eh, 5 of them?
1スタック、500個のまとまりを1つ。
One stack, a bundle of 500.
500？
500?
まずは、あの...
First off, um...
あ、ここ、来てる！来てる！来てる！飛んでる！
Ah, here! It's coming! It's coming! It's flying!
え、嘘！嘘！嘘！嘘！
No way! Unbelievable! Unbelievable!
えー！こっち！
Whoa! Over here!
ゴザルチェイスしてる！ゴザルチェイスしてる！
Gozaru is chasing it! Gozaru is chasing it!
大丈夫ー！
Are you okay?!
あ、いける！チェイス、いける、いける！
Ah, we can chase it! Go, go!
大丈夫ー！石持って...石持って来るよ、じゃあ。
Are you okay? I'll bring some stone then.
なんか罠使って、こいつを作って、こいつハメようかなって思ったんですけど...
I thought about using a trap and trapping this guy, but...
じゃあ石持って来る...
I'll bring some stone then.
ゴザルがチェイスできてるから、ワンチャンいいかも。大丈夫かも。
Gozaru is chasing it, so maybe we're good. It might be fine.
大丈夫？オッケー！
Is it okay? Okay!
とりあえず、気絶...お願いしまーす！
For now, please knock it out!
ゴザルー！
Gozaru~!
ノープロ、ノープロ。いける、いける、いける！
No problem, no problem! We got this, we got this!
つか生肉持ってないけど平気？
Wait, I don't have raw meat, is that fine?
あ、生肉あります！生肉あります！
Ah, I have raw meat! I have raw meat!
じゃあこいつを寝かさせて、肉を...
Then let's put this guy to sleep and...
あれ、ちょっと待って、なんかしょうもない麻酔矢しか持って来てない...原始の弓しか持って来てないけどいいか。
Wait a sec, I only brought cheap tranq arrows... I only brought a primitive bow, but is that fine?
平気！
It's fine!
よく分からんけど...
I don't really know, but...
今放したから、あのユウティラだっけ？あいつに...
I just let it go, so at that Yutyrannus, right? At him...
頭に全部麻酔、麻酔を！
Hit its head with tranqs, with tranqs!
まさかのとんでもないの、大物来たー！
Unexpectedly, a huge monster came!
入ってるでしょ！なんか知らんけど！
It's inside, right?! I don't know how, but...
入れてみた！
I got it inside!
すごい、すごい！うわー！
Amazing, amazing! Whoa!
入れてみた！よし、チェイス完了！巻いてきましたあいつを！
I trapped it! Okay, chase completed! I lured it over!
ねぇ待って、これさー...
Wait, look at this...
うわ、虫除けスプレーとか欲しいな。
Ugh, I wish I had bug repellent spray.
いや欲しい！分かります！
Yeah, I want it too! I totally get it!
行った...びっくりした。行ったように見せかけてーの？
It left... That scared me. Pretending to leave?
頼む！
Please!
なんかいい感じにテイム出来てくれそうあいつ！来た来た来た！
It feels like we can tame that guy nicely! Here it comes!
Go to sleep!
スリープ、スリープ、レッツゴースリープ！
Sleep, sleep, let's go sleep!
ヒューチー（ほのぼの）と繊維があれば弓矢作れるのに、嘘...
If I had thatch and fiber I could craft arrows, shoot...
なんかちょっとおとなしくなった感じするけど...
It feels like it's quieted down a bit...
そうですよね！もうすぐかな？みんなで麻酔矢打ち込んで...
Right! Is it almost down? Everyone fire tranq arrows into it...
え、まだか...あ、逃げ出した！
Wait, not yet? Ah, it's fleeing!
逃げるなー！
Don't run away!
寝ろー！寝ろー！
Go to sleep! Go to sleep!
寝ろー！全然寝てない！
Sleep! It's not sleeping at all!
ねぇ、藁とさー...
Hey, is there thatch and...
はい！
Yes!
藁ある？
...do you have thatch?
あ、待って、あります！
Ah, wait, I have some!
弓矢をくれれば、麻酔の...
If you give me arrows, tranq...
矢をつくれそう。
...arrows could be crafted.
なるほど！矢あります、矢めっちゃある！
I see! I have arrows, plenty of arrows!
あ、矢ほしい。矢もらっていい？
Ah, I want arrows. Can I have them?
あ、落とした、落とした。あと藁も一応落としておきます。
Ah, I dropped them, I dropped them. I'll drop the thatch too.
ナイス、ナイス。これでボディーで作るときだから...
Nice, nice. I'll craft them on my body...
寝ろー！
Go to sleep!
ボディーで作りながらやるわ。
I'll do it while crafting on my body.
寝てくれ！
Please sleep!
寝ろ！お願いだ！頼む！寝てくれ！
Sleep! Please! I'm begging you! Go to sleep!
え、なんか...私を狙ってる気がする...
Eh, wait... I feel like it's targeting me...
狙ってる気がする！あ、やばい、お前射線に入ってくるな！
I feel like it's targeting you! Ah, oh no, don't get in my line of fire!
逃げろ、逃げろ、逃げろ！
Run, run, run!
おねがーい！
Pleaeeeeease!
大丈夫ー？寝た！寝た！
Are you okay? It's asleep! It's asleep!
起きて肉入れろ！肉入れろ！
Get up and put meat in! Put meat in!
こいつのインベントリが、こいつがデカくて邪魔すぎて開けない！
This guy's inventory... He's too huge and in the way, I can't open it!
体で作っちゃってるから、そっち行かないと...
I crafted it on my body, so I have to go over there...
なるほど、そっち！
I see, over there!
お前だ！
It's you!
あ、ちょっと待って！
Ah, wait a second!
やばい、体が...
Oh no, my body is...
体がガタガタ、邪魔で！
My body is shaking, it's in the way!
ちょっと、飛ばさないで！やめて！
Wait, don't blow us away! Stop it!
今、このとんでるをどうにかするか。
Let's figure out what to do with Tonderu now.
あ、とんでるーで...
Ah, with Tonderu...
こいつーって。
...at this guy.
こっち来るかな？
Will it come over here?
それで行ける？
Can you do it with that?
来ました、来ました！こっから...
It came, it came! From here...
あ、ナイス！ナイス！ナイス！
Ah, nice! Nice! Nice!
とんでもないの手に入れたんじゃないか、これ！やばー！
Didn't we just get something insane?! This is crazy!
えぐい！えぐい！
Insane! Insane!
てかさ、これ攻撃されるときつくない？
By the way, wouldn't it be bad if it gets attacked?
こっち...ちょっと...
Over here... Wait...
上手く出来たりします？
Can we manage it well?
まず、ちょっと遠い場所に、この...
First, to a place slightly further away, this...
今、ちょっとこっちに呼び寄せてるけど...あ、来た！こっち運んじゃうね。
I'm drawing it over here now... Ah, it came! I'll carry it this way.
お願いしまーす！よし、よし、よし。
Please do! Alright, alright!
ユウティラ持てれば...ユウティラ持ってきます。
If I can carry the Yutyrannus... I'll bring the Yutyrannus.
おおー！あははは！
Ooh! Ahahaha!
ナイスーな、ナイスーな。
Nice, nice!
ナイス！
Nice!
まさかの...
Unbelievable...
すごー！えー！
Amazing! What?!
なんか、ある罠に入ってくれてラッキーでしたね！
It was so lucky that it ran right into an existing trap!
やばいなそれ！ラッキー！
That's crazy! Lucky!
ここに走って良かった！
I'm so glad I ran over here!
ね！入れるか分からなくて走ったら入ってくれて、めっちゃラッキーでした！
Right! I didn't know if it'd fit, but it did when I ran, so lucky!
ちょっと回転体できるかなと思って、あっちに走ったんですけど、ラッキー！
I ran over there thinking I could loop around, but that was so lucky!
攻撃してこない？ファイトこれ？
Is it not attacking? Is this a fight?
あ、はい！
Ah, yes!
これ肉にしちゃう、肉。
I'm turning this into meat, meat.
肉。
Meat.
でかい！
It's huge!
食え食え。サンキュー。
Eat, eat. Thank you.
ここ暑いって言われるアルゲン。
The Argentavis that says it's too hot here.
卵。
The egg.
暑いんか？
Is it hot?
雪山に近くに持っていくとか？
Should we bring it closer to the snowy mountain?
そうね。なんかそこのプテラ...
Yeah. Also, that Pteranodon over there...
痛痛痛痛痛！
Ow ow ow ow ow!
くそ、誰か...
Damn, someone...
おー！
Woah!
おい、肉よこせ！あ、くそ。
Hey, give me the meat! Ah, shoot.
でか。
Huge.
来てくれてありがとうねー。
Thank you for coming over~
ユーティらちゃん...
Yuty and the others...
お、来た！肉！イエーイ！
Oh, here it comes! Meat! Yay!
ついでにプテラもテイムしとこう。さっき死んじゃったから。
Let's tame this Pteranodon too, since the last one died.
確かに。
True.
ナイス。
Nice.
なんか追ってたから、プテラテイムしときます。
I'll tame this Pteranodon since it was chasing something.
おー！
Oh!
でか！
Huge!
てかさ、ここさ、今思ったけどこれ金鉱石じゃない？
By the way, I just realized, isn't this gold ore right here?
あ、そう。この辺鉱石めっちゃあって。
Ah, yeah. There's so much ore around here.
うん。だからなんかここサブサブにしてて。
Yeah. So I made this like a secondary sub-base.
昨日作った時に...
When I built it yesterday...
もはやもう何が本当か...
At this point, what's even real...
分からない。どこ、何が拠点か分からんよな。
I don't know. You can't even tell where the main base is.
ここをテイム場にしようかなって思ってました。
I was thinking of making this place a taming spot.
いいで、いいで、いいで。
That's good, that's good, that's good.
ちょっともう、金鉱石ちょっと燃やしにいっちゃいます。
I'm gonna go melt down some gold ore now.
うん。
Okay.
やばい、また喉が渇いた。
Oh no, I'm thirsty again.
お水を取ってこなきゃ。ちょっと一瞬TONDERUに乗らせてください。
I need to get some water. Let me ride TONDERU for a second.
はい。
Sure.
あ、水ここ居ますよ。
Ah, there's water right here.
ちょっと！名前！ちょっと！
Wait! The name! Wait!
いな、こいつなんて名前付ける？
Ina, what should we name this guy?
え？
Huh?
ゆ... ゆーてぃ？
Yu... Yuty?
ちゃん？
Chan?
ゆーてー！ゆーてー！
YOU TEA! YOU TEA!
ゆーてー！
YOU TEA!
YOU... TEA... YOU TEA?
待って違う！カルノ来たカルノ来た！
Wait, no! A Carno is here, a Carno is here!
うわー！まずいまずい！
Uwaaah! Bad bad!
いて！
Ouch!
TONDERU!
あ、痛い痛い！ヤバいヤバい、これさ...
Ah, ouch ouch! Oh no, oh no, this...
ヤバいみんなこれ攻撃になっちゃった。
Oh no, everyone's attacking now.
こいつやらないと無理だ。
We have to take this guy down.
うん。
Yeah.
待って待って、ブロロンまじ...
Wait, wait, Buroron is seriously...
出れるのかこいつはまず？
Can this guy even get out in the first place?
ちょっとデブすぎて出ない！
He's too fat to get out!
ヤバい！これ出さないとマズイけど！
Oh no! It's bad if we don't get him out!
ヤバいブロロン死ぬブロロン死ぬ！ヤバいヤバい！
Oh no, Buroron is gonna die! Oh no!
あ、オッケオッケ出た出た出た！ナイスナイス！
Ah, okay, okay, he got out! Nice, nice!
よしよし、ちょっとユーティらはここでちょっと飼うか。
Alright, alright. Should we keep Yuty right here for now?
拠点に連れてってもいいかもな、このユーティら。
Maybe we should bring this Yuty back to base.
てかさ、共有の拠点に持ってって見せびらかそうぜこれ！
By the way, let's bring it to our shared base and show it off!
「すごいやろ」つってこれ！
Saying, "Isn't this awesome?!"
マジで。
Seriously.
YOU TEA!
YOU TEA! ほらYOU TEAでしょこれ！生肉あげる！
YOU TEA! See, it's YOU TEA, right? Here's raw meat!
完璧！
Perfect!
生肉はありませんか？
Do you have any raw meat?
あ、いっぱい... ここで気絶してるプテラに入れてほしい。
Lots... Put it in the knocked-out Pteranodon here.
あっち側ですか？
Over that way?
あ、そこ...
Ah, right there...
こっちこっちだ！いろはこっちだ！
Over here, over here! Iroha, over here!
あ。
Ah.
あ、居た。
Ah, found it.
なんか蜂、蜂、蜂みたいな... ごめん、いろはがゴリラに見えたごめんけど。
Like a bee... Sorry, I thought Iroha was a gorilla.
野生のゴリラ居ると思って。違った。
I thought there was a wild gorilla. But I was wrong.
あで、ここに眠ってるこのプテラ、この辺に... あれ？居なくなった。
And the sleeping Pteranodon around here... Huh? It's gone.
了解です。
Got it.
ユーティさんは任せていい？
Can I leave Yuty to you?
はい！もちろんもちろん！
Yes! Of course, of course!
ちょっとじゃあ、原油とか取りに行ってミッション進めちゃうわ。
I'll go gather some crude oil and push through the mission.
お願いしまーす！肉入れました。
Please do! I put the meat in.
ありがとー。
Thank you~
でか、でかすぎだろ！
Huge, it's way too big!
とんでもないアルゲンかと思いきや...
Just when I thought it was a crazy Argentavis...
なんかユーティ入ってきた。
Yuty joined in.
アルゲンの交配できる？できそう？
Can we breed the Argentavis? Does it look possible?
なんかちょっと暑いので、ちょっとその雪山あたりまで行って交配させた受精卵を持っていこうかなって感じですね。
It's hot, so I thought of flying near the snowy mountain to breed them and bring back the egg.
ただ怖いからユーティ連れて行こうかなみたいな。
But since it's scary, I thought I'd bring Yuty along.
いいね、いいね。
Nice, nice.
ね。
Right?
あれは何だろう… あれかな
I wonder what that is... Is it that?
やばい、また水なくなった
Oh no, I ran out of water again.
水… あそこにあった
Water... over there...
あ、ちょっとまた飲ませてもらって、かつ… 水を補給しなければ
Ah, let me drink some more, and... I need to replenish my water.
必要だったら、もう川に行きますよ
If needed, I can go to the river now.
あ、本当ですか？じゃあ一回水筒全部中に入れるんで、行ってきて貰いつつ…
Really? Then I'll put all the waterskins inside, so while you go...
ちょっと待って… 1キロ足りるか？
Wait a second... Will 1 kilo be enough?
キチンっていう素材をイナ先輩持ったらこの中に入れて欲しいんですけど…
Ina-senpai, if you have any chitin, could you put it in here?
あ、多分入れるはずです
Ah, I should be able to put it in.
サンキュー！
Thank you!
これも飲んで… ちょっと喉乾いた…
Drink this too... I was a bit thirsty...
あ、行けるか？ 行きます
Oh, can we go? I'm going.
サンキュー！
Thank you!
アルゲンサドル…
An Argentavis saddle...
待って、アルゲンのやつ作れるやん！
Wait, I can make the Argentavis one!
おー！
Oooh!
えーっと、今何しようとしたっけな…
Um, what was I trying to do just now?
えっーと、餌だ餌、餌… 餌箱
Um... food, right, food... feeding trough.
木材、繊維、わら
Wood, fiber, thatch.
木材、繊維、わら、わら…
Wood, fiber, thatch, thatch...
あ、来た！
Ah, there we go!
アルゲンのサドル1個作れたー！
I was able to craft one Argentavis saddle!
おー！
Ooh!
ただいまー
I'm back~
おかえりー
Welcome back~
レベル50だけど、ワイバーンの卵をゲットしてきた。一旦戦力になるかなと思って、やっぱり。
It's level 50, but I got a Wyvern egg. Thought it'd be useful for firepower for now.
え、待って、ナイス！こちらもございますよね？
Wait, nice! We also have this, right?
ユウティラ捕まえました！
I caught a Yutyrannus!
なにー！？ 最強じゃん！
What?! That's so strong!
最強じゃん！で、残念ながらケツァルコアトルじゃなかったです、ミッション。
That's awesome! And unfortunately, the mission wasn't a Quetzalcoatlus.
違かった？
It wasn't?
ラバエレメンタルだっけ？
Was it Lava Elemental?
ラバエレメンタルじゃないかって、文字数的に。
People said it might be Lava Elemental based on the character count.
へー！
Huh!
ワンチャン、ラバエレメンタルが火山洞窟のボスらしくて、ライトニングワイバーンで行けるんじゃないかみたいなコメントにあって。
There's a chance Lava Elemental is the volcano cave boss, and comments said a Lightning Wyvern might work.
なるほど。
I see.
怖えー！
Scary!
なんかすんごい戦力固まった？
Somehow our combat power really got stacked?
いい感じにはなってるから、ワンチャン行けるか、どうだっていう感じですね。
Things are looking good, so it's a matter of whether we can pull it off.
了解です。
Got it.
どっか行ってもいいんじゃないかな、どうなんだろう？
Maybe we could go somewhere, what do you think?
行ってみるのはありそう… サドル系ちょっと作って…
Going somewhere sounds good... Let's craft some saddles...
サドルほしいかも。
We might want saddles.
ユウティラのサドル検索するか… ユウ…
Let's search for a Yutyrannus saddle... Yu...
ユウティラはいいぞー
Yutyrannus is great~
パイロテイムしたいんだよね。
I want to tame a Pyromane.
あ、確かに！みんなで、ちょっとパイロをテイムしに行ってもいいかもしれない。
Ah, true! It might be good if we all go tame a Pyromane together.
どの道、明日いるでしょ、多分、やろうと思ったら。
Either way, we'll probably need it tomorrow anyway if we try.
そうだね、確かに。パイロ先行っちゃうか。
Yeah, true. Should we go for Pyromane first then?
あ、ユウティラも真珠が必要なんですね。
Ah, Yutyrannus also needs pearls, huh.
真珠、めちゃめちゃトワ様が獲ってきてくれてるから行けるはず！
Towasama gathered tons of pearls for us, so we should be good!
おー、ジャス！
Oh, nice!
最高最強！
The absolute best!
旋盤の中に… あるで！
In the fabricator... there's some!
誰このベッド？何この斜めのベッド？
Whose bed is this? What's with this diagonal bed?
無理無理無理！荒らしだろ、これ！
No way, no way, no way! This is griefing!
なんだよ、いいじゃん！
What, it's fine!
汚ねえよ、お前！おしゃんティーやん！
It looks messy! It's stylish!
おしゃれじゃねえよ、バカ！
It's not stylish, you idiot!
なんだよこれ… 直線でさ、四角四角できてんのに斜目でこれ！マイクラだったら…
What is this... Everything is neat and square, and then this diagonal thing! If this were Minecraft...
いいじゃん、アシンメトリーでいいじゃない！
What's wrong with asymmetry? It's fine!
不親切！
So user-unfriendly!
アシンメトリーじゃね… シンメトリーだろ、それ！
It's not asymmetry... That's symmetry, you mean!
シンメトリーでいいじゃない！
Symmetry is fine, isn't it!
え、これどうしたらいい？拾う… 拾うでいいか。あ、拾える。
Wait, what should I do with this? Pick up... pick up is fine, right? Ah, I can pick it up.
カマキリ獲ってくれたおかげでギリースーツが治る！
Thanks to catching the mantis, I can repair my Ghillie Suit!
先輩も一回拠点戻りますか？ユウティラ連れて行くか、そっちに。
Senpai, are you heading back to base too? Should I bring the Yutyrannus over there?
あ、じゃあ私のもちょっとカプセルに入れて持って行きます？
Ah, should I put mine in a Cryopod and bring it over?
一匹なんか持って来ようかな。
Maybe I'll bring one over.
そうですね、入れて… うちでも一匹ちょい持って行きます。
Yeah, put it in... I'll bring one or so from our end too.
いいよー
Alright~
恐竜、何がいい？クエストで貰ったやつだったら…
Which creature would be good? If it's one from a quest...
えーっと、何… 何だっけ名前？えーっと…
Um, what... what was its name again? Um...
ユウティラじゃなくて… 何て名前だったっけ… 一番クレートで貰えるやつ何だったっけ？
Not Yutyrannus... What was its name again? What's the one you get from the crate?
クレートで貰える…
The one from the crate...
テリジノのも使えるはず
We should be able to use Therizino's too.
じゃテリジノ持ってくるか
Then should I go bring Therizino?
ちょっと先行っててもらってもいい？
Can you go ahead without me for a bit?
オッケー
Okay.
あとあれ見てくるわ
I'll go check that out too.
いいよ
Sure thing.
一応予備プテラも連れてきました
I brought a spare Pteranodon just in case.
ナイス
Nice!
俺は今田んぼの様子見に行くんや
I'm going to go check on the farm field now.
原油ポンプも設置したんですよ
I already set up the oil pump too.
いいね 原油ポンプ設置できたならありがたや
Nice, that's really helpful!
あとは納品したらいいかな
I guess I just need to hand these in now.
麻酔薬ってどっかに無かったっけ？
Where did we keep the Narcotics again?
あ 麻酔あげれる
Ah, I can give you some Narcotics!
麻酔薬ね
Narcotics, right!
別の拠点にちょっと刷ってるはずです ちょっと取ってきます
There should be some crafted at the other base, so I'll go fetch them.
ハーイ サンキュー
Okay, thank you!
55個だけ？
Only 55?
ポンプって1個しか設置しちゃいけないんだっけ？
Are we only allowed to place one pump?
そういうわけではないけども 独占しちゃダメってだけで 別に1個以上ダメとかじゃない
No, it's not like that, you just shouldn't monopolize them. It's fine to place more than one.
こっからが独占になるんだ
So from here it counts as monopolizing...
ぷっちゃんさ 昨日原油取ったのってさ
Puchan, yesterday when you gathered oil...
クジラの死体からだっけ？
Was it from the whale carcass?
そうだよ
Yeah, that's right.
クジラの死体って右上だったっけ？
Was the whale carcass in the top right area?
右上だよ
Yeah, top right!
消えた！あれ？
Wait, it vanished! Huh?
作れるもの作るか ユウティ...
Let's craft what I can. Yuty...
インゴットそんなに必要なんだ
It requires that many ingots?
何してる？
What are you making?
麻酔薬 1000 鍛冶場の中にあるやつをもらって
Narcotics... 1000... Taking the ones inside the Forge...
作る 1000
Crafting... 1000...
よし これで イム先輩！
Alright, with this... Imu-senpai!
はい！
Yes!
ここにユウティサドル出してもらっていいですか？
Could you pull out a Yuty saddle right here for me?
おお いいね！
Oh, awesome!
今戻りまーす
Heading back now!
ちなみにワイバーン右上にいるわ
By the way, there's a Wyvern in the top right.
本当だ いるわ
Oh, you're right, it's there.
大量にいるよ
There's a whole bunch of them!
これどう行くんだったっけ？
How do I get there again?
そうしたら お！お！お！
Alright then... Whoa, whoa, whoa!
怖い！
Scary!
大丈夫？これどうしたらいい？これどうしたらいい？
Are you okay? What should I do? What should I do?!
何をしてるのーい！
What are you doing?!
ヤバいヤバいヤバい！ / どうしたの？
Bad, bad, bad! / What happened?
ヤバいヤバいヤバい！ / 助けてー！
Bad, bad, bad! / Help me!
何やってんのー！
What are you doing?!
死んだ ライトニングワイバーン！
I died... Lightning Wyvern!
な 何事？ライトニングワイバーン？
W-What happened?! Lightning Wyvern?
あ ユウティここ
Ah, Yuty is over here.
ユウティありがとう でっけー！
Thanks for the Yuty... It's huge!
デカい！
It's gigantic!
まあ いってきてくれ
Well, go give it a shot.
何事？！
What happened?!
なぜ なくなった？
Why... why did it disappear?
痛い！
Ouch!
えー すごい！
Whoa, amazing!
まぁ色々あった / いろいろね
Well, a lot happened. / A lot, huh?
攻撃力 体力か 体力に振って
Attack power... or Health? Put points into Health...
近接攻撃力を
Melee attack power...
テリジノ持って行きます
I'll bring the Therizino over.
はーい
Okay.
あ オッケーオッケー
Ah, okay, okay.
お肉落ちてるかも サンキュー
Meat might drop, thank you!
これで
With this...
あー可愛い！
Ah, so cute!
ユウティラ乗れますこれで
I can ride the Yuty now with this!
みんなギリースーツって1個持ってるよね？
Everyone has one Ghillie Suit, right?
持ってる！
I have one!
風真のは無くすの怖くてまだあの中に入れてある
Kazama's scared of losing hers, so she put it inside.
樽の中？ / 樽の中
Inside the barrel? / Inside the barrel.
全然使いたいなら使ってください！
If you want to use it, please go right ahead!
取りに行くとかではないから大丈夫
It's not like I'm going out to fetch it anyway, so it's fine.
取りに行くとか以前の問題だからね
It's a problem way before going to fetch it!
向こうにーはスッキリしてるわけ。
It's all cleared out over there.
あーなるほど。
Ah, I see.
そうスッキリ。
Yeah, clean.
どこで落としたの？スッキリしてるわけよ。
Where did you drop it? It's all clear.
ん？
Hmm?
ん？じゃないよ。どこで落としたの？
Don't "Hmm?" me. Where did you drop it?
イナ先輩！
Ina-senpai!
はい！
Yes!
記憶喪失してんじゃん。
You're having memory loss.
どこ…これを…
Where... this...
どこにあったの？
Where was it?
火山、火山だよね？さっき言ってたからね。
The volcano, it's the volcano, right? Since you said so earlier.
火山ね。
The volcano, right.
拾ってできるか。これワンチャン…
Can we pick it up? Maybe we have a chance...
みんな今どこにいるの？
Where is everyone right now?
仮拠点にいるよ。仮拠点にいるよ。
We're at the temporary base.
王子とユウティラくんの尻尾邪魔やな。
Prince and Yutyrannus's tail are in the way.
乗りやす！
Can I ride?
くそ！下手くそだ！
Damn! That was so clumsy!
ユウティラくんって何に振ったらいいんでしたっけ？
What stats should I put into Yutyrannus?
ユウティラくんは何優先だ？体力、スタミナ？
What's the priority for Yutyrannus? Health, stamina?
一旦攻撃振っちゃいました。
I put some into attack for now.
攻撃かな？
Maybe attack?
これで…
With this...
着地しろ！つかんで！インセクトを取りたいんや！
Land! Grab it! I want to get the insect!
スタミナ…スタミナの…スタミナか体力か。
Stamina... stamina... stamina or health.
ユウティラは体力。じゃあちょっと体力振っとこう。
Yuty is health. Then I'll put a bit into health.
テリジノって何振ったらいい？
What should I put into Therizino?
テリジノくんも…一応体力振っといた方がいいかな？
Therizino too... maybe it's better to invest in health?
体力か。
Health, huh.
うん。
Yeah.
テリジノくん…
Therizino-kun...
おっと、ここは…間違えちゃったわ。
Oops, here... I made a mistake.
やばい、掴めないこいつが。
Oh no, I can't catch this guy.
スタミナも振っとこう。
I'll put some into stamina too.
近接振っとこうかな？
Maybe I should put points into melee?
あー、強い！
Ah, so strong!
そう、よかった！ユウティ強い！
Yes, great! Yuty is so strong!
ついちゃっ、ついてきちゃってるね。
It's... it's following us.
あ、ユウティ強い！赤ちゃんが！
Ah, Yuty is strong! The baby!
あいあい、赤ちゃんがよちよちしてる。
Ah, the baby is waddling around.
おーいおいで。ごめんよ赤ちゃん。
Hey, come here. Sorry, baby.
ばぶちゃん、ばぶちゃん。ばぶちゃん何？あなた何？何々？
Baby, baby. Baby, what is it? What do you want? What, what?
ばばばばぶ。お世話はまだ要らない？
Ba ba ba baby. You don't need care yet?
お世話お世話を…
Care, care...
草食動物の好物だけど食べるござるが…
It's a herbivore favorite, but it's eating...
欲しくない？君は何してほしいの？
You don't want it? What do you want me to do?
あ、ダメダメ。黒いベリーダメ。
Ah, no no. Black berries are no good.
あったった。黒いベリーいけたっけ？
There it is. Could they eat black berries?
世話をしてもらいたがってる。なんだ？
It wants to be taken care of. What is it?
そしたらさ、どうしよう。
In that case, what should we do?
え、イナ先輩と…え、どうします？もうなんだっけ、パイロ…
Eh, with Ina-senpai... eh, what shall we do? What was it, Pyro...
パイロ…パイロ行っていいんじゃないか？
Pyro... Shouldn't we go to Pyro?
行きます？なんかもしあれだったら…
Shall we go? If that's the case...
この…まだ時間かかりそうだったら、寒いとこ行って一瞬でパパッと産ませてきちゃおうかなと思って。
If this... if it's gonna take more time, I was thinking of going somewhere cold to quickly hatch it.
アルゲンの子供…イナ先輩と…なんだ？
The Argen baby... with Ina-senpai... what?
あ、ほうか。
Ah, I see.
行ってくる？
Are you going?
ちょっとパパッと産ませてこようかな。有精卵あるから。
I think I'll quickly go hatch it. Since I have a fertilized egg.
うん。
Yeah.
うん。で、入れてこっち帰ってきますわ。じゃイナ先輩あの…
Yeah. Then I'll put it in and come back. So Ina-senpai, that...
プテラでついてきてください。フォローミー、レッツゴー！
Please follow me on the Pteranodon. Follow me, let's go!
ユウティラもうちょっ、戦わせたいなユウティラ。レベリングしたいよな。
I want Yutyrannus to fight a bit more. I want to level it up.
ナイッスー！
Nice!
お前も戦いたいよな、ユウティラ。
You want to fight too, right, Yutyrannus?
ナイスっふー！
Nice!
うんちが落ちた。飯食え飯食え、飯食え飯食え。
Poop dropped. Eat food, eat food! Eat food, eat food!
こっちのね、ここ寒くて、イナ先輩。
Over here, it's cold here, Ina-senpai.
ここなら生まれる気がしているんです。
I feel like it'll hatch if we're here.
お世話はもうないかもだし。
It might not need care anymore either.
ここ。
Here.
だからちゃっちゃと産んで、モンスターボールに入れて連れて帰りましょう。
So let's hatch it quickly, put it in a Cryopod, and bring it back.
おー、はい。
Oh, okay.
有精卵これだ。
The fertilized egg is this one.
とんとんとーん。
Thump thump thump.
ちょうどいいだろ。こいつ倒せるかな？あ、熱い！
This should be just right. Wonder if we can beat this guy? Ah, it's hot!
熱いらしいです、ここ。
Apparently it's hot here.
やんの？やんの？
You wanna fight? You wanna fight?
ここも熱い？ここ熱い？
Is it hot here too? Is it hot here?
この辺だったらどう？
How about around here?
あ、なんか上に怖そうな人いる。
Ah, there's someone scary looking up there.
うわぁ！
Uwaah!
マンモス。
Mammoth.
マンモス、マンモス、マンモス。どう？さすがに涼しいやろ。
Mammoth, mammoth, mammoth. How is it? Surely it's cool here.
どう？ささささ寒いー！
How is it? S-s-s-so cold!
寒い！
Cold!
ここノ、このメーターが…それやめて？それやめて本当に！それやめてまじで！
The, the meter here... Stop that? Really stop that! Stop that, seriously!
オッケー！
Okay!
これが…これさえ…あったかくなったら…
If this... if only this gets warm...
はいはいはい。
Yes yes yes.
お、でも早い！
Oh, but it's fast!
ね。
Right?
あれ？養殖物が入ってんのか？養殖…あ。
Huh? Are farmed items in here? Farmed... ah.
助けてー！
Help!
もう本当にそこ行くのやめて、本当に。
Seriously stop going there, really.
暖かくしてくれ。
Warm me up.
ふぅ…寒すぎモンスター！
Phew... Cold monster!
助けてー！
Help!
なんだよマグマとかいうクソクソクソな地形はクソー！
What's with this damn terrain called magma? It's so terrible!
しょうがないね マグマも
Can't be helped, magma either.
後ろにクマがいる ここ下がって
There's a bear behind us. Lower it here.
許さない！
Unforgivable!
大丈夫？
Are you okay?
場所にさ もうこのクマお前もう本当にクマやめて
Seriously, this bear... Seriously, cut it out with the bear.
もうすぐ もうすぐ
Almost... Almost...
クマいる あと もうちょっと
There's a bear! Just a little bit more!
本当だ こっち来てる
It really is coming this way.
これに入れて 帰ろう
Put this in and let's go back.
飛んだ飛んだ飛んだ ナイスナイス
Flew, flew, flew! Nice, nice!
重すぎ…
Too heavy...
やばいやばいやばい
Bad, bad, bad!
こっち来る こっち来る…
It's coming here, it's coming here...
いっせーのー とう！
Ready, set... Tooh!
あ、もうちょっと
Ah, a little bit more...
ただこれを落としたら すぐにあるか
If I drop this, it'll happen right away, though.
いや もうちょっと もうちょっと
No, a little more, a little more...
うわぁ イノシシ欲しいな 回復のやつ
Whoa, I want a boar, the healing one.
こんにちはー
Hello~
1匹は引っ張ってて こんにちはー こんにちはー
Pulling one... Hello~ Hello~
あ、生まれました！
Ah, it was born!
おかえりー おかえりなのかな？
Welcome back! Or is it welcome back?
ウンチやめてね ボールに入れて
Don't poop, okay? Put it in the ball...
帰れる？ ボールに入れて
Can you return? Put it in the ball!
ボール！ 入った！
Ball! Got it in!
こんにちはー
Hello~
あ、待てない！ あ、まじ！
Ah, couldn't wait! Ah, really?!
できました
Done!
あ、入れました
Ah, put it in!
戻ります？
Going back?
戻ろう戻ろう！ Let's go!
Let's go back, let's go back! Let's go!
ちょっと待って！ 突っ込んでる！
Wait a second! Plunging in!
木閉じてる！
Trapped in trees!
え？ ちょっと待って
Eh? Wait a second.
おいしょー
Heave-ho!
え、またゼロからになった？
Eh, did it go back to zero again?
ゴザル治安や
Gozaru's public safety...
え？ 飛んで… え？
Eh? Flying... Eh?
ユウティラ テイムしました なんかまぐれで
I tamed a Yutyrannus, somehow by fluke.
お！ やったー！ 2匹目！
Oh! Yay! The second one!
え？ あ、今アキ先輩と話してます これ
Eh? Ah, I'm talking to Aki-senpai right now.
あー OK OK！ びっくりした
Ah, okay okay! You startled me.
ゴミすぎこいつ
This guy is absolute trash.
罠の中のテイムに入ってしまったんです あいつが
It went into the trap during taming, that guy did.
不法侵入者をつかまえて
Catching the illegal intruder!
麻酔矢ほしい麻酔矢！ OK OK 麻酔
I want tranquilizer darts, tranquilizer darts! OK, OK, tranqs.
それほしかった
I wanted that.
あ、ここに渡した
Ah, passed it over here.
どー！ すごい！ それ本当にやめてくれないかな
Whoa! Amazing! Could you really not stop that?
頑張れー！ おー すごい！
Do your best! Wow, awesome!
1個 ちょっと待ってくださいね
Hold on just a second...
ここじゃねー
Not here.
お！ よいしょ！
Oh! Up we go!
うえ！
Whoa!
とりあえず僕はいつでもいけますよ
At any rate, I can go anytime.
いつでも？ いつでも？
Anytime? Anytime?
よいしょ よいしょ
Heave-ho, heave-ho.
アルゲン組が帰ってきたらかな？
Maybe when the Argen squad gets back?
OK
えーっと これと…
Umm, this and...
自分の矢を… えー
My arrows... um,
ちょっと待って ごめんごめん 本当にごめんね
Wait a second, sorry, sorry! Really sorry!
許してください
Please forgive me.
大丈夫か？ ドア
Is it okay? The door.
大丈夫ではある 一応 一応大丈夫ではある OK
It's okay for now. At least for now. OK.
イナ先輩！
Ina-senpai!
イナ先輩ってブリーディングミッションって達成してましたか？
Ina-senpai, did you complete the breeding mission?
あ、はいはい！
Ah, yes yes!
じゃあイナ先輩に引っ張られてブリーディング達成になったのかな？
Then did it count as completing breeding because Ina-senpai led it?
ゴザルじゃなくて多分ハマってたから ワンチャン…
Not Gozaru, but probably because it was stuck, maybe...
ブリーディング達成は えーっと…
Breeding completion was, um...
達成みたいなのは出なかったはず
Something like 'Completed' shouldn't have popped up.
あの携帯電話みたいな スマホみたいなやつでピピッてわかる感じですよね？
It's like that phone-like smartphone device where it beeps to let you know, right?
そうそう！ そうですよね
Exactly! That's right.
そう ワンチャン どっちなんだろう？
Yeah, which one could it be?
今分からず…
Currently unknown...
ちょっと1回聞いてみた 生まれたけどゴザルには判定来てなかったので
I tried asking once. It was born, but Gozaru didn't get the credit for it.
イナ先輩に行ってればそれでいいんですけど
If it went to Ina-senpai, that's fine though.
交配ボタンを押した人だから
Because it's the person who pressed the mating button.
あー でもゴザルなー 交配ボタン 途中で変わっちゃったから
Ah, but Gozaru... the mating button changed halfway through,
もしかしたらダメだった可能性はある
so there's a chance it might not have worked.
かもしれない
Might be.
無事に帰ってこれた！
Made it back safely!
おかえり！ ナイス！ イナ先輩！
Welcome back! Nice, Ina-senpai!
よし！ ナイス！ おかえりー！
All right! Nice! Welcome back~!
おかえりー！
Welcome back~!
ゴザルさん ブリーディングよく分かってないんですけど この辺で
Gozaru-san, I don't really understand breeding, but around here...
赤ちゃん出したらワンチャン
If we pop the baby out, maybe...
ワンチャンかな？ ゲーム内ボイスがオンか？
Maybe? Is in-game voice on?
ここでいいんじゃない？ この…
Isn't here fine? This...
これも行けるのか？
Can this go too?
あ、生まれました！
Ah, it was born!
えっと お世話表示…
Umm, care details...
ウンチが大きい！ ウンチでっけー！
The poop is huge! Huge poop!
ユウティラのウンチおっきいね
Yutyrannus poop is huge, isn't it?
ケアが必要になるまであと4分だ
There's 4 minutes left until care is needed.
よいしょ
Heave-ho.
やばい 生肉全然ないや 入れてあげなきゃ
Oh no, there's no raw meat at all. Gotta put some in.
あん、あ、アーキ先輩と合体した。
Ah, I merged with Aki-senpai.
よし
All right.
はい、先ほどの問い合わせに対しての回答が返って参りましたので、
Okay, we received a reply to our inquiry earlier,
お知らせします。
- あ、ありがとうございます！
so I'm letting you know.
- Ah, thank you!
はい。えっと子供が生まれて、
まあ触って名前をつける時が判定ポイントです。
Yes. When a baby is born,
touching it and naming it is the trigger point.
あー、ありがとうございます！
Ah, thank you very much!
はーい、頑張ってね。
- なるほどね。
Yup, good luck!
- I see.
はい、サンキューです。
Alright, thank you!
よいしょ。
Up we go.
じゃあ、名前をつけるタイミングだから、
名前をつけるタイミングってどこだ？
So, if it's the timing of naming them,
where is that timing?
あ、なんか生まれて、
インプリントをするってメニューが…
Ah, like when it's born,
there's a menu to imprint...
じゃあ名前つけられてるから、え、じゃあイナ先輩これで
達成は出来てる…なんかスマートフォンみたいなところで…
So it's already been named. Wait, then Ina-senpai,
is this cleared? In that smartphone-like device...
あ、開けてます、はい。
Ah, I'm opening it, yes.
あ、じゃあOKですね！
Ah, so it's OK then!
イナ先輩の分ができたから、
これでブリーディングを…
Since Ina-senpai's portion is done,
with this, breeding...
オッケー。
Okay.
クリア？
Cleared?
うん、イナ先輩もクリアかもこれで。
オッケーオッケー。
Yeah, Ina-senpai might be cleared with this too.
Okay, okay.
あ、オッケー。はい。
Ah, okay. Yes.
だから…えーっと…ちょっと待ってね。
So... um... hold on a second.
よいしょ。
Alright.
ほんなら、じゃあこれでいってみるか？
Well then, shall we go with this?
いってみるか！
Shall we go!
ちょっと、じゃあパイロメインをじゃあお世話が…
Wait, so then Pyromane needs care...
えーっと、ビロハの二重になってるよ、声。
Um, Viroha's voice is echoing.
あ、本当だ。
Ah, you're right.
B押してもらって。
Press B please.
あれ？こいつ…
- ほんまやで、ほんまやで。
Huh? This guy...
- Indeed, indeed.
死んじゃったのか？
Did he die?
あー、もうちょっと…
Ah, just a bit more...
よいしょ。ホイ。
Alright. There.
これで、なんかブリーディング…
With this, like, breeding...
イナ先輩、この…
- はい。
Ina-senpai, this...
- Yes.
なんだろう、カーソルを合わせると、なんかケアみたいなやつがあって、
今あと残り…はい、2分…2分半ってなってるんですけど…
What is it... when I point the cursor at it,
there's a care option, and right now it says 2 and a half minutes remaining...
うん。
Yeah.
必要になると、なん頭のこの…鳥の頭の上に…
何々してくれって出てくるんで、それをやってあげると…
When it becomes necessary, an instruction will pop up
above this bird's head asking for something, so if you do that...
オッケー。お世話判定になって、育ちます。
Okay. It counts as care, and it grows.
あー。
Ah.
トワさん大丈夫？生きてる？
- い、生き…生きてる！
Towa-san, are you okay? Are you alive?
- A-ali... alive!
生きてる。
- 全然大丈夫ではあるんだけど。
She's alive.
- I'm totally fine though.
パイロ行くよー。
Pyro, here we go.
あ、行っていでよー。
Ah, off you go.
おに？
Oni?
チャットで合流するわ、もうイ…あとちょっとで。
I'll join via chat soon... in just a bit.
オッケー。じゃあイナ先輩ブリーディングしてても me 貰って…
- そうだね、今3人で行ってみるか。
Okay. Then Ina-senpai, please handle the breeding...
- Yeah, shall the 3 of us try going now?
オッケー。
Okay.
はい、いってらっしゃい。
Yup, have a good trip.
ブリーディングお願いします！
- はい！
Please take care of the breeding!
- Yup!
よいしょ。ほんじゃあ…
Alright. Well then...
アルゲン乗ってた方がいいですか？それとも…プテラ乗って…
- アルゲンかな。
Is it better to ride an Argent? Or... ride a Pteranodon...
- Probably Argent.
オッケー。
Okay.
あ、てかワイバーン、君…ファブリーズ連れてくか。
こいつ弱いけど…
Ah, or Wyvern, you... shall I bring Fabreeze?
Though this one is weak...
イノシシとか必要。ちょっと後で終わったらな。
A boar or something is needed. A bit later when it's over.
オッケー。
Okay.
よいしょ。はい。ほんじゃあ火山行ってみよう。
Alright. Okay, let's head to the volcano then.
行ってみましょう。
Let's head there.
えーっと、これはどうやって行けばいいやつだ？
Um, how should we head there?
乗り物乗って…
- テレポート…最初はテレポートで行きやすいよ。
Riding a mount...
- Teleport... At first, it's easy to go by teleporting.
あ、テレポート。了解です。ちょっと水のままなきゃ。
Ah, teleport. Got it. Wait, I need to drink water.
そうだね。
True.
えーっと…
Um...
水飲んで…
Drank water...
よいしょ。
Alright.
乱暴持ってくの、もういってけってことですか、まったく。
Carrying wild things, saying just go already, jeez.
コメント欄は心配性の人が多いんですから。
Because there are many worrisome people in the comment section.
ある、あるよ。
- しょうがにゃいにゃあ。
There are, there are.
- Can't be helped, meow.
私はすべてを失う覚悟で全部持っていくから。
I'm going all in with the resolve to lose everything.
しょうがにゃいにゃあ。どんだけ心配性なんですか。
Can't be helped, meow. Just how worrisome are you guys?
スリル。百戦の猛者ですけど。
Thrill. Even though I'm a seasoned veteran.
スリルを味わうの、スリルを。
It's to taste the thrill, the thrill.
よいしょ。
Alright.
めんどくさい心配性のおじさんが…
Annoying, overly worried old guys...
よいしょ。はい、行けます。
Alright, yes, ready to go.
コメントのオジサンが騒ぎ立てている。
The old guys in the comments are making a fuss.
えーっと、ほんじゃあ着地いけるか？
Um, so then, can we land?
これは乗っていますか？あ、乗ってる乗ってる。
- 乗ってる。
Are they riding this? Ah, they are, they are.
- Riding it.
よし、行くぞー！
Alright, let's go!
とーっ！邪魔！私飛んだし！こうやって被ってくるんだなー。
Wheee! Get out of the way! I jumped!
It keeps overlapping like this, huh?
被ってくるね。待っとくわ。
- はーい。
It overlaps, yeah. I'll wait.
- Okay.
そうだね。ちょっと早くどけてほしいなこいつ。
Right. I kind of want this guy to move quickly.
いいよ。
It's fine.
えーっと、ほんじゃあ火山にレッツゴー！
Um, so then, let me go to the volcano!
よーし、行くぞー！
- オッケー。
Alright, let's go!
- Okay.
でもあれだよね。だから水とギリギリなんか火山と生え際のところにいるパイロ…
But you know, that's why, Pyromanes near the water
and right on the edge of the volcano...
そうだね。それが一番いいかもしれないね。
That's right. That might be the best option.
じゃあ一旦海辺に行くか。
- そうだね。
Then shall we head to the seaside first?
- Yeah.
よいしょ、よいしょ。
Alright, alright.
イェーイ！
Yay!
このまま真っ直ぐ行って…あの滝の近くね、ちょうど。ねー。
Go straight like this... near that waterfall, right there. Right.
行ってくれたら。
If you go there.
もうちょっとゆっくりおいで、アルゲン
Come a little slower, Argen.
あ、大丈夫です、大丈夫です
Ah, I'm okay, I'm okay.
最悪プテラも持ってきてるんで 帰り荷物少なかったらプテラでも帰れます
Worst case, I brought a Ptera too, so if we have less luggage, we can return on Ptera.
オッケー 一応そこにいるけどね 1匹
Okay. There's one over there, though.
連れてってみるか
Want to try taking it along?
まだ遠いか？ 1回下見てみる？
Is it still far? Want to check below once?
もうちょい見れそうだね もうちょいちょっと...
Looks like we can see a bit more. A bit more...
もうちょい見てから行くか
Shall we go after checking a bit more?
このあたりにいたらめちゃめちゃ嬉しい
I'd be so happy if it's around here.
あ、めちゃ良い！ あ、いるいるいるいる！
Ah, super good! Ah, there it is!
いました？
Was it there?
一応いる
There is one, at least.
どんな見た目？わ、すごい！
What does it look like? Wow, awesome!
あ、燃えてるやつね
Ah, the flaming one, right?
カラフルなやついるね、こっちに
There's a colorful one here.
うん、あ、いる？
Yeah, ah, is it there?
うん、あ、すごい！ ジンオウガみたいな色してるよ！
Yeah. Ah, amazing! It has colors like Zinogre!
本当だ！ ジンオウガがいる！
It's true! There's a Zinogre!
ジンオウガやめてくださいよ！
Please stop calling it Zinogre!
ジンオウガいる！
There's a Zinogre!
ちょっと待って！
Wait a second!
いや、でもガチでジンオウガだぞ、これ
No, but seriously, this is a Zinogre.
ちょっと誘えるかな？いけるかな？ おー！あっち！
Can I entice it? Can I? Woah, hot!
燃えてます！
It's burning!
大丈夫？
Are you okay?
こっち来い！こっち来い！海辺に今！
Come here! Come here! To the beach now!
海辺こっちだとあれだよ、海辺...
Beach this way is... beach...
あ、いいね、いいね、いいね
Ah, good, good, good.
本当だ、ジンオウガだ！
It really is Zinogre!
ジンオウガだから、ジンオウガだけど...
Because it's Zinogre, it's Zinogre, but...
ちょっと待って、ここで...
Wait a second, here...
あー！
Ahhh!
大丈夫？
Are you okay?
燃えた！
I'm burning!
大丈夫、プテラそのまま置いておいていいよ、浮いてるから
It's fine, you can leave Ptera there since it's floating.
で、それで攻撃をしなきゃいけない
And then we have to attack it.
あ、綺麗やね
Ah, it's pretty.
あれだ、下に降りちゃった
Ah, it fell down below.
えー！どうしよう？ プテラで攻撃できないよね？
What should we do? We can't attack with Ptera, right?
プテラで攻撃するしかないかも
We might have no choice but to attack with Ptera.
それか私あれ、テリジノ持ってきてるけど
Or I brought a Therizino, though.
テリジノでも行けるならって感じかな
If Therizino works, then maybe.
ちょっと浮かせて回復中です
Floating it a bit and recovering.
オッケー
Okay.
テリジノ行くか
Shall we go with Therizino?
倒さないで、でもテリジノって...
Don't kill it, but Therizino...
テリジノでもワンチャンいけるかもしんない
With Therizino, we might have a chance.
そっか、私足がないや、ごめん
Ah, right, I don't have a mount. Sorry.
どちらかプテラ、テレポーターまで連れて来れたりする？無理か
Could either of you bring Ptera to the teleporter? Impossible?
今頑張って...ちょっと待ってくださいね
I'm trying now... please wait a moment.
私ターゲット取ってるから、ちょっと...
I'm drawing target right now, so...
本当ですか？やべっ、アルゲンの体力がなくなってしまって
Really? Oh no, my Argen is low on health.
落とされました！あ、なんかバグった
I got dropped! Ah, it glitched.
フラグ回収お疲れ様。サンキュー！
Thanks for triggering the flag! Thank you!
1級フラグ建築士の方でしたか。1級フラグ建築士だったか
So you were a certified flag builder...
やばい、登れなくてやばい
Oh no, I can't climb up, this is bad.
いける！行け！こんなもん！
You can do it! Go! This is nothing!
ちょっと、ちょっと待っとくわ
I'll wait a little bit.
待って、なんか誰かの...エリートファミ...
Wait, someone's... Elite Fami...
こっちか。誰か置いてったのかと思っちゃった
This way? I thought someone left it behind.
裸足で 助けてね
Barefoot... Save me...
こっちじゃないか？
Isn't it this way?
ターゲット取らないと、でも
We need to draw aggro though.
登りたいのに登れない
I want to climb, but I can't climb...
ヒットポイント...あ、でもリジェネ上がっちゃうな
Hit points... ah, but regen will go up.
私ターゲット今取ってるから...
I'm drawing target right now...
一定時間...まあ消えてる...
For a certain time... well, disappearing...
いろは、乗れそうだったら乗ってほしい。こいつ乗らないと...
Iroha, if you can mount it, I want you to mount it. If you don't mount this...
乗れない！来た来た来た！乗った！やば、ハマった！やばい！ハマり！
I can't mount... It's coming, coming! I mounted! Oh no, stuck! Oh no, stuck!
こいつ、パイロン、パイロン。こいつ、まだ乗れない、これ
This one, Pyron, Pyron. This one, you can't mount yet.
体力半分以下じゃないと乗れないはず
You can't mount unless its health is below half.
なるほど。ちょっと待ってくださいね
I see. Please wait a moment.
体力わかる？これ
Can you tell its health? This...
難しいね。でも体に血が滲み始めたら、だいぶ削れてる兆候かな
It's difficult. But if blood starts showing on its body, that's a sign it's taken a lot of damage.
よいしょ。まだかな
Up we go. Not yet, maybe?
それまだずっと一人でヘイト取ってられそうですか？
Can you keep holding hate by yourself for a while longer?
まだ行ける
Still fine.
あ、じゃあちょっと、一旦...あ、ごめん！倒しちゃった！
Ah, then a little, once... ah, sorry! I killed it!
あ、倒しちゃった？オッケー、オッケー
Ah, you killed it? Okay, okay.
まあしゃーない。あ、でも倒せるってことが分かったから大丈夫だ
Well, it can't be helped. Ah, but we know we can kill it, so it's fine.
オッケーだね。手加減したら行けるわ
Okay then. If we hold back, we can do it.
そうだね、そうしよう
Yeah, let me do that.
じゃあプテラを、すまんが呼んで...
Then sorry, call Ptera...
呼んで追従で...あれ？！崖から落ちて死ぬー！
Call it and set to follow... Huh?! Falling off the cliff, gonna die!
あ、死なない、なんで？
Ah, didn't die, why?
俺を殺してくれ！
Kill me!
今どこに置いたっけな...
Where did I leave it just now...
じゃあ、またさっきの湖連れてきてくれたら私タンクやるから
Then if you bring it to that lake again, I'll tank.
オッケー
Okay.
減ったら誰か乗ってあれしてほしい
When it decreases, I want someone to mount and do that.
オッケー
Okay.
じゃあ、自分今からポータル行くから、ござるさん多分自分が飛んだら分かるはず
Then I'm heading to the portal now, Gozaru-san will probably know when I teleport.
よいしょ。助かります
Up we go. That helps.
ちょっと休憩させつつ...
Taking a little break while...
さっきのね、パイロン、レベル50になったから多分余裕だったんだよ
Earlier, Pyron reached level 50, so it was probably easy.
待って、白髪のプテラいたっけ？いなくないか？
Wait, was there a white-haired Ptera? Isn't it gone?
あー、白髪のプテラいない。よいしょ
Ah, no white-haired Ptera. Up we go.
近くの敵倒しとくか
Should I defeat nearby enemies?
やっと...こっちかな...この辺かな...
Finally... maybe this way... around here...
ござるさん迷子？迷子ー？あ、そこにいて！
Gozaru-san, lost? Lost? Ah, stay there!
飛んできたら分かるやつ。あ、そうそうそう。そのあたりに...
You'll know once you fly over. Ah, yeah yeah. Around there...
ちょっと安全地帯に行って...
Let me go to a safe area...
こっち、行き過ぎていたポータル...
Here, the portal I went too far past...
えっと... よしよし
Let's see... Okay, okay.
息吸っているんですか？
Are you taking a breath?
そう言えば... 声聞こえたら...
Speaking of which... if you hear a voice...
ここだ！ここだ！
Over here! Over here!
どこー？
Where are you~?
ここだよー！地図開いてー！
Here I am~! Open the map~!
何色ー？
What color~?
早く来てー！来てー！虫がいやのー！あー！姿が見えないー！
Hurry up and come~! Come~! I hate bugs~! Ah~! I can't see them~!
パイロ乗った後にさ、敵倒さないといけないんだよね。
After riding the Pyromane, we have to defeat the enemies.
合流できます！近くにいるから大丈夫か。
We can join up! Since we're nearby, it should be fine.
一応合流できる体になりました！
I'm now in a state where I can join up!
あ、オッケー！ありがとう！で、追従切ってもらえたら...
Ah, okay! Thank you! So if you could stop following...
着地！ありがとう！
Landed! Thank you!
あ、乗れた！サンキュー！
Ah, mounted! Thank you!
これでじゃあ、合流しに行きやす！
Alright then, let me go join up!
火山です！
At the volcano!
火山... えーっと、恐竜何連れてったら一番いいかな？
Volcano... Um, which dino would be best to bring?
一応今タンクはできてるから、プテラでも平気そうなの？
Since we have tanks right now, is a Pteranodon fine?
テリジノで行ける。さっき55倒せたから...
We can go with Therizino. Since we beat level 55 earlier...
うん、多分いけるんじゃないかな。
Yeah, I think we can probably do it.
あれ？待って！日課のミッションって今すぐやっても達成になるってこと今知った！
Huh? Wait! I just realized that doing the daily missions right now still counts toward completion!
ね！今落ちてきたね！本当だ。
Right! It just popped up! You're right.
えっと... あれ？この辺で拾わなかったっけ？
Um... Huh? Didn't I pick it up around here?
水に落ちちゃいましたかね？アイテム...
Did it fall into the water? The item...
アイテムのこの辺だったような...
I feel like the item was around here...
アイテム、岩のところにあるよ。
The item is over by the rock.
ありがたやー！これか！
Thank you~! Is it this?
あれ、ドアどこだっけなー
Huh, where was the door again?
あら！行かないでー！
Oh no! Don't go~!
追従が解除されてないです、ござるさん！
Follow mode hasn't been cancelled, Gozaru-san!
持っていかれましたー！
It was carried away~!
帰ってきた。ちょっと待ってください。えーっと、着地にしたんだけどな...
It came back. Please wait a moment. Um, I set it to land though...
えっとね、そのアルゲンに乗りながら追従解除ボタンを押してほしいかも。
Um, while riding that Argentavis, I think you should press the stop following button.
なるほど、アルゲンに乗っちゃってるのか。
I see, it's following while riding the Argentavis.
あ、でも来たっぽい、来たっぽい！オッケー！
Ah, but looks like it's back, it's back! Okay!
どこ行くねん！どこ行くねん！ほんま！
Where are you going?! Where are you going?! Seriously!
エナも終わった？
Is Ena done too?
あ、はい！合流する？あ、はい！
Ah, yes! Join up? Ah, yes!
なんかみんなのところ合流しちゃって大丈夫だよ。あ、オッケーです。
It's fine to join up where everyone is. Ah, okay.
火山のところにテレポートで...
Teleporting to the volcano area...
危ねぇ、マジで... 体が燃えるところだった...
That was close, seriously... My body was about to burn...
わー！蛇だー！
Woah! A snake!
え、騎乗解除やめてー！すまん！蛇やって...
Eh, stop dismounting me~! Sorry! The snake...
騎乗解除やめてー！やめてー！
Stop dismounting me~! Stop it~!
ありがたやー
Thank goodness~
うわー！カマキリだー！
Woah~! It's a mantis~!
いっぱい来るな、ここ。
A lot are coming here.
そして再度原油を... 原油...
And once again, crude oil... Crude oil...
オッケー、一旦原油やるか。
Okay, shall we do crude oil for now?
ここにちょうど一匹いますわ。
There's exactly one right here.
ちょうど水の中入ってた、あいつ！
That guy was just in the water!
えなちゃん、ごめん、そこはさ、違うところテレポートしちゃうから...
Ena-chan, sorry, teleporting there will send you somewhere else...
こっち連れてきて。はいはい、こっちこっちこっち。どうよ？
Bring it over here. Yes yes, over here. How about this?
吠えたら... あ、ここじゃねぇ。ミスった。
When it barks... Ah, not here. My mistake.
でも誰かに乗ってもらわないとなんだよね。乗るか、ござるが。
But someone needs to ride it. I'll ride it then, Gozaru.
なんか今自分がヘイト取っちゃってる... あ、そんなことないか。
Did I grab the aggro just now... Ah, maybe not.
あ、吠えたかも！乗れるかも！オッケー、行ってみる！
Ah, it might have barked! Might be rideable! Okay, I'll go check!
追従切れない... 追従ちょっと...
Can't cancel follow... Follow is a bit...
乗れる？いや、騎乗出てこない。
Can you ride? No, mount prompt isn't showing up.
泳いでるからかな？フフちゃんのほう。
Is it because it's swimming? Towards Fufu-chan's side.
いや、出てこないな... ごめん！
No, it's not coming up... Sorry!
ごめん、ござる、もう一回連れてきて...
Sorry, Gozaru, bring it over one more time...
乗ってもらっていこう。
Let's have them hop on.
あ、確かに。一回行かないとダメか。
Ah, right. We have to go at least once.
やばい！
Oh no!
すべてが…
Everything...
えっ、追従… 追従じゃダメなのかな？
Wait, is setting them to follow not working?
いや、まだかもね。
No, maybe not yet.
あ、まだだった！あー、ヘイト買っちゃった！やばい！
Ah, not yet! Ah, I drew aggro! Oh no!
急いで乗らないと、切れちゃうのか。
If I don't hurry and ride it, will it drop aggro?
いてっ！
Ouch!
あらららら。
Oh dear.
あ、脚がなくなった。えっと…
Ah, I lost my mount. Um...
あーてででで。脚が…
Ow ow ow. My mount...
うわー、ちょっと借りるか。
Woah, guess I'll borrow one.
申し訳ない。絶対殺さないという気持ちで…
Sorry about this. I promise I won't get it killed...
プテラお借りしまー…あ、でもそっか、手綱がないのか。
Borrowing your Ptera... Ah, wait, there's no saddle.
そうなんです。
That's right.
あー、こりゃちょっと終わったかもしれないです。ソーリー。
Ah, this might be the end for me. Sorry.
大丈夫か？ / 大丈夫ですか？
Are you okay? / Are you okay?
そっちに向かうための脚がなくなっちゃって…
I lost my mount to head over your way...
私のプテラが…
Ah, my Ptera...
ちょっと待って。
Wait a second.
俺のプテラ…
My Ptera...
あー、寝袋置いとけばよかったなー。
Ah, I should have placed down a sleeping bag.
えっと、皮… キチン…
Um, hide... chitin...
イイミさんのBBBだったらいるけど…
Iimi-san's BBB is here though...
あー、ワンチャンそれ… 絶対殺さないという…
Ah, maybe that could work... Promising not to get it killed...
あ、いいよ、乗ってって。トワの。
Ah, sure, go ahead and ride Towa's.
一旦借りるか。ちょっと借りよう。 / いいよいいよ、借りて。
I'll borrow it for a bit. Let's borrow it. / Go ahead, borrow it.
あ、あれ？どれだ？
Ah, wait, which one is it?
これね、ワシの適当につけた名前のプテラ。
This one, my Ptera with a randomly given name.
ちょっとハマってる。
It's a bit stuck.
よいしょ。何だっけ？か、火山？火山だね。
Heave-ho. What was it? Vol... Volcano? It's the volcano, right.
プテラ、大丈夫かな、アイツ？なんかスタックしてない？
Is that Ptera gonna be okay? Is it stuck?
スタックしちゃってる？ちょっと自分もちょっとこのハイ… そーっと借りちゃいます。よいしょ。
Is it stuck? Let me gently borrow this high... Heave-ho.
あれ？原油って余分にどっかに無かったっけな？
Huh? Didn't we have extra oil somewhere?
原油は残念ながら旋盤で使っちゃった。 / マジか！倒さないとやばいな。
Unfortunately, the oil was used up in the lathe. / Really? We need to defeat it then.
あ、でも、あるわ！ちょうどあるわ！行くわ、これで！
Ah, wait, there is! We have just enough! I'm going with this!
え？これで？おいおいおい！なんでお前、ここにいるんだよ！
Huh? With this? Hey hey hey! Why are you over here?!
今、乗れるかな？
Can I ride it now?
こっち、こっち、こっち…
Over here, over here...
テレポートのところにでっかい恐竜がいる！
There's a huge dinosaur at the teleport location!
いやー！こっちこっちこっち…
Nooo! Over here, over here...
とーさま！あかん、あかんて！大丈夫か？！
Towa-sama! No, no! Are you okay?!
イキロが、イキロがヘイト買っちゃってるかも！こっちこっちこっち！
Ikiro... Ikiro might have drawn aggro! This way, this way!
え、マジ？ / そうそうそう！テレポートのところにでっかい恐竜いて引き付けてるから、今のうちに！
Wait, really? / Yeah, yeah, yeah! There's a big dino at the teleporter pulling aggro, so do it now!
あ、やばいやばいやばい！ / こっち来て、こっち来て…
Ah, bad bad bad! / Come over here, come over here...
あ、倒しとくか。 / イキロどこ行った？
Ah, should I defeat it? / Where did Ikiro go?
なんか、アルゼンが… / ありがとう、ママちゃん！
Looks like an Argen... / Thank you, Mama-chan!
はいはい、今のうち今のうち！移動するなら今のうち！
Alright, hurry, hurry! If you're gonna move, do it now!
トワちゃんの、でもね、キリヤねぇはまだ生きている。
Towa-chan's... but Kiriya-nee is still alive.
あ、本当に？オッケー、今から飛びます。
Ah, really? Okay, I'm flying over now.
オッケーオッケー。
Okay, okay.
よいしょ。生き残ったのね、お前も。
Heave-ho. So you survived too, huh?
こー…よいしょ。
Here... heave-ho.
下、危ないんだよなー。
It's dangerous down below...
ロザルが死んだところが… あ、ここか。
Where Rozaru died... Ah, is it here?
よいしょ。マジで？！
Heave-ho. Seriously?!
すーい。イキちゃん、ありがとうー。
Swoop. Iki-chan, thank you!
ん？やばいか、これ？
Hm? Is this bad?
BBBに乗ろうか。
Should I ride BBB?
これ、やばいな。
This is bad.
やばい！
Oh no!
よいしょ。
Heave-ho.
ハードな…
Quite harsh...
ねー、なかなかハードなとこやな。ちょっと拠点が怖いな。さっきそいつに旋盤壊されたんだよね。
Yeah, it's pretty harsh here. Our base is scary. That thing destroyed our lathe earlier.
え、これ誰だ？
Huh, who is this?
グリフィン、手に入れてるー！
They got a Griffin!
あ、原油 200… / 原油 200個じゃないか？
Ah, oil 200... / Isn't that 200 oil?
あ、それか！ / うん。
Ah, that's it! / Yeah.
ちょっとあれしとくか。原油入れますよー。
Let me do that then. Putting in the oil~!
はーい！
Okay!
しまっとくか。
Should I put it away?
きたー！メガテリウムとグリフィン！
Awesome! Megatherium and Griffin!
あ、ナイス！ / あ、全員持ってきてもらえるかい？なんなら。
Nice! / Ah, can you bring everyone over if possible?
オッケー。
Okay.
6個だね。
There are six.
あ、ありがとう。キリヤねぇいるー。助かるよー。
Ah, thanks. Kiriya-nee is here. Helps a lot!
キンダス、しまっとくわ。
I'll store Kindas away.
狡猾のアーティファクトなんだ、次。
Next is the Artifact of the Cunning.
じゃあ、あれか？
Then, is it that one?
よいしょ。入れて…
Heave-ho. Putting it in...
よいしょ。ダメだ。
Heave-ho. No good.
はいはい。あれ？
Alright. Huh?
アッキー。 / ほい。
Aki. / Yeah?
よいしょ。
Heave-ho.
やばい。あ、ちょっとあっちまで行くのにまた飛んで行かなきゃいけないか。
Oh no. Ah, do we have to fly again to get over there?
BBBがしまえない。よいしょ。
Can't put BBB away. Heave-ho.
しまっとくか。
Guess I'll store it.
はーい、ありがたやー。
Okay, thank goodness~
はーい。
Sure thing.
よいしょ。
Heave-ho.
あ、もうそろそろなのか。
Ah, is it almost time?
そうだね、もうそろそろだね。
Yeah, almost time now.
メガテリウムとグリフィンか。
Megatherium and Griffin, huh?
あ、大丈夫ですか？
Ah, are you okay?
ボタン先輩、予備のプテラが一応ここに一匹
Botan-senpai, there's a spare Pteranodon here for now.
あ、私プテラ大丈夫だよ
Ah, my Pteranodon is fine.
大丈夫でした？オッケーオッケー
You're good? Okay, okay.
さぁ...
Now then...
行くか。やるか。
Shall we go? Shall we do this?
やるか。
Shall we?
やるか...
Shall we...
一、二、三...
1, 2, 3...
四、五...
4, 5...
え、メガテリウムのサドルがある！
Eh, there's a Megatherium saddle!
まずい！
This is bad!
ちょっと待って...
Wait a second...
今ここで手に入るの、世界で一番やばい！
Getting this right here is the craziest thing in the world!
やばい！襲われてる！
Oh no! I'm being attacked!
やめて！気絶させられてる！助けて！
Stop! I'm getting knocked out! Help!
メガテリウムのサドルは持ってるよ、私。
I have the Megatherium saddle.
持ってる...
I have it...
助けて！助けて！
Help me! Help me!
そこから離れな！気絶してるんかい！耐え！
Get away from there! You're knocked out?! Hang in there!
大丈夫？
Are you okay?
あっち、ちちち！
Hot, hot, hot!
一旦全員の報酬獲得したから...
Since we've retrieved everyone's rewards for now...
いやぁ！
Nooo!
これまずい！
This is bad!
死んでるって！
I'm dying!
やめろー！
Stop it-!
えーっと、全息それを引き連れて...
Um, everyone took their...
帰ります、帰ります、帰ります！
Going back, going back, going back!
こざるの荷物も拾えたりしますか？
Can you pick up Kozaru's items as well?
行けるか？
Can you make it?
アルゲンが生きてればバッグの中に全部突っ込んで...
If Argen is alive, stuff everything inside its bag...
あ、オッケーオッケー。じゃあ...
Ah, okay okay. Then...
いーなの近くに降ろすわ。
I'll drop it near Ina.
大丈夫でございますか？
Are you doing alright?
持ってきました、多分。
I brought it back, probably.
助かります！
That helps so much!
よいしょ。
Up we go.
なんか知らない子入ってない？この家の中に。
Isn't there someone's tame we don't know in here?
いや、野生だよね？
No, it's wild, right?
オッケー。
Okay.
これ、みんなのプテラがここにめっちゃいるんだけど、これどうしたらいい？
There are so many of everyone's Pteranodons here, what should we do with them?
あ、持ってく、持ってく。
Ah, I'll take them, I'll take them.
持ってく？
Take them?
お願いします。
Please do.
あいよ。こんな感じか。帰るか。
Alrighty. Is that it? Shall we head back?
そやね。
Yeah.
一旦帰りましょう。
Let's head back for now.
あんまり持て...
Can't carry too much...
みんな、ちょっと着地しといてほしいね。
I want everyone to land for a bit.
えーっとね、メガテリウムとグリフィンは冷蔵庫の中に入れといた。
Um, I put the Megatherium and Griffin in the fridge.
あいよ。
Alright.
一旦これ帰る？
Are we going back for now?
一旦帰っちゃってもいいかな。
I think it's fine to head back now.
オッケー。
Okay.
うん。
Yeah.
飛んでるぞい。
I'm flying!
あ、待って。アルゲンもしや前...
Ah, wait. Is Argen perhaps...
メガテリウムさ、サドル付けてくれてるんだけど。
They actually equipped a saddle on the Megatherium for us.
ありがたや。
How wonderful.
お前、あ、待って。
You... Ah, wait.
本当だ！
It's true!
元々付いてたんだっけか？
Was it already on?
オッケー？
Okay?
うん。オッケー。
Yep. Okay.
付いてるよ。
It's equipped.
行こう。
Let's go.
オッケーオッケー。
Okay, okay.
あれ、私のプテラどこ行った？
Huh, where did my Pteranodon go?
あ、連れてっちゃってるかも、今。ファボリーズ？
Ah, I might be taking it with me. Fabreeze?
あ、ファボリーズ... 違う。
Ah, Fabreeze... Wait, no.
違う、あ、キンダス... あ、一緒、一緒、ごめんごめん！一緒について来ちゃってるわ、ごめんごめん！
No, ah, Kindas... Ah, it came along with me, sorry, sorry!
キンダスさん...
Kindas-san...
キンダスさんも一緒に来ちゃってたわ、ソーリーソーリー。
Kindas-san came along with me too, sorry, sorry.
すまぬよ。
My bad.
待ってよ。
Wait up.
おい！カマキリやめろ！
Hey! Mantis, stop it!
キンダスどこ行った？
Where did Kindas go?
あ、メガテリってそうなんだ。
Ah, so that's how Megatherium is.
あれ？キンダスいない？
Huh? Kindas isn't here?
めっちゃ遠くにいる。
It's super far away.
ん？どこだ？どこだ？どこだ？
Hmm? Where? Where? Where?
めっちゃ上にいる。めっちゃ上にいる。
It's super high up. Super high up.
降りてきてー！待ってよ。
Come down~! Wait up.
はいはい、降りてきてくれた。オッケーオッケー。
Alright, it came down. Okay, okay.
はい、ありがとう。
Alright, thank you.
オッケー。
Okay.
オッケー、はいはいはい。
Okay, yes, yes, yes.
ほな... ほな...
Well then... well then...
帰ろう。
Let's head back.
次は... あれ、あれか。
Next is... that one?
ミッションじゃなくてあれか、イベントか。
Not a mission, an event?
そう、イベントがあるからもう一旦回るのやめて帰ろうかなと。
Yeah, there's an event, so I thought I'd stop exploring and head back.
オッケー。
Okay.
はい。
Yep.
まぁアルゲンいるんだったら、アルゲン6匹いるんだったら...
Well if we have Argen, if we have 6 Argens...
行っちゃってもいいんだけどね、洞窟。
we could go to the cave, though.
メガテリいるなら正直メガテリで全然いい。
If we have Megatherium, honestly Megatherium is totally fine.
行けるはず。
We should be able to go.
アルゲンまだそんなに実はいないんですよ。
Truth is, we don't actually have that many Argens yet.
ユウティラに邪魔されてそんなに実は...
We were disrupted by Yutyrannus, so not that many...
あれ、アルゲンって交配させてないんだっけ？
Wait, didn't we breed the Argens?
交配させて今出来上がったやつ1匹と、
We bred them and have 1 complete one now, and...
うん。
Yeah.
昨日捕まえた3匹...
the 3 we caught yesterday...
きー...
Key...
あ、じゃあ5匹いるじゃん。
Oh, then there are five of them.
なー。で、あとあと1匹捕まえれば...
Yeah. And if we catch one more...
って感じ。その交配させたやつがメスで...
That's the plan. If the one we bred is a female...
メスだったらその交配終わった子供と生ませたら...
...and if we breed her with the offspring after...
いいんじゃないか？
Wouldn't that work out?
多分ね。
Probably.
あとはあれだ、なんちゃらブリュー作らないと。
Also, we need to make that whatever-it's-called brew.
あ、そうだ、メディカルブリューね。
Oh right, Medical Brew.
ほしいな。回復薬がほしい。
I want some. I need healing potions.
よしよし。
Alright, alright.
ほい。
Up we go!
メディカルブリューってどれだっけ？
Which one was Medical Brew again?
メディカルブリューは料理鍋にティントベリー...
For Medical Brew, in a Cooking Pot, Tintoberries...
ティントベリーと麻酔薬入れればOKなはず。
Tintoberries and Narcotics. Put them in and it should work.
鍋作んないとじゃん。
Then we need to craft a pot.
鍋、家の中かどっかに置いたと思うんだけど。
I think I placed a pot inside the house or somewhere.
あ、あるわ。あるじゃん。
Oh, there is one! Look, right there.
大量生産してほしい。
I want us to mass-produce it.
そう、でもティントベリーがそんなになくて...
Yeah, but we don't have that many Tintoberries...
あ、じゃあちょっと集めてもらわないと...
Ah, then we'll have to gather some...
ティントベリー400個あるけど。
I have 400 Tintoberries, though.
あ、じゃあそれ全部使っちゃってOK。
Oh, then feel free to use all of those!
赤いやつか、ティントベリーって。
Tintoberries are the red ones, right?
はーい。めっちゃ持ってるよ、確か私も。
Yep. I have a ton of them too, pretty sure.
えーっと...中海所かな？え、これで...
Ummm... the offshore station? Wait, with this...
うわ、虫が！
Whoa, bugs!
うわー！やば！パイロ来てる！
Whoa! Oh no, Pyromane is coming!
あ、これ乗せられない...
Ah, I can't ride this...
うわー！これやばい！
Whoa! This is bad!
これ倒せるかな？倒せるかな？
Can we defeat this? Can we defeat it?
大丈夫ですか？
Are you okay?
うわー！一旦タゲ離れた方がいいかも。
Whoa! Maybe we should back off and reset aggro.
これ誰にタゲってんだ？誰にタゲってんだ？
Who is this targeting? Who is it targeting?
誰だろう？あ！ファボリーズが！ファボリーズだ！
Who could it be? Ah! Febreze is... Febreze!
うわー！ファボリーズ！
Whoa! Febreze!
お前、ちょっと降りてこい、降りてこい！
Hey, you guys come down, come down!
ファボリーズはサドルが付いていますが...
Febreze has a saddle, but...
うわー！ちょっとちょっとちょっと！
Whoa! Wait, wait, wait, wait!
遠くに離して...
Lead them far away...
うわー、なんかめっちゃ飛んでくる！
Whoa, so many of them are flying over!
あー！ファボリーズがやられたー！
Ah! Febreze got killed!
こっちこっちこっちこっち！
Over here, over here, over here!
一旦ちょっと拠点から離れて...
Let me get away from the base for a second...
あー、やばい！お前、お前死ぬか！キレやね！
Ah, bad! Hey, are you gonna die? Kire-ya-ne!
お前死んじゃいそうだな、お前な。
You look like you're about to die, buddy.
くそ、ハード拠点。
Damn, this hard base location.
水の瓶はどこにしまったかな...
Where did I store the water bottle...
お、いいね、土台。
Oh nice, a foundation.
なんかどっかにしまったんだよな...
I definitely stored it somewhere...
ワンチャン、モンボに入れてテレポの方がいいかも。
Cryopodding them and teleporting might be better.
ちょっと2対1近くにいて、厳しいかも。
Having two almost against one nearby is tough.
おとり行きましょうか、体しかできることないですけど。
Should I act as a decoy? My body is all I can offer though.
あで、ひえー！
Ah... Hiee!
どういうこっちゃね、ここの拠点。
What is up with this base area?
よしよしよし...
Alright, alright...
でもここ...
But here...
あと1日しか居ないから。
We're only here for one more day.
確かに。
True enough.
しかも金属は美味しいから、わざわざ出向かなくてもあるし。
Plus the metal node is rich here without going far.
資源が美味しいから...
Since the resources are great...
待って、トーチどこやったっけかな...忘れたわ。
Wait, where did I put the torch... I forgot.
お前！お前らだ！お前らだ！
You! It's you guys! It's you guys!
チェイスちゃん、これ死んでるんで、もう体何もないんで...
Chase-chan, this one is dead, there's nothing on the body...
あ、拠点から離してほしいかも。遠くに行ってほしい。
Ah, pull them away from base please. Go far away.
それでね、皮なんちゃら...
And then, leather something...
キレやねー！お前の火傷...お前！
Kire-ya-ne! Your burn... You!
乗ってくれたら、ファストトラベルするよ。
If you hop on, I'll fast travel.
キレやねーが全然降りてこなくてさ...
Kire-ya-ne wouldn't come down at all...
やばい！ちょっと1回飛ぶ。
Oh no! Wait, flying out once.
オッケーオッケー。やばいから1回飛ぶ。
Okay, okay. It's dangerous so flying out once.
あ、よかったよかった！ちょっとこっちこっち！
Ah, thank goodness! Over here, over here!
飛んでるー！1回飛んだ、ちょっとやばいから。
It's flying! Flew away once since it was dangerous.
あ、ありがとうございます！
Ah, thank you very much!
で、あとプテラのサドル回収しに行かなきゃでござる...
Also, I have to go collect the Pteranodon saddle...
これちょっとどうしようかな...
What should I do about this...
飛んでるー！
It's flying!
一旦帰ってきた
I'm back for now.
おかえりー
Welcome back!
怒ってる！やめて、やめて！
It's mad! Stop, stop it!
大丈夫か？
Are you okay?
今みんな大丈夫か？
Is everyone okay right now?
テレポータのところにパイロがずっといて帰れないんだよね
Pyro is sitting by the teleporter, so we can't get back...
オッケー、じゃあちょっと待って
Okay, hold on a second.
テレポート…あの、仮拠点の上のとこ？
The teleporter... you mean above the temporary base?
そう！あ、じゃなくて…えっと火山先！火山、火山！
Yeah! Ah, wait, no... at the volcano! Volcano, volcano!
火山先か！
At the volcano, I see!
そうそう、火山で帰れなくて今…
Yeah, yeah, we can't get back because of the volcano, so right now...
ちょっと待って、綺麗に一回モンスターボールにしまって…
Wait a sec, let me pocket this real quick...
取れました！取れました！
Got it! Got it!
取れました？
You got it?
いーな先輩！
Ina-senpai!
オッケーオッケー、ちょっと待って
Okay okay, hold on.
これで…
With this...
ありがとう！
Thank you!
テレポートして帰ってもらって…
Please teleport back...
あ、オッケーオッケー、テレポート…
Ah, okay okay, teleporting...
あ、いける？いけそう？
Ah, can you make it? Looks good?
オッケー！
Okay!
飛べました！
Teleported!
あー！まだ…い、行けるか？
Ah! Still... c-can you go?
あ、トラベルしました！
Ah, I traveled!
オッケー、降りちゃった！
Okay, I got off!
ナイス！
Nice!
ナイス！いけた？
Nice! Did you make it?
いけた！
We made it!
帰ってこれたー！
We're back!
あ、よかったよかった！
Ah, glad to hear!
アルゲンがあんなところに…めっちゃ遠くに行っちゃった…
The Argen went way over there... so far away...
アルゲン！
Argen!
アルゲンいるよ、いるよ！
The Argen is here, here!
あ、帰ってきたよ、アルゲン
Ah, it came back, the Argen!
ちなみにファボリーズの死体って漁られたりしました？
By the way, did Fabreeze's corpse get looted?
ファボリーズは多分その拠点の近くにいるんだよね、多分
Fabreeze is probably near the base, I think.
死体が、なるほど…
The corpse, I see...
サドルだけ回収しなきゃ…サドルが…
I need to retrieve at least the saddle...
待ってよ、サドルだけ回収し…
Wait, retrieving just the saddle...
なんかめっちゃやばいやつが近くに…
Something super dangerous is nearby...
いる？
Is it there?
拠点に…あ、そうですね
At the base... Ah, yes.
あ、あいつだまた！あのデッカいやつか！
Ah, it's that guy again! That huge one!
デッカいやつです！
It's the huge one!
デッカいやつ…
The huge one...
えー！もう！
Ehh! Again?!
脚がね…
Its legs...
やばいやばい！
Oh no, oh no!
一旦拠点から離れよう！拠点から離れよう！遠く行こう、遠く！
Let's get away from base! Get away from base! Go far, far away!
まずい、これ！
This is bad!
まずい！
Bad!
あ、ごめん！アルゲンも付いて来ちゃった
Ah, sorry! The Argen followed us too.
これ、ユーティラで食える？
Can we take it with Yutyrannus?
ユーティラで行けるならユーティラでやってほしいかも
If we can do it with Yutyrannus, maybe we should.
戦えるなら…
If we can fight...
戦え！
Fight!
全然動かないんだけど！
It's not moving at all!
なにこのユーティラ！動かない！
What's with this Yuty! It's not moving!
は？
Huh?
なにこのユーティラ…
What's up with this Yuty...
これみんな、ヘイト取ったほうがいいか？
Should everyone try to pull aggro?
引っかかってるか何かかな？
Is it stuck on something?
やばいよ、それ！
That's bad!
いーなのユーティラも！よし！
Ina's Yuty too! Alright!
サドルなくなっちゃった…まいっか
The saddle's gone... oh well.
なんでこのユーティラ動かないんだ？
Why isn't this Yuty moving?
追従再定義…どのユーティラだ？
Redefine follow... which Yuty is it?
ユーティ、そもそも命令聞いてないよ！
Yuty isn't taking orders in the first place!
え、しまっちゃった？
Eh, did you put it away?
帰ってこれそう？行ったほうがいい？
Can you get back? Should I go over?
まずいな、これ…
This is bad...
ちょっと待ってね
Hold on a sec.
荷物預けて…ま、この辺なくなってもいいか
I'll put away items... well, if I lose these it's fine.
いけるか？いける？
Can you make it? Can you?
あー！頑張れー！
Ah! Do your best!
オッケーオッケーオッケー！
Okay okay okay!
今、他のやつ荒らしてほしいな。「生きろ」とか引っ張ってくれない、これ？
Can't someone lead "Ikiro" away or something?
トワに追従になってるから、追従切らないと無理かも
Since it's set to follow Towa, it might not work unless follow is turned off.
あ、そうだっけ？
Ah, is that so?
今、「生きろ」はトワ追従…そうそう。オッケーオッケー。でもこいつ戦うに…
Right now "Ikiro" is following Towa... yeah. Okay okay. But is this one set to fight?
無敵モードにした。どこ？
I put it in god mode. Where is it?
オッケーオッケー！
Okay okay!
どこだ？
Where is it?
オッケー、「生きろ」逃げました！ナイス！
Okay, "Ikiro" escaped! Nice!
逃げた？
It escaped?
荷物取りに行ってる？
Are you going to get your stuff?
拠点のほうにデカい恐竜がいて、そいつと今戦ってる
There's a big dino near the base, fighting it now.
仮拠点？強すぎる…あ、仮拠点のほうか！
Temp base? It's too strong... Ah, towards the temp base!
ナイス！倒せた！ナイス！
Nice! We killed it! Nice!
いけるか？
Can you make it?
これ何が…生肉と皮か？
What's this... raw meat and hide?
これでゴザルさんのサドルが取りに行けるかな？
Can we go retrieve Gozaru-san's saddle now?
あ、待って。ゴザルの自分の元の死体も取りに行かないとヤバいかも
Ah wait. Gozaru's original corpse needs to be retrieved too or it's bad.
どこだ？元の死体
Where is it? The original corpse.
さっき一番最初で…
Earlier, the very first one...
それはアルゲンの中に入ってる
That's inside the Argen.
アルゲン1ですか？
Inside Argen 1?
アルゲン1の中にない？そいつ連れて帰ってきたやつ
Isn't it inside Argen 1? The one brought back.
あれ？入って…
Huh? It's not...
いーながどれに入れたかな…
Wonder which one Ina put it in...
あ、私持ってます！
Ah, I have it!
あ、持ってるか！ありがとう！よかった！
Ah, you have it! Thank you! Glad to hear!
助かりました！
Thank you so much!
ほんじゃら、とりあえず…
Well then, for now...
ほんじゃら、これでイベントがあるから行くか！
Well then, since we have the event, shall we go?
ありがとうございます、いのうえ先輩！助かりましたー！
Thank you so much, Inoue-senpai! You saved me!
えっと、しま... テルボをしまった方がいいのかな...
Um... Should I put away the Terbo?
そうだね
Yeah.
えっと、よいしょ
Um, okay.
あ、白神の荷物はまた後でこれ取りに行くか。白神はたぶん荷物を置き去りだよね？
Ah, should I go retrieve Shirakami's items later? Shirakami probably left her items behind, right?
あー
Ah.
よいしょ
Here we go.
よ
Alright.
これね
This one.
ふー、あぶなーい
Whew, that was dangerous!
間に... 間に合わないよね？
Will we make... won't make it in time, right?
間に... 間に... あれっと
Make... make... wait...
よいしょ
Up we go.
多分間に... 間に... いや、間に合うかこれ？いけるか？
Maybe make... make... wait, can we make it? Can we go?
間に合うか？ 回す
Can we make it? Spinning!
間に合った！あ、みんななんかみんな行っちゃいな
We made it! Ah, everyone, you guys go ahead!
おーい
Hey~
はい
Yes.
よいしょ
There we go.
めっちゃ荷物パンパンにさせてそうだった
Looked like their inventory was completely packed full.
荷物パンパン！いのうえ先輩
Inventory is full! Inoue-senpai.
えっと、海岸の方だっけ？
Um, was it towards the coast?
何だっけ？
What was it?
イベント... なんかワープ...
Event... something warp...
キー作ってくれたって言ってた気がするけど
I feel like they said they made a key for us or something.
あ、さくらさん！
Ah, Sakura-san!
メディカルベリー
Medical Berry.
あの...
Um...
金属の鍋じゃないと無理っぽいな
Looks like it's impossible without a metal pot.
あと水を引いて来ないとキツイな
Also, it'll be tough if we don't bring water over.
革袋か何か、水筒か何か入れちゃい... 作っちゃい... 無理だった？
Couldn't we put water in a waterskin or canteen... craft one... was it impossible?
これ足んないわ
This isn't enough.
相当大変 そのやり方だと
It's really tough doing it that way.
そうだね、革袋にいっぱい水入れて作ってはー
Yeah, filling waterskins with plenty of water to craft...
あれ？ワープポイントどこだっけ？
Huh? Where was the warp point again?
何これ、どこ？
What's this? Where is it?
死んだかも？
Maybe I died?
あ、ベビー死んでしまった？
Ah, did the baby die?
多分...
Probably...
おふ...
Oof...
あれ？荷物ない、あれ？
Huh? Where's my stuff? Huh?
オーマイガー
Oh my god.
あ、テレポートの近く...
Ah, near the teleport...
あー、テレポートの近くの方か
Ah, near the teleport side, huh?
ここにサドルとかは入れておくか
Should I put saddles and stuff in here?
わさわさ、あれかな？
Rustle rustle, is that it?
えっと
Um...
テレポの近く...
Near the teleporter...
あ！
Ah!
死んでなくて、大人になってた！
It didn't die, it grew up into an adult!
あー！
Ahhh!
なんだ、よかったー！
What a relief, thank goodness!
よかったね！
That's great!
大人になってんだよね？
It grew up into an adult, right?
大人になってた！そっか！
It grew up! Ah, I see!
ふぅ
Phew.
行けないんだけどこれ
Wait, I can't go through here.
荷物しまったときか
Is it when I stored my items?
これイベント会場でどこから行くの？
From where do we go to the event location?
なんか... イベント会場...
Like... event venue...
えっと、テレポータから飛べるぐらいですか？
Um, can we fly from the teleporter?
あ、なるほど？
Ah, I see.
なんか一番下の欄にむきろぜなんちゃらかんちゃらみたいなやつが...
Like, in the bottom row, there's something like Mukiroze something something...
なんかワープでさ、テレポで行けないんだけど
For some reason with the warp, I can't go by teleporter.
え？
Eh?
置いてっていいか、じゃあ
Can I just leave them here then?
ワーフのテレポができない？
Can't do warp teleport?
むきろぜ...
Mukiroze...
これ置いてこう
I'll leave this here.
な、なんだここ？
Wh-What's this place?
体温低下...
Body temperature dropping...
もしかして今混雑してるからかもね
Maybe it's because it's congested right now.
着いたけど...
I arrived, but...
手持ち全部置いてった方がいい？マジ？
Should I leave all my inventory items behind? Seriously?
一旦置いてった方がいいかもね
It might be better to leave them behind for now.
オッケー、全裸に...
Okay, butt naked...
ほう、来て...
Ooh, coming...
死ぬかもしれんからってこと？
You mean because we might die?
うん、一応ベッドタッチはあると思うけども
Yeah, I think there's a bed touch point, but still.
うーん、でもこの辺なんかもう無くしてもいいなーってものが結構
Mmm, but around here, I have quite a few items that I wouldn't mind losing.
この障害物中に、お前らが死なないことを祈るぜ
I pray you guys don't die during this obstacle course.
恐竜たちよ
Dinosaurs.
ねぇ、ちょっとぐちゃぐちゃだけど1回転送しようかな
Hey, it's a bit messy, but maybe I should transfer them once.
混ざっちゃってすいません状態です、ちょっと
Sorry for mixing things up, just a bit.
ね、1分前
Hey, 1 minute ago.
あ、必ず拠点に置いて...
Ah, make sure to leave it at the base...
参加者景品あるんだったら行きたいな
If there's a prize for participants, I want to go.
ね！
Right!
てかもうこのへん無くなってもいいまである
In fact, I wouldn't even care if these items were lost.
無くなってもいいならもうね、いっそね
If losing them is fine, then honestly, might as well...
いっそ水道ある？
Is there even water supply?
あー、喉乾いてるわ。よいしょ
Ah, my throat is dry. Yoisho.
わーわーわー、喉乾いたな
Wawa, so thirsty.
これ飲めてるのか？
Is she drinking this?
これ飲め... え？これ飲めてるのか？
Drinking this... huh? Is she drinking this?
ワンポチって... あ、オッケーオッケー。
One click... Ah, okay, okay.
よっし、いいぞ。オッケー。
All right, good. Okay.
これ1人1頭ですか？
Is it one per person?
はーい。ふむふむ、馬...
Yesss. Hmm, a horse...
え、じゃあお前だ！
Eh, then it's you!
これ持っちゃった、ここに。よし。
I ended up taking this here. Alright.
えーっと... 装備置き場...
Let's see... Equipment storage...
あー、みんな装備入れてんだね。
Ah, everyone put their equipment in here.
お、シマウマじゃね？お前だけシマウマなんだ！
Oh, isn't that a zebra? You're the only one with a zebra!
Cチーム、お肉。
Team C, meat.
レース用動物。
Animals for the race.
ちょっとトイレ行ってきます。ー はーい。
I'm gonna go to the bathroom real quick. — Okay.
あー、お肉...
Ah, meat...
水道...
Water...
オッケーオッケー。
Okay, okay.
ステータスどうしようかな...
What should I do with my stats...
浴びなければ... え、馬の...
If I don't get hit... Eh, the horse's...
え、どうします？ — スタミナ...
Eh, what are you gonna do? — Stamina...
やはりこっちか？
Is it this after all?
とりあえず1万くらい... いるー。
For now, around 10,000... Needed.
スタミナかな...
Stamina, maybe...
何がいいんだ、これ？
What's good for this?
スタミナじゃね？
Isn't it stamina?
ただヒットポイントちょっと増やしておかないと怖い気がする。
Though I feel like it's scary without a bit more HP.
え、障害物... え？
Eh, obstacles... Eh?
念には念を。
Just to be extra safe.
どうしようかな...
What should I do...
むずくね？
Isn't this hard?
どうしようかな...
What should I do...
体力上げたところでさ、回復しきれないよな、生肉ないし。
Even if I raise health, I can't heal up, and there's no raw meat.
あ、馬だからベリーか？
Ah, since it's a horse, berries?
なんとも言えなくない、これ？ — 生肉ないんだよね。
Isn't it hard to tell? — We don't have raw meat.
焼肉食え食え。3000くらいまで上げて...
Eat cooked meat, eat. Raise it to about 3000...
どうなんだろうね...
I wonder how it is...
もう、あんま分からなーい。
Honestly, I don't really know.
あの、イベントのところどこですか？
Um, where is the event spot?
あ、痛っ！ — トイレ持った... ミスった...
Ah, ouch! — Brought the toilet... Messed up...
馬... 馬に...
Horse... To the horse...
何がいいかな... 馬の名前...
What would be good... The horse's name...
爆速エリート！ — 爆速かぶっちゃったわ、あかん。
Super fast elite! — "Super fast" overlapped, no good.
馬の... 馬の名前、何にしようかな...
Horse's... What should I name the horse...
あ、待って、アズちゃんのシマウマじゃなかった！
Ah, wait, it wasn't Azu-chan's zebra!
やっぱこれやな、レースと言ったらな。
As expected, it's this when talking about a race.
何？ — マッハタカネ。
What? — Mach Takane.
マッハタカネ！シマウマ... シマウマ...
Mach Takane! Zebra... Zebra...
体力あげたら馬さんが...
If you raise health, the horse...
言ってることとか 難しいでしょうか？
Is what I'm saying difficult?
でお肉を入れておくことで
And by keeping meat in there,
体力は上げた分マックス値は上がるけど
while max HP increases when leveled up,
回復させるには えーっと馬たちはケーキしか
to heal them, the horses can only eat cake,
野菜ケーキしか回復しないようになっておりまして
they can only heal using Veggie Cakes,
全員に何個かあげてた
and I gave several to everyone,
そう 一応回復することはできません
so, basically, you can't heal them during the race.
傷つけてごめんな
Sorry for hurting you.
でもさ 危険は... ないんじゃない？危険はないんじゃないはずです
But isn't there... no danger? There shouldn't be any danger.
危険はないでしょう
There shouldn't be any danger.
うん 落っこちない限りは
Yeah, as long as you don't fall off.
それで 体力... 体力増えやがった！
And with that, HP... HP went up!
ドキドキ
My heart is pounding!
体力量減ってはいないので安心してくださいね
Their health hasn't actually decreased, so please don't worry.
ポルカの馬なんかボロボロ... なんか歴戦個体みたい
Polka's horse looks all battered... Like a battle-scarred veteran.
すげえ！ボロボロ！
Awesome! So battered!
湯気が出てるよ！血が出てるよ！
It's steaming! It's bleeding!
血出てるよ
It's bleeding.
右クリックで後ろ蹴りできる
You can kick backward with right-click.
嘘だ！
No way!
なんで連打してんだ、この馬
Why is this horse spamming it?
邪魔できるってことかな？
Does that mean we can sabotage each other?
右クリックでヒヒーンってしてくれる
Right-click makes it whinny.
遅れてくる人、これだけなの？
Are these the only people who arrived late?
もしかして、遅れてやってるのか？
Are they participating late?
参加賞よりさっていうところがあるかもしれない
There might be something beyond just a participation prize.
いやいや、そんな！うちのチームだけ全員参加してる
No way! Only our team has everyone participating.
全員参加、うちのチームだけ？
Is our team the only one with full attendance?
優秀なので
Because we're excellent.
それでは、まだ準備してない人に案内します
Now then, I'll guide those who haven't prepared yet.
装備など失いたくないものを持ってきてしまっている人は
Anyone who brought items or armor they don't want to lose,
それぞれ各チームの装備置き場があるので、金庫に入れてください
please put them into the vault in your team's storage area.
ちなみに、この馬が入ってたポットは
By the way, for the cryopod this horse was in,
入れちゃっていいんですか？装備のところに
is it okay to put it in the equipment vault?
あ、もらっちゃっても大丈夫です
Oh, you can keep it if you want.
金庫でもね、後ろのボックスから
In the vault, or from the box behind,
I have an idea... Oh sweet girl!
自由に使っていただいて、可愛がって...
Feel free to use it as you like and take care of it...
体力を振った際に、血まみれになるんですが
When you level up their HP, they look bloody,
体力減ってるわけではないのでご安心ください
but their HP isn't actually reduced, so please don't worry.
でっかつ！でっかいお前！
So huge! You're huge!
優勝目指すわ
I'm aiming for victory.
あとは、金庫にお肉が入ってるので食料を取ってください
Also, there is meat in the vault, so please get food from there.
横取りしないでね
Don't steal each other's, okay?
ありがと、ありがと
Thank you, thank you.
レベルアップしていいの？
Can I level them up?
うん、好きにステータス振って大丈夫
Yeah, feel free to allocate stats however you like.
Ina, you can level up your dinosaur.
どうする？スタミナ振っとくか？
What to do? Should I level stamina?
もう始まるのかな？
Is it about to start?
お集まりいただいた皆様、ほとんど同じチームのメンバーで
Everyone gathered here, most are from the same team,
参加する予定だけどまだ辿り着けてない人いるか確認お願いします
please check if anyone planning to join hasn't arrived yet.
Cチーム、よろしくお願いします
Team C, please check.
同じチームのメンバーで辿り着いてない人はいますか？
Is there anyone from the same team who hasn't arrived?
Bチームはいません！今来ました！
Team B has no one missing! We just arrived!
みんな来てます！
Everyone is here!
今来た人たち、ここのエクウスを1人1匹取ってもらって
For those who just arrived, take one Equus per person
好きにステータスを振ってください
and allocate stats as you like.
食料と水は後ろにあるので補給してください
Food and water are in the back, so please restock.
名前つけてもいいんだよ
You can give them names too.
シマウマだな
It's a zebra.
21時になりましたので、皆様...
It's now 9:00 PM, everyone...
今からルール説明を行っていきたいので、声が聞こえる範囲にお越しください
We will now explain the rules, so please gather where you can hear my voice.
それでは、ルール説明させていただきます
Now then, let me explain the rules.
はーい、はい
Okay, yes.
えー、皆さんまず馬の準備大丈夫ですね？ステータスも振ってますか？
Alright, is everyone ready with their horses? Have you allocated your stat points?
はいー！
Yes!
はい、えー、装備や持ち物、失いたくないもの、手前のスロットに入ってるなど、忘れ物があったら右の、えー、装備置き場使ってください。
If you have gear, items, or anything you don't want to lose, or something in your quick bar, please store them in the equipment storage on the right.
はい！
Got it!
はい、それでは、えー、ルール、レースの説明します。
Alright then, I'll explain the rules and the race.
はい、えー、ピンク色のゲートがレースのルートに設置してあるので、そこをくぐりながらゴールまで競い合ってください。
Pink gates have been set up along the race route, so please pass through them and race all the way to the finish line.
はいー！
Okay!
ゲートは必ず通ってください。
Make sure you always go through the gates.
あーなるほど
Ah, I see.
くぐらずにショートカットした場合は引き返してくぐり直してください。
If you shortcut without passing through a gate, you must turn back and go through it.
周回場前に白い床が敷いてあるピンクのゲートがゴールになります。
The pink gate with a white floor in front of the gathering area will be the finish line.
もう一回言って。もう一回... 白い...
Say that again. White...
集会場前に白い床が敷いてあるピンクのゲートがあるので、そこがゴールポイントになります。
There is a pink gate with a white floor in front of the gathering area, and that will be the finish line.
なるほど
I see.
はい、集会所目の前みたいな感じになってるので、おそらく分かるかと思います。
Yes, it's right in front of the gathering area, so I think you'll easily spot it.
えー、もしも途中で馬が死んでしまったり自分が死んでしまっても、2回まで復活できます。
If your horse dies or you die along the way, you can revive up to two times.
2回！？やば！そんな死ぬ...？
Two times!? Wow! Will people die that much...?
死ぬかな？
Will they die, I wonder?
怖い怖い怖い
Scary, scary, scary!
はい、もし復活したい場合ですね、復活する場合は集会所で一度復活してからテレポートでスタート地点まで戻ってください。
If you want to respawn, please respawn at the gathering area first, then use the teleporter to return to the starting line.
ええー！大変だ！なるほどなるほど
Ehh! That's tough! I see, I see.
あ、ちょっと待って。もしかしたらもうちょっと便利なところが開発間に合ってる可能性があるので、ちょっと一瞬確認していいですか？
Ah, wait a second. A more convenient option might have been finished in time, so may I check for a moment?
あ、なるほど！はい！
Ah, okay!
やばいやばい！暴れてる！暴れてるね！誰かの馬が暴れてる！
Oh no! They're going wild! A horse is going crazy!
はい、失礼しましたー！
Alright, sorry about that!
無抵抗にしたほうがいいのかな？
Should I set them to passive?
はい、すみません。お待たせいたしました。もうちょっとね、みんなが復帰しやすいところの開発が間に合ったというところで...
Yes, sorry for the wait. It turns out a setup that makes it easier for everyone to respawn was finished in time...
もし死んでしまった場合は、集会所で復活するんですが...あ、違うわ。復活する際の場所が、集会所もしくはここ、このレース会場を選べるようになってます。
If you die, when you respawn... ah, wait, no. You can choose to respawn either at the gathering area or right here at the race venue.
なので、こちらの会場を選択して、ここに戻ってきてください。
So please select this venue and return here.
なるほど！はい！
I see! Got it!
もし間違えて集会所とか行っちゃったら、テポーターまで行ってもらうか、自分で死んでもらって、ここに復帰する形でお願いします。
If you accidentally go to the gathering area, please go to the teleporter or kill yourself to respawn back here.
はいー！
Got it!
で、レースなんですが、5位の人まで、5位の人がゴールした時点でレースの集計を締め切ります。
As for the race, it will close as soon as the 5th place player crosses the finish line.
へー！はい！
Ohh! Okay!
その後、アナウンスが...3分後に表彰式を行います。
After that, there will be an announcement... and the award ceremony will be held 3 minutes later.
はい！
Okay!
で、えー、ゴールできなかった方も、参加賞がございます。
And for those who couldn't finish, there are participation prizes.
わーい！ありがたい！
Yay! Thank you!
えー、参加賞はゴール地点に、参加賞の金庫を置いてありますので、それを1人1つ取っていってください。
Participation prize safes are set up at the finish line, so please take one per person.
えー！めちゃいいじゃん！
Woah, that's awesome!
はい、表彰式行いますが、アナウンスする形で行いますので、そのままもうゴールして攻略に戻ってもらっても大丈夫です。
The award ceremony will be announced, so if you like, you can head straight back to the main mission after finishing.
はいー！
Alright!
なので、そのままね、5位の人で集計終わってしまうんですが、その後レースを完走してもいいですし、そのままミッションに戻ってもらっても大丈夫です。
So even though counting ends at 5th place, you can either finish the rest of the race or return to the mission.
はいー！
Got it!
1位から5位の人には賞品がありまして、終わった後にアキローズから...私に行きます。
There are prizes for 1st through 5th place, which will be given by Aki Rosenthal... from me after it ends.
はーい！
Okay!
ということで、皆さん準備は大丈夫でしょうか？
With that said, is everyone ready?
はい！質問です！
Yes! I have a question!
はい、質問受け付けます。 / 馬の食べ物って、空っぽのままですか？
Yes, taking questions. / Should the horses' food inventory stay empty?
はい、ありません。そのままで大丈夫です。
Yes, no food. Leaving it as is fine.
分かりましたー！
Understood!
死んじゃった場合
If you die...
馬はどうすれば？
...what should we do about the horse?
えーっと、馬はですね、後ろの金庫に入ってるのかな？新しい馬を補充するみたいで。
Um, for the horses, I think they're in the safe in the back? Looks like you get a new horse to restock.
そうです。了解です。
Exactly. Understood.
了解です。はい。
Understood. Yes.
なので2回まで、そのような形で復帰してレースに戻ることができます。
So up to twice, you can respawn like that and return to the race.
はい。
Okay.
今多分血まみれになってる人は、えっと減ってるように感じるかもしれないんですが、
For those who look bloody right now, it might look like your HP is down,
基本的には体力は減ってるけ...あ、増えた分血まみれになってるだけで、最初から体力減ってないので安心してください。
but basically, your HP didn't decrease—it's just bloody because max HP increased, so don't worry.
うんうん、わかったー。
Mm-hmm, got it.
はい、ではまもなくレーススタートしていきますので、こちらの扉の
Okay, we'll be starting the race shortly, so once this gate...
開きましたらスタートになります。
...opens, the race will begin.
ええー！
Woah!
Okay...
すごい。最初にひかれてったらあれだな。
Amazing. It'd be bad if I get trampled right at the start.
追い越し怖いなこれ。
Overtaking looks scary.
どきどきだね。
So nervous.
がんばるぞー。
Good luck everyone!
レースを問題なく完走できた場合、最速でゴールできる可能性は、まあ8分前後でゴールできる...
If you finish the race without issues, the fastest possible time to goal is around 8 minutes...
8分！？
8 minutes!?
"Fastest expected is like 8 minutes."
相当走るね！
That's a long run!
それでは、レース...スタートー！
Well then, race... start!
イエーイ！
Yay!
あれ？
Huh?
めっちゃ...
So many...
"Lots of people."
めっちゃダメだよ！蹴るなよ！絶対蹴るなよ！
Don't hit me! Don't kick! Absolutely don't kick!
蹴るなよー！
Don't kick!
"Oh, it's so refined."
およ、ちょっと待って、祭り！引っかかってる！
Woah, wait a second, a traffic jam! I'm stuck!
引っかかってる、これ！
I'm stuck on this!
あ、ラグがね。
Ah, lag, huh.
ラグはあるんだ。
There is lag.
8分か...
8 minutes, huh...
おー！
Whoa!
めっちゃ飛べる！
It jumps so high!
飛びすぎだろ、これ！
Jumping way too far!
なんだこれ！？
What is this!?
うわあああ！
Wahhh!
え、なに！？
Wait, what!?
Huh?
おっと...ここ？
Oops... here?
え、どこ行けばいい？
Where should I go?
この辺？
Around here?
"Should I go back to spawn?"
ここ？
Here?
"Gathering point or the start?"
ここ？
Here?
あ、ここか！
Ah, here!
たらこっちみたいだから...
Looks like it's over here...
体調が...
My condition...
入ってみようか。
Let me enter.
回復してほしい！
Please heal me!
HP減っとるか。
Is my HP down?
行くぞー！
Let's go!
"Yay!"
"And..."
うー
Ugh...
これ、もう一回ステータス振らなきゃいけないのかな？
Do I need to assign status points again?
え、ふ？
Huh, level up?
"Or level up?"
"Is there like a way to access the tame inventory while riding? Do I always have to get off?"
F!
なるほど。
I see.
Can you high jump over the water?
I would assume that's how you kind of go about it, but...
I feel like I'm gonna die again.
やばい！やばい！
Oh no! Oh no!
My arms!
いやー、もう無理でしょう。
Yeah, that's impossible.
詰まってるとあそこからもう出れないよね。
When they're stuck like that, they can't get out from there, right?
バグってる？
Is it bugged?
無理そうだけどな。
It seems pretty unlikely, though.
なんかね、帰って別のことした方が... あ、でも確かに。
Maybe it's better to go back and do something else... Ah, but true.
I don't think HP is... yeah. It's not gonna help much.
え？あそこ普通焦らずって感じなのかな？
Huh? Over there, are you supposed to just stay calm?
誰かが走っていったぞ、今。
Someone just ran past right now.
やばい！危なかった！
Oh no! That was close!
何も持ってない！
I'm not carrying anything!
まあまあ...
Well, well...
ジャンプ...？
Jump...?
どこまで... ジャンプが... できるか...
How far... I can jump...
お、ラグか？うん。
Oh, is it lag? Yeah.
あ、ジャンプで...いけるけど...あ、こっちか。
Ah, I can make it with a jump... but... Ah, this way?
あー、どうしよう...
Ah, what should I do?
痛っ！
Ouch!
お、回っていってみよう。
Oh, let's try going around.
あっ、痛痛痛...
Ah, ow ow ow...
HPちょっと少ないけど...
My HP is a bit low, but...
Terror bird
怖いよ
I'm scared...
え、また...
Wait, another...
何かある...
There's something there...
怖い...
I'm scared...
ちょっと...
Wait...
いいのか？
Is this okay?
チャンスだ！
Now's our chance!
ジャンプして！
Jump!
行け行け行け！
Go, go, go!
寒い！寒い！
It's cold! So cold!
大丈夫？
Am I safe?
I forgot to bring some meat.
長っ... 長い...
So long... It's so long...
もう何かある、怖い...
There's something else again, I'm scared...
え、これ...
Wait, this...
The end?
間に合った？
Did I make it in time?
行けた？
Did I make it?
イェーイ！
Yay!
バリアだ！
A barrier!
バラバラ... 楽しい！
All scattered... This is so fun!
直った
It's healed.
みんなおるんか？
Is everyone here?
そう、3位どこかにしや
Right, where should 3rd place go...
あ、これ3位でしょうか？
Ah, is this 3rd place?
おー、3位？
Oh, 3rd place?
3位ある！イノシシ？
There's 3rd place! A boar?
もうみんなボロボロだよ！
Everyone's completely worn out!
これイノシシかな？
Is this a boar?
やったー！
Yay!
あ、3位！受け取り…
Ah, 3rd place! Receiving...
どうやって開ける…
How do I open...
明日の匂いー！
Scent of tomorrow!
This is the prize? Armadoggo...
順次お出しします。集計結果その後、1位から5位発表していきます！
I'll hand them out sequentially. After tallying, I'll announce 1st through 5th place!
敢闘賞はないんですか？敢闘賞は？
Is there no Fighting Spirit Award? What about the Fighting Spirit Award?
敢闘賞は参加賞となっております。
The Fighting Spirit Award is the participation prize.
えー！知らなかったのにー！
Eh! I didn't know that!
お帰りー！
Welcome back!
こいつなんだ？
What's this guy?
アルマドッゴかー！
An Armadoggo!
犬！犬だ犬！
A dog! It's a dog, a dog!
よかったね、なんか。
Good for you, somehow.
なんかもらえた？最初のやつでみんなドコドコ死んでいった…
Did you get something? With that first one, everyone kept dying left and right...
可愛い！
Cute!
寝袋を運んでくれる！平和ー！
It carries sleeping bags for you! So peaceful!
はい皆様、それではこちらにて…
Alright everyone, well then, right here...
締めとさせていただきます！
we will wrap things up!
生肉…！
Raw meat...!
発表…！
The announcement...!
すごいレースだったね！
That was an amazing race!
次は… まず5位から発表させていただき…
Next is... First, let me announce 5th place...
お！すごい！4位だ！おめでとう！
Oh! Amazing! 4th place! Congratulations!
4位は…ミニュです！
4th place is... Minyu!
ゼッペリンって何だろう？
What's a Zeppelin?
どんな感じだったんだろう？
What was it like, I wonder?
入賞者の方たちはアキさん…私に…
The prize winners, please go to Aki-san... or me...
パイロをテイム行くか、先洞窟行くかどっちする？
Should we go tame a Pyro or head to the cave first?
パイロも欲しいけど…
I want a Pyro too, but...
洞窟かな！洞窟行っちゃうか！
Maybe the cave! Shall we go to the cave!
雪フクロウってこの世界にいるんですか？
Are there Snow Owls in this world?
そして今回のラグナロク…
And for this Ragnarok...
優勝は… スバル！
The winner is... Subaru!
雪フクロウいるのかな？どうなんだろ？
Are there Snow Owls? How is it?
何ででも使え…ボス戦でも使える…
Useful for anything... even in boss fights...
ペコちゃんのところでシャドウメイン捕まえてたからね！
Because they were catching Shadowmanes at Peko-chan's place!
パイロ撮ってきます！
I'm going to take photos of Pyro!
参加賞受け取ってない方は、こちらの金庫から1人1つ取って帰ってください！
If you haven't received your participation prize, please take one per person from this vault!
引き続きロゼキャノARK、ミッション攻略楽しんでください！
Please continue to enjoy Roselia & Canary ARK mission conquest!
一旦グリフィンもらっとこう。
I'll take a Griffin for now.
キャンプ装備ってどこにあるんだ？
Where is the camping gear?
マナ… マナガルムが今なんか報酬だった？
Mana... was a Managarmr the reward just now?
確かに、ありがと…
Indeed, thank you...
とんでもないやつゲットしたんや！
I got an incredible one!
I can hear you. It's safe to say voice is in my head.
私のほうが低く聞こえてないかも？
Maybe mine isn't sounding lower?
ぺこちゃん！あーにゃ！
Peko-chan! Anya!
協力拠点で出来たらしいからさ！
It seems they built a co-op base!
アコスと一緒に行ってさ、新拠点に穴開けて…
I went with Akos and dug a hole in the new base...
すみません、お願いします！
Sorry, please!
モナー、ハコス！
Mona, Hakos!
From now... All right. It's time for me to go back to my team.
でも穴掘るぐらいはそんなに遠くないんだけど…
But digging a hole isn't that far...
Silent communication...
もらいに行くか！
Shall we go get it!
I forgot what we were doing to be honest.
あそこですぐ行けるよ！すぐ行けるよ！
You can get there soon! You can get there soon!
教えて、どこだ？
Tell me, where is it?
今ね、ベーちゃんと一緒に行こうとしてるのかな？
Right now, are they trying to go together with Bae?
going to the dino place so we put down the bed...
よいしょ。
Heave-ho.
あ、本当だ！
Oh, it's true!
かなで？かなでいる？
Kanade? Is Kanade here?
いいじゃん！
Nice!
やった！
Yay!
戻りました。
We're back!
おかえりー！
Welcome back!
でもマジでさ、ボタンの途中のさ、ジャンプすると体力減るぞーみたいな... あれめっちゃナイスアシストだったわ。
But seriously, mid-way through button, warning that jumping drains health... That was such a nice assist!
でしょう？あの平地でジャンプしないとアレ、高所でジャンプすると着地ダメージ... 着地ダメージがね、意外と入っちゃって。
Right? If you don't jump on flat ground... Jumping from high places causes fall damage. Fall damage unexpectedly adds up!
ねー、気がついてなかったわ、それ。
Right? I didn't notice that at all!
危ねー！危ね、危ね！
That was close! Close, close!
ねえ、洞窟行こうかなって。そう、攻略...
Hey, I was thinking of going to a cave, for the walkthrough...
何の... あの服、服着るというか、服じゃなくて... 恐竜？恐竜何がいいかなーって。
Which... well, not clothes, but like... line-up? Which dinos are good?
えーっと、全然そういえばミッションを多分こなせてないんだよね。
Well, speaking of which, I haven't done any missions at all.
ミッションこなせてない、全然埋めてなくてやばい。
I haven't cleared missions at all, I haven't completed any, it's bad.
埋めなきゃ、子育てしなきゃ。
Gotta fill them, gotta raise babies.
自分のやつどこだったっけ？
Where was mine again?
えーっと、何、どれを出すんだっけ？
Um, which one should I bring out?
ちょっと集会所行きます。
Heading to the meeting spot!
はいよー。
Alright~
でもまあ、グリフィンかメガテリか... あ、メガ使えるの？メガテリかー、まあユウティラも全然...
Well, Griffin or Megatherium... Oh, can we use Megatherium? Or Yutyrannus is fine too.
洞窟... 今日テリジノか、テリジノで行けるんじゃないかなと思ってあるが無理？
Cave... Therizinosaurus today? I thought we could go with Therizino, but is that impossible?
行けそうだけどねー。みんなで出せば行けるんじゃない？
It seems doable though. If everyone brings one out, can't we do it?
かなー。
Maybe?
ど、どの... どのやつ？
Wh-Which one? Which one were you talking about?
一番最初のやつ？
The very first one?
えっと、肉食だっけ？行こうって言ってたのは。
Um, were you talking about going to the carnivore cave?
イナの... 犬が...
Ina's... dog is...
高圧のアーティファクト取りに行く話のアレ？
Right, the one about getting the Artifact of the Cunning?
そうそうそうそう！
Yes, yes, yes, yes!
飛べるやつと...
Something that can fly, and...
飛べるやつと、ま、プテラとかでもいいし、飛べるやつと1匹なんか戦えるやつ持っていけばいいんじゃないかな？
A flyer like a Pteranodon is fine, bring a flyer and one combat dino, wouldn't that work?
いいよね。
Sounds good.
一旦それ、追従... 追従するか？
Let's try set it to follow? Shall we set it to follow?
ならメガテリさん連れて行くか。
Then I'll bring Megatherium along.
来ないな。
He's not coming.
すみません、来ないです！
Sorry, he's not coming!
うちの犬が...
Our dog...
これ追従か何かで外出てこれない？
Can't he come outside if you whistle follow or something?
あ、いけるいけるいける！
Ah, okay, okay, okay! You can do it!
だぜ！うちの犬が...
There we go! Our dog...
あっちまでとりあえず行っちゃって...
For now, let me head over there first...
で、洞窟が... えっと、肉食の洞窟がどこにあるんだっけかな？
And the cave... um, where was the carnivore cave again?
縮小のあれじゃないかな。
Isn't it the one in the screenshot?
あのーなんだっけ？
Um, what was it again?
座標のとこ？
The coordinates place?
どこだっけ？あ、座標座標...
Where was it? Oh, coordinates, coordinates...
あれ、私鉄の斧... あったあったあった。
Wait, my iron axe... Ah, here it is!
えーっと... どこだっけ？あれ？
Um, where was it? Huh?
肉食の洞窟はね...
The carnivore cave is...
なんかどっか貼ってくれてたっけ？
Did someone post it somewhere?
貼ってる。
It's posted.
座標54の52。
Coordinates 54, 52.
あ、近いんだ。
Ah, it's pretty close!
いぇーい！
Yay!
あ、なんか... ごめんなさい！
Ah, wait, someone, someone...
誰か誰か誰かが... 毎晩を殴っている... ごめん自分か？
Someone, someone is hit every night... Wait, is it me?
誰かの犬が！誰かの犬が暴れてます！
Someone's dog! Someone's dog is going wild!
誰かの犬が攻撃してますめちゃくちゃ！まずいまずいまずい！
Someone's dog is attacking like crazy! Bad, bad, bad!
無抵抗、無抵抗にしてほしい！無抵抗？
Passive, please set it to Passive! Passive?
ごめんごめんごめん！
Sorry, sorry, sorry!
はい、オッケー！
Okay, got it!
先輩方どうでしたか？ビビ、今から参加させてもらいます！お疲れ様です！
Seniors, how was it? Biboo will join from now! Thanks for your hard work!
お疲れ様ですー！
Thanks for your hard work!
死ぬ！死ぬ！死ぬ！
I'm dying! I'm dying! I'm dying!
あ、ユウティラ持ってるの忘れてました。ユウティラ出すとこ。
Ah, I forgot I had Yutyrannus. Let me bring Yutyrannus out.
今から洞窟に行こうっていう感じです。
We are about to head to the cave now.
え、ビビ行けるのかな？行ける行ける。
Wait, can Biboo make it? She can, she can!
ちょっと待って、ワイバーンが... ワイバーンが攻撃されちゃってるわ。
Wait a second, Wyvern... Wyvern is getting attacked!
おーい！ワイバーンくーん！
Hey~ Wyvern-kun~!
ワイバーン... テリジノが...
Wyvern... Therizino is...
だ、大丈夫かな？うん、オッケー。
I-Is it okay? Yeah, okay.
あれ？なんかあんな所に建物ありましたっけ？
Huh? Was there a building in a place like that?
あれ？しまえない、まあいっか。
Huh? I can't put it away... Oh well.
お隣さん出来た？もしやって
Did a neighbor move in, by any chance?
お隣さん居るよ。
There is a neighbor over there.
え、お隣さん居るの？
Wait, we have a neighbor?
居るよ、近くに。乾く...目の前に居るよ。
Yeah, close by. Kawaku's right in front of us.
本当だ！
It's true!
お隣さん居ます？
Are they there right now?
いや、逆になんか分散されて助かるわ。
Honestly, having us spread out actually helps a lot.
ね。確かに。
Yeah, that's true.
ここティラノ結構来るからｗ
Because Rexes come around here quite often!
でかいの来るからね、ありがたや。
Big ones show up, so I'm grateful.
えーっと、原始的コンパニオンのキャンプ装備？何これ？
Umm, Primitive Companion Camp Gear? What's this?
これは犬につけるっぽい。
Looks like you equip this on a dog.
犬につけて...アルマドッゴ。
Equip it on the dog... Armadoggo.
ほい。
Yup.
なんかコンパニオンモードにすると、ユニークな性能を引き出せる...
If you put it in companion mode, it brings out unique abilities...
元々ついてるこの犬に何だ？あまりか...しまっとくか？
What about this dog that had it originally? Not much... Should I store it?
何になるんだろうね、コンパニオンって？ねー。
I wonder what companion mode actually does? Yeah.
とりあえず54, 5...だから、一応近いっちゃ近いよ。
Anyway, it's 54, 5... so it's relatively close.
あ、じゃあ行くか。
Ah, then shall we go?
どんな準備して行けばいいですか？今から...
What kind of preparations should I bring? Starting now...
あ、今からこっちの...
Ah, heading to this side...
仮拠点の方だね。来てもらえたら。
To the temporary base. If you can come over.
仮拠点の方。はい、分かりました！
To the temporary base. Okay, got it!
あ、一瞬ピピピ...
Ah, just a second, beep beep beep...
2日目ー！イエーイ！
Day 2! Yay!
あれ？9時からのイベントどうでしたかー？
Huh? How was the 9 o'clock event?
なんと、トワが...
Believe it or not, Towa...
はい！
Yes!
勝ちましたね！何だったっけ？
Won! What was it again?
すげー！
Amazing!
ナイス、ナイス！
Nice, nice!
良いですね！
That's awesome!
服どこに入れたっけ？覚えてない...
Where did I put my clothes? I don't remember...
役に立ちたいぞー！
I want to be useful!
何を？
With what?
いやいやいや、自分の服どこに入れたか覚えてない。
No, no, no, I just don't remember where I put my own clothes.
服、えっと...
Clothes, um...
どうしたんだー？
What's wrong?
いや、たぶんゲーム会場じゃない？
No, isn't it probably at the event venue?
ゲーム会場のチェスト...
In the event venue's chest...
イナ先輩のギィは、仮拠点の...
Ina-senpai's gear is at the temp base's...
ギリギリで行こうかｗ
Shall we just go with minimal gear? lol
脱いでも大丈夫だ！
It's fine even if you're naked!
服作ってないんだよな。服作らないとあれか...
I haven't crafted clothes. Without clothes, is it...
皮の装備とか作っちゃったら？
Why don't you craft some hide armor?
うん。
Yeah.
すっぽんぽん。
Stark naked.
えーっと仮拠点...あれ、どこやっけ？迷子...
Umm, temp base... Huh, where was it? I'm lost...
水晶とかなんとかってところ。
The place called crystal something or another.
テレポーターの。毒水晶ってとこですね。
Near the teleporter. The Poison Crystal area.
ありがとうございます！向かいにずっと犬が追従してますよ、ちょっと。
Thank you! A dog has been following me across the way for a bit.
犬が邪魔で出れないよー！
The dog is blocking the door, I can't get out!
ちょっと待って！ワンちゃん！
Wait a second! Doggie!
ワンちゃんが奥行っちゃった。なんで？
The doggie went further inside. Why?
あ、ワンちゃん捕まえたんですか？
Ah, did you catch a doggie?
ワンちゃんね、参加賞で貰えたんだよね。
The doggie, we got it as a participation reward.
そうなんだ！
Oh, I see!
ドア！ドア！ドア！
Door! Door! Door!
あー！ごめんごめん！
Ah! Sorry, sorry!
全員やっちゃった、なんか！表！
I accidentally wiped everyone out somehow! Outside!
あ、ごめんごめん！
Ah, sorry, sorry!
何？
What happened?
離れて、離れて！
Move away, move away!
悪いな、悪い。
My bad, my bad.
これ犬貰ったけど...
I got this dog, but...
使い方調べないと分かんないから...
I won't know how to use it unless I look it up...
そうだね。
That's true.
大変だわ。
It's tough.
なんかすごいデカイの居るー！
There's something huge over here!
おーい！ごちそう！
Hey! It's a feast!
はい、こんにちは！
Yes, hello!
おめでとうございます！すごい、すごい！
Congratulations! Amazing, amazing!
え？商品？
Eh? A reward?
出た！ツェッペリン？
There it is! Zeppelin?
気になる、気になる！
I'm curious, I'm curious!
ん？なんだ？
Hmm? What is it?
あれ？あれれ？
Huh? What's going on?
出た！
It showed up!
なんだ、なんだ。行ってもいいかな？
What is it, what is it. Is it okay if I go over?
およ？
Oho?
う、寒い
Ugh, it's cold.
寒いか？
Is it cold?
寒いー、さむむー
It's cold~ So cold~
あ、温まった
Ah, I warmed up.
待って、ツェッペリン
Wait, Zeppelin?
美味しそう、ツェッペリン
Sounds tasty, Zeppelin.
あ、おやつみたい
Ah, like a snack.
誰かご飯ください！ビビ死にしそう！
Someone please give me food! Bibi's gonna die!
あー、行け行け
Ah, go go.
ちょっと待ってね
Hold on a moment.
あ、ありがとうございます
Ah, thank you very much.
いただきます
Thank you for the food.
ってか何これ？あ、やば、踏まれた
Wait, what's this? Ah, crap, I got stepped on.
何これ？恐竜じゃない！
What's this? It's not a dinosaur!
え、乗れる！何これ！
Eh, you can ride it! What is this!
文明進んだ！え？
Civilization has advanced! Eh?
え、すごい！
Eh, awesome!
ガソリン？
Gasoline?
ガソリンかー
Gasoline, huh~
大変なの？これ
Is it tough to get? This...
大変宜しそうなものが
Looks like something that takes a lot of effort.
これ、え、うわあ
This, eh, woah.
え、仕舞えないってこと？
Eh, does that mean we can't store it?
あ、しまえないよ
Ah, we can't store it.
あははは！浮いた！
Ahahaha! It floated!
ちょっと待ってね、ガソリンは... 私に来てくれる？
Wait a second... Gasoline... Can someone bring it to me?
ガソリンあった！
There was gasoline!
ございます！
Here you go!
空飛びたい！
I want to fly in the sky!
ハイオク満タンでお願いします！
High-octane full tank, please!
レギュラーじゃなくてハイオク！
Not regular, high-octane!
ハイオクがいいんだ？
You prefer high-octane?
なんでハイオクなんだ？
Why high-octane?
やっぱりあんまり関係ないけどね
Actually it doesn't matter much.
そうなんや
Is that so?
車の車種によって違うってだけで
It just depends on the car model.
へー！無免許やから分からんかった
Aha! I didn't know because I don't have a license.
無免許って言うな！
Don't say unlicensed!
無免許！
Unlicensed!
よかった、ガソリン支給で
Glad gasoline was supplied.
でしたねー
Indeed~
装備揃えるのに何が必要ですか？
What do we need to prepare our gear?
とりあえず服着て
For now, put on clothes.
はい
Okay.
ご飯持って、飛べる子で行くのがいいのかな？
Bring food, and maybe go with a flying creature?
はい
Okay.
飛べる子！ビビの恐竜達は生きてるか？
A flyer! Are Vivi's dinosaurs alive?
ここに誰か入れてるはずです
Someone should have put them in here.
賢い子だ！生きてた
What a smart child! They survived.
生きろ！誰やこれ？うさぎさんだ！
Live! Who's this? It's Mr. Rabbit!
ビテラがいる、ビテラが
There's a Ptera, a Ptera.
あ、よかった！ありがとうございます！
Ah, thank goodness! Thank you very much!
ありがとうございます！やったー！
Thank you very much! Yay!
ちょっと待って、なに？なに？なに？
Wait a moment, what? What? What?
ガソリン来たよ
Gasoline is here.
ガソリン満タンでお送りまいりましたー
Delivering a full tank of gasoline~
今ここに投げますのでお使いください
I'll drop it right here, so please use it.
こちらどうぞ
Here you go.
拾うぞ
Picking it up.
はい、どうぞ
Yes, go ahead.
では、お楽しみをー
Well then, enjoy~
あー！ありがとうございます！
Ah! Thank you so much!
アキロ先輩すげー！いいな、ビビも欲しい
Akiro-senpai is awesome! So cool, I want one too.
ドラゴン
A dragon.
一応 Discord に戻そう
Let me head back to Discord for now.
Discord に戻した
I went back to Discord.
肉、もうちょっと持つか
Should I grab a bit more meat?
おー！飛んだ飛んだ！
Oh! It flew, it flew!
うわー！飛んでるー！浮いてる！
Woah! It's flying! Floating!
かっけー！
So cool!
すごい！カッコいいー！
Amazing! So cool!
あ、いいね、いいね
Ah, nice, nice.
うわー！
Woah-!
飛びたい、飛びたい
I want to fly, I want to fly.
運転上手くない？運転
Isn't the driving really good? Driving.
ビビも運転したいなー
Bibi wants to drive too~
いいね
Nice.
墜落させちゃうよん
I'll make it crash~
それトワの賞品だから！
That's Towa's prize!
お前たち勝手に本人を差し置いて乗ってるから！
You guys are riding it without asking the owner!
え、乗っていいですか？
Eh, can I ride it?
乗っちゃおう
Let me hop on.
どうぞどうぞ
Go ahead, go ahead.
いいかい？
Is it okay?
まぁ懐広いからね
Well, she's very generous.
誘導めっちゃあるな
That's so leading!
自分かい
About yourself?!
ねー
Right?
懐広いからね
'Cause she's generous.
自分言わんのよそういうのは
You shouldn't say that about yourself!
とりあえず、行きますか？
Anyway, shall we head out?
そうだね
Yeah.
はーい、行きますか。まあそれには乗っていかないよ
Okay, shall we go? Well, I won't ride on that one.
高過ぎるわ、こいつ
This guy is way too tall.
それには乗っていかないかな
I guess I won't ride on that.
プテラとかその上走れる？
Can Pteras fly above that?
道中で行ける恐竜1匹持ってって
Take one dino that can make the journey...
アルゲンとかプテラとか
Like an Argent or a Ptera...
あとはその地上で戦えるやつ1匹持ってって
And bring one dino that can fight on the ground,
って感じかな
something like that.
冷蔵庫の中にメガテリウムが一応いるから
There's a Megatherium in the fridge,
洞窟内でちょっと戦えるかわかんないけども、それおすすめかな
so I'm not sure if it can fight inside caves, but I recommend that.
メガテリウム...
Megatherium...
あ、こいつか
Ah, this guy?
よいしょ
Upsadaisy.
ビビちゃん
Bibi-chan.
あの、拠点攻撃されて... ほんまやで、死にました。
Um, our base was attacked... Seriously, I died.
ほんまやで何も持ってない
Really, I have nothing with me.
ほんまやではいなくなりました
Seriously, it's gone.
え、ほんまやでいなくなったの？
What, it really disappeared?
うん
Yeah.
えええー！
Eeeeeh?!
ほんまやで仕舞ってなかったから
Because it wasn't put away.
あー！ なんでやねん！
Ah! Why?!
なんでやねん！
Why?!
だからビビはいったんそのミイラと
So Bibi, for now, with that mummy...
あの、この冷蔵庫の中にメガテリウムっていうのがいるから、それ1匹持って来たらいいかな
Um, there's a Megatherium in this fridge, so bringing one of those should be fine.
で、イナはユーティラ権でもいいかもね
And maybe Ina can take Yutyrannus.
ユーティラ...
Yutyrannus...
私がユーティラ...
Me on Yutyrannus...
ユティ、そうそうそう。これイナのユティだから、イナはユティに乗って戦う感じかな
Yuty, right right. This is Ina's Yuty, so Ina will probably fight on Yuty.
うんうん
Mm-hmm.
ユーティラ... どこに書いてあるの？
Yutyrannus... Where is it written?
あ、違う違う。ビビはメガテリウムな
Ah, no no. Bibi gets Megatherium.
あ、ビビはメガテリウム。あー
Ah, Bibi gets Megatherium. Ah.
そうそうそう。メガテ... これだ
Right right. Megathe... Here it is.
これで、タッキミー... あ、でもご飯付いて
With this... Ah, but food is attached...
よいしょ
Upsadaisy.
お、何？
Oh, what?
お肉が... 気を付けてないと...
The meat... If you're not careful...
お肉28個あったら足りますか？
Will 28 pieces of meat be enough?
どうかな...
I wonder...
もうちょっとあったらいいかも
Maybe a bit more would be good.
もうちょっと、はい
A bit more, okay.
水筒どっかにやっちゃったー
I lost my canteen somewhere!
なんでプテラ捕まったー！
Why did my Ptera get caught?!
どういうこと？
What do you mean?
すいません、さっきなじられていました
Sorry, I was getting scolded earlier.
あーびっくりしたー
Ah, that scared me!
なんか急に...
Suddenly...
いなくなっちゃって、自分のプテラどこだったんで作りました
It was gone, and I didn't know where my Ptera was, so I crafted one.
つくりました...
Crafted one...
繊維と皮...
Fiber and hide...
ヤバい！これ63...
Oh no! This is 63...
イナ準備大丈夫なら行っちゃいますか？
Ina, if you're ready, shall we head out?
はい！
Yes!
あ、ちょっと、お水だけ...
Ah, wait, just water...
しまえないんだけど...
I can't put it away though...
置いていったら？
How about leaving it behind?
まいっか
Oh well.
アルゲンに乗らせてもらおう
Let me ride the Argent.
ちょっと、プテラの居なくなっちゃったんですよね、多分
Well, the Ptera probably disappeared...
回収してないから1時間経っちゃいましたよね
Since I didn't retrieve it, an hour has passed, right?
多分
Probably.
諦めるか...
Guess I'll give up on it...
イナちゃん、モンボに入れられるかな？ボールに。ユーティラ。
Ina-chan, can you put it in a Cryopod? The Yutyrannus.
あ、えっと... はいはい。
Ah, um... Yes yes.
ある？
Got one?
うん
Yeah.
よいしょ
Upsadaisy.
それを持ってこう
Let's bring that.
洞窟じゃちょっとデカすぎる可能性もあるが、まあ行こう
It might be a bit too big for a cave, but let's go anyway.
行こう！
Let me go!
座標が...
The coordinates are...
54, 52
あんまり遠くない
It's not too far.
あんまり遠くないよ
It's not that far away.
54, 52
みんなについて行きます！
I'll follow everyone!
見れないから
Since I can't check the map.
飛べ！
Fly!
はい！
Yes!
54の52
54, 52.
よいしょ。こっちか。
Upsadaisy. Is it this way?
こっちや！みんな行くぞー！
This way! Everyone, let me go!
はーい！ついて行きます！
Okay! We'll follow you!
ビビ、ちょっと待って... おそ！
Bibi, wait a sec... So slow!
みんな早... え？
Everyone is fast... Huh?
アイテムかな？
Is it items?
重量かな？重量が重くて...
Is it weight? Being too heavy...
重量オーバーの可能性ありますね
There's a chance of being encumbered.
この辺じゃない？言っても
Isn't it around here though?
重い物持ってきちゃった...
I brought heavy stuff...
皮持ってきちゃった、バカタレ...
I brought hide with me, idiot...
同じく持ってきちゃった、バカタレって感じ
Same, I brought it too, total idiot move.
54... 52.9
入るなら準備出来次第入れー
If you're going in, enter as soon as you're ready-
みんなが言った後合流してるから、先中入っててもいいし
Everyone will join up after, so you can go inside first,
降りなければ
as long as you don't dismount.
よいしょ
Upsadaisy.
あれ？ビビ、これボタン先輩についていってます。大丈夫か？
Huh? Bibi is following Botan-senpai. Is that okay?
大丈夫だよ
It's fine.
大丈夫大丈夫
It's fine, it's fine.
だって洞窟内飛行禁止じゃなかったっけ？
Wait, wasn't flying forbidden inside caves?
この辺じゃねえの？この辺の下とかじゃねえの？多分
Isn't it around here? Maybe under this area? Probably.
入れてるけどね
Though it lets us fly in.
あれってなんかミッションじゃなかったんですか？このクレートってアイテム取るの
Wasn't that a mission? Getting items from this crate?
それミッションだね。取っていいよ。
That's a mission. You can take it.
あ、間違えた間違えた間違えた...
Ah, my bad, my bad, my bad...
クレート？ Fで...
A crate? Pressing F...
クレートって個人ミッションでしたっけ？
Were crates for individual missions?
あ、個人ミッション！
Ah, individual missions!
あ、じゃあ他の人が取った方がいいや。
Ah, then someone else should take it.
まだ進んでないや、ござる。
I haven't progressed yet, gozaru.
びびも進んでなーい。
Biibi hasn't progressed either~
クレート取ったら...いいやで。 / 分かりました。
If you take the crate... that works. / Got it.
お、なんだこれ？時間が足りないゲームだ、これ。
Oh, what's this? This game doesn't give you enough time.
全部取っていいのか？
Can I take everything?
ここじゃねえかな？で、違うか？違うわ。
Isn't it here? Wait, no? Never mind.
なんか、近くにあると思うんだよね。
I think it's somewhere nearby.
入口があるんだよね、たぶんね。
There's probably an entrance.
そうそうそうそう！洞窟の穴があると思うけど...
Right, right! I think there's a cave entrance, but...
ん？びびさんだ。
Hm? It's Biibi-san.
そう、ちょっとボタン先輩見失いました、びび。
Yeah, Biibi kind of lost sight of Botan-senpai.
あ、今ね洞窟の穴探してほしい。
Ah, right now I want us to look for the cave entrance.
洞窟の穴探して... 了解。
Look for the cave entrance... Got it.
滝の入り口とかかな？ / 滝っぽいよね。
Maybe an entrance by the waterfall? / It looks like a waterfall.
滝壺の中飛び込んでいったら洞窟説を唱え...飛び込む！
Proposing the theory that if you dive into the waterfall basin, it's a cave... Diving in!
はいはいはい。まぁ、あるよね。
Right, right. Well, that's a common trope.
な...何もない...
There's... nothing...
なかったね。
There wasn't any.
ここら辺？ここら辺かな？
Around here? Maybe around here?
らしい...この辺りらしい... / この辺りか？
Apparently... Supposedly around here... / Around here?
うわ！今雨降ってる！ハイ六角できそう！
Whoa! It's raining now! High Hexagon potential!
雨雨...え、どこだ？
Rain, rain... Uh, where is it?
どこだ〜？
Where is it~?
この辺？
Around here?
いやぁ〜！うさぎさん来た！
Noo~! A rabbit came!
54.9、52.9...
54.9, 52.9...
ん〜？どこだ〜？
Hmm~? Where is it~?
ん？ここか？違うか...
Hm? Is it here? Or not...
52.9？
52.9?
52... 55.9... 52.9...
52.9とは書いてるけどね、画像貼って書いてくれてるやつ。
It says 52.9 though, on the posted image.
この辺だな。この黄色い光が...
Around here. This yellow light...
黄色いクレートかな？黄色クレートに向かおう、じゃあ。
Is that a yellow crate? Let's head to the yellow crate then.
この辺のどこか？
Somewhere around here?
ボタン先輩発見！
Botan-senpai spotted!
これが入り口じゃないもんね。この辺の下ら辺なのかな？
This isn't the entrance though. Is it lower down around here?
上下はでも分かんないよね。
Though you can't tell the vertical level, right?
確かにね。
That's true.
だから下の方かなって思ってたんだけど...
So I thought maybe it's lower down, but...
ね、下にありそうですよね。
Right, it seems like it would be below.
え、これ滝の裏とかになんかねえかワンチャン？
Eh, is there any chance it's behind the waterfall?
突っ込んだんですけど見つけられなくて...
I charged into it, but couldn't find anything...
白い目印にだって！下の沼地の壁って書いてあるな。
It says at the white marker! "Wall of the lower swamp".
あーなるほど？
Ah, I see?
白？白？白なんかあります？
White? White? Is there something white?
この辺に白？
White around here?
え、どこだ？お城？
Eh, where is it? A castle?
ちょっと高く飛ぶか...
Let's fly higher...
城って言ったら、あっちの緑色に光ってるやつですかね？
Speaking of a castle, is it that green glowing thing over there?
いや、あれじゃないだろう。 / これじゃないですよね。
No, probably not that. / Probably not this, right?
え、この世界って建物あるんですか？城みたいなの。
Eh, are there buildings in this world? Like a castle?
あ、違うこれ誰かのアルゲンの...罠か。トラップ？
Ah, no, is this someone's Argentavis... trap? A trap?
あーそれ、昨日捕まえたやつかも。 / あ、捕まえたやつか！
Ah, that might be the one we caught yesterday. / Ah, the caught one!
え、城ってどこだ？あ、ここにまた黄色いクレート落ちてきたよ。
Eh, where's the castle? Ah, another yellow crate dropped here.
クレートミッションで取っちゃいな。
Just take it with the crate mission.
こんにちはー！あ、と思ったら、まつり先輩いたわ。
Hello~! Ah, wait, Matsuri-senpai was there.
僕の画像載せた...ここら辺じゃなくない？
The image I posted... Isn't it not around here?
え、マジでどこ？これ洞窟じゃないんだよね。
Eh, seriously where? This isn't a cave, right.
これ滝裏なんだよな...え、そもそも違う？もしかして。
This is behind the waterfall... Wait, is it wrong in the first place?
そもそも左上って調べたら書いてあるけどどうなんだろう？
When you search, it says upper left, but I wonder.
待って僕たち...座標が...
Wait, for us... the coordinates...
僕たちが行きたい場所はですね、肉食の洞窟ですね。
Where we want to go is the Carnivore Cave.
そう、肉食の洞窟！
Right, Carnivore Cave!
みんなに渡されてる画像の座標が違くない？
Aren't the coordinates in the image given to everyone wrong?
そもそも間違ってるこれ。 / あ、間違ってる？
This is wrong in the first place. / Ah, it's wrong?
なんかサイトで調べたら全然違うとこになった...
When I looked it up on a site, it was somewhere completely different...
肉食の洞窟はマップ上だよって言われてる。 / 左上なんだよね。
They're saying Carnivore Cave is at the top of the map. / Upper left, right.
じゃあこの資料が違うことか。ネットに基づいて行ってみますか。
Then this reference is wrong. Shall we go based on the internet?
オッケーオッケー！ネットに基づくと...えっと...
Okay okay! Based on the internet... umm...
ワープかな？
Should we warp?
うん、ワープか、オッケー
Yeah, warp? Okay.
じゃあ一回ワープしましょう
Let's warp once then.
そうだね、一旦拠点に戻ろう
Yeah, let's head back to base first.
なんか攻撃されてる
Wait, someone's being attacked!
イキろがめっちゃ攻撃されてる！
Ikiro is taking huge damage!
え、行けないじゃん
Huh? We can't go!
死なないで！
Don't die!
死ぬな！
危ない危ない
That was close!
お、アルゲンたちが
Oh, the Argents are...
危ない危ない
Watch out, watch out!
ふざけやがって
Screw you guys!
大丈夫？
Are you okay?
大丈夫でした
I made it out okay!
よかった
What a relief.
じゃあ、テレポータイキあしょ
Alright, let's head to the teleporter.
よいしょ、よいしょ
Heave-ho, heave-ho!
ほい
Here we go!
プテラば！
Bye-bye, Ptera!
プテラまでやっちゃう
Even the Pteranodon's fighting!
あ、いたいたいたいた
Ah, ow ow ow ow!
みんなやる気満々だな
Everyone's so eager to fight.
任せる、アルゲン任せる
I'll leave it to you, leave it to the Argents!
はい
Okay!
プテラもお前
Ptera, you too!
あっち行け
Go over there!
Get outta here!
あっち行け
Shoo!
Go over there!
ちょっと届いてないか
Can it not quite reach?
ちょっと届かない
It can't reach!
足短いね
Its legs are so short!
一回飛んじゃってくださいね
Please fly up once!
うん
Yeah.
よいしょ
Up we go.
あ、ごめんね、ごめんね
Ah, sorry, sorry!
降りられなかった
I couldn't dismount.
あ、えーっと、一応降りてるけど
Ah, um, I dismounted for now, but...
渋い顔やめかい
Stop making that sour face!
ナイスー
Nice!
よろしくテレポーター
Teleporter, do your thing!
あ、誰か飛んできた
Ah, someone warped in!
どうぞ
Go ahead.
なんか左側だから
Since it's on the left...
えっと、ここ、これかな？
Um, here... is it this one?
ジャングルだね
It's the jungle, right?
はーい
Okay!
取り残された！
I got left behind!
あ、肉食洞窟ってあるやん
Oh, there's a Carnivore Cave option!
テレポート先に
At the teleport destination!
あ、ほんとだ
Ah, you're right!
あれ？どこに行きましたか？
Huh? Where did you guys go?
美々だけ一人取り残された！
Bibi was left all alone!
あ、なんかの肉食の洞窟って名前が付いてるみたいですよ、テレポーターに
Looks like one of them is named Carnivore Cave on the teleporter!
肉食の洞窟？
Carnivore Cave?
うん
Yeah.
ちょっと探してみるわ
I'll try looking for it.
お願いします
Please do!
非常に...
It's extremely...
雨降ってて視界が悪いですね
It's raining, so visibility is terrible.
ごめんね、プテラも、プテラも、プテラもね
Sorry, the Pteras too, the Pteras too...
え？プテラだけ、どっ...
Huh? Only the Ptera went...
プテラだけ行ってしまったね
Only the Ptera went through!
美々がテレポーターから出ちゃってたんだっかな？
Maybe Bibi stepped off the teleporter?
あぁー
Ahhh...
来た
They came back!
えーっと
Um...
歩くな
Don't walk!
来た
Here they are!
で、プテラどこだ？
So where's the Ptera?
美々居ないよ
Bibi isn't here!
あれ？美々あれ？
Huh? Bibi is...?
美々は、プテラはもうこっち来てるよ
Bibi, the Ptera is already over here!
肉食の洞窟にテレポートしました
I teleported to Carnivore Cave.
多分違うとこに居る
You're probably in the wrong spot!
いや、ここジャングルだ
Wait, this is the jungle!
え、ここジャングル？
Huh, this is the jungle?
ここジャングルだ
This is the jungle!
違うわ、ここじゃない
No, it's not here!
そもそもここじゃないかも
Maybe it wasn't even here to begin with.
あ、そこじゃない？
Oh, not there?
美々そこ居ていいよ
Bibi, you can stay right there.
あ、よかった
Oh, phew!
あ、そっちか
Ah, that way?
隣居るわ、私
I'm right next to you!
オッケー
Okay!
こっちだよ
Over here!
よいしょ
Here we go.
そっち行きまーす
Heading over there!
はい
Yep!
一旦テレポしちゃってもいいかな、これ
Can I go ahead and teleport us?
テレポしちゃっていいよ
Yeah, feel free to teleport us.
えーっと
Um...
肉食の洞窟
Carnivore Cave!
うん
Yep.
よいしょ
All right.
こっちか
Is it this way?
来た来た来た！ありがとうございます！
Here they are! Thank you so much!
オッケー
Okay!
テレポーターから
Right off the teleporter...
プテラ
Ptera!
プテラ埋まってない？それ
Isn't that Ptera stuck in the ground?
目と目の前
Right in front of us!
目の前や
Right before our eyes!
目の前だね
Yeah, right in front!
あ、これか！
Ah, this one!
で、ここで手に入れるのがアーティファクトだよね？
So what we need to get here is the artifact, right?
そうだね、そうだね
Yeah, exactly, exactly!
ワンチャンこのままみんな飛んで行けないかな？
Can we all just fly through like this maybe?
飛んで行けそうだけどね
Looks like we can fly through though.
行ってみる？
Want to try going in?
どこ来た？
Where are we?
あ、居る居る居る、はいはい
Ah, here they are! Right, right.
居る？
Are you here?
こっちこっち、ここだよ、もう
Over here, right here!
よいしょ
Whew.
あ、そこか！ありがとう、ありがとう
Ah, there! Thanks, thanks!
目の前
Right ahead.
で、これでもう奥まで行ったらあるかな？
If we go all the way inside, will it be there?
行ってみましょう
Let's go check it out!
うん
Yeah.
行きます
Here we go!
洞窟？
A cave?
洞窟ですね
It's a cave, all right.
うわー、面白ーい！
Woah, cool!
めっちゃ青いな
It's super blue!
ねー
Yeah!
強猾のアーティファクトっていうやつを...
The Artifact of the Clever...
取る
We take it.
一番奥まで行けたら多分あるはず
If we get all the way to the end, it should be there.
はい
Okay.
でも結構ずっと飛んで行けそうな感じはしてますけどね
But it feels like we can just fly the whole way through.
ねー
Yeah!
うわー、でも広い！
Woah, but it's huge!
これ右行ってる？
Are you going right?
あ、左行ってみた、今
Ah, I tried going left just now.
3人右行ってるよね？
Three of us are going right, right?
左行くわ
I'll go left.
右行き止まりだった
Right was a dead end!
左結構広いよ
Left is pretty spacious!
嘘？見えなかっただけ？
Really? Did I just miss it?
フブ先輩ついてってる？
Is Fubu-senpai following?
一旦このまま真っ直ぐ行ってみてる
I'm just heading straight for now.
じゃあ、ちょっと左行ってみようかな
Maybe I'll try going left then.
美々も左行ってます
Bibi is going left too!
これみんなで手分けした方がいい？
Should we split up?
みんなで手分けしたっていい
It's fine if we split up.
美々1人で恐いな
Bibi is scared alone!
あれ？これもしや...
Huh? Could this be...
別なとこ出ちゃった？
Did I end up somewhere else?
なんか違いそうですよね、こっち側
It seems wrong on this side.
このフブキ先輩も居るところ...
Here where Fubuki-senpai is...
これさ、別のチームも居るかも
Wait, there might be another team here too!
え？
Huh?
あれ？その場合ってどうするんだっけ？
Wait, what do we do in that case?
いや、ここ分かんないけど...
I don't know about this spot, but...
え、ここ洞窟か？
Wait, is this a cave?
ここ洞窟じゃないか？
Isn't this a cave?
あ、なんか絶妙だよね。この判定的に。
Ah, it's kind of subtle, in terms of hitboxes.
違うよ。
No, it's not.
なんだここ？どこ行けばいいんだ？
What is this place? Where should I go?
なんだこれ？
What's this?
迷子の迷子の...
Lost, lost...
こねこちゃん...
...little kitten.
迷子だね。
You're lost, huh?
こっち行ってみるけど。
I'll try going this way.
分かりづらいちゃん！
It's hard to tell!
うわ、迷ってるんですかね？
Woah, are you lost?
ガスガスのガス。
Gassy gas.
でも、めっちゃ紫になってるはず。
But it should be really purple.
めっちゃ分かりやすいと思う。めっちゃ宝物みたいな感じの。
I think it's very easy to spot. It looks just like a treasure.
確かに、主張発してるから。
True, since it's standing out so much.
これダンジョンなの？そもそも、これってダンジョン？
Is this a dungeon? Wait, is this even a dungeon?
あ、でもなんかピンクの...
Oh, but there's a pink...
苔が見えた。
...moss visible.
ダンジョンじゃないならいいんじゃないかって思ったけど。
I thought if it's not a dungeon, then it's fine, but...
あ、青... あ、これキノコ... あ、青キノコだ！青キノコ来たよ！
Ah, blue... Ah, these are mushrooms... Ah, blue mushrooms! Here are blue mushrooms!
わー、なにこれ？
Woah, what's this?
このピンクのやつ、有機ポリマーだ。ちょっと待って。
This pink stuff is Organic Polymer. Hold on.
あー、そうだ！
Ah, right!
取っていいっすか？
Can I take it?
取ってくれてたやつよ。
That's what you were collecting.
あ、そうそうそう！あれ？
Ah, right, right, right! Wait?
あ！取れません！
Ah! I can't harvest it!
ものすごい、あ！見つけたかも！
Amazing, ah! I might have found it!
探者ねえぞ！
No seekers here!
ナイス！
Nice!
これあれだ！上行ったら出口だ！
This is it! If you go up, it's the exit!
これかな？
Is it this one?
なんか2個あるっぽいけど...
Looks like there are two of them, but...
これじゃないですか？
Isn't it this one?
あ、あ、あんたこれ「免疫のアーティファクト」ってやつだね、でも。
Ah, wait, this is the Artifact of the Immune, though.
あ、じゃあ強かつじゃないわ。
Ah, then it's not Cautious.
ま、でもまだあるはず。
Well, but there should be more.
それ、でも持っていっていいよ。
Still, you can take it with you.
うん、持って帰る！持って帰る！
Yeah, I'll take it back! I'll take it back!
じゃあ、こっちにしよ。
Then, let's go this way.
これ上行ったら外に出れそう。
Going up here looks like we can get outside.
迷子、迷子、迷子、迷子...
Lost, lost, lost, lost...
そうだね。集めてよかった！
Yeah. Glad I collected it!
え、免疫のアーティファクトの出口だったんじゃない？
Wasn't that the exit for the Artifact of the Immune?
ね、この、今フブキ先輩と風真が通った...
Right, where Fubuki-senpai and Kazama passed...
あー、ってことか！
Ah, I see!
多分そういうことなんだと...
I think that's what it is...
こっち行ってみるか、探す。
Shall I try going this way and search?
色々迷路です。
It's all a maze.
迷路だ！大変なことになってますわ。
It is a maze! Quite a chaotic mess, indeed.
やべえ、迷子。
Shoot, I'm lost.
もう迷子ですわ。
I'm completely lost now.
くそ迷子。
Super lost.
Oh my god.
もうみんなと離れている。
I'm already separated from everyone.
いや、でかい！広い！
Wow, it's huge! So spacious!
でかい！広い！ヤバい！
Huge! Spacious! Crazy!
これ何なんだろうな？
Wonder what this is?
でかい、広い、ヤバい、広い...
Huge, spacious, crazy, spacious...
でもなんか他の人見えないから、被ってないんじゃないか？
But since we can't see anyone else, maybe we're not overlapping?
ね。
Right.
いないか。
Maybe not.
さっきテリジノみたいなの乗ってたんだよな。
Earlier someone was riding something like a Therizino.
まあ...
Well...
すごいあり得ん黄色いとこは見つけたけど、これは何だ？
I found an unbelievably yellow place, but what is this?
何これー？
What is this?
分からんあげ。
Got no clue.
えーっと...
Um...
スタミナ回復。
Recovering stamina.
あー。
Ah.
左、左。
Left, left.
迷い...
Lost...
あ、重い重い重い重い！
Ah, lag, lag, lag, lag!
押して...
Press...
あ、なんだここ？
Oh, what is this place?
追っていく。イナ先輩いくよー。
Following. Ina-senpai, here I go!
はーい！
Okay!
あ、これ氷系か？
Ah, is this ice-themed?
こっちか？
Is it this way?
確かに。
True.
あ、なんか出てきた！
Ah, something came out!
ごめんトワねえ、ちょっとガンガン行っちゃってるわ。ふたりごめんね。
Sorry Towa-nee, I'm kind of rushing ahead. Sorry to you two.
ついて行けてません。大丈夫です。
We're not catching up. It's alright.
オッケー。
Okay.
見えなくなったら言ってー。
Tell me if you lose sight of me!
はーい！
Okay!
お城のところに出てきちゃった。
I ended up at the castle area.
いや、自分はまだ下でいろんな道探してるんですけど...
Well, I'm still below looking for various paths, but...
上にちょいちょい出れるところがあって... うー...
There are spots here and there where you can go up... oof...
そうだよね、出れるとこあるよね。
Right, there are places where you can exit.
プテラのね、スタミナ気をつけてね。
Watch out for Ptera's stamina, okay?
はーい！
Okay!
一旦ここで休まないと、スタミナ無くなる。
I need to rest here for a moment or I'll run out of stamina.
大変だ！
Oh no!
それはクリスタルか。
Is that crystal?
違うの？
No?
なんか本当に、ピンク色でブワァーッてオーラ生えてるアイテムがあるはず。
There should really be an item glowing pink with an aura coming off it.
そう、誰かはいるんだけど、ここが果たして洞窟扱いなのかが分かんない。
Yeah, someone is here, but I don't know if this counts as a cave or not.
多分洞窟扱いだと思う。
I think it counts as a cave.
じゃ、待たないといけないってことか。でも何やってるか分かんないんだよね、結局。行っても。
So we have to wait. But in the end, I don't even know what they're doing if we go.
探してるのかな？あ、あそこがポータルか。
Are they searching? Ah, is that a portal over there?
あれ、違うか、ポータルじゃない。誰かの家か、ここ。
Wait, no, it's not a portal. Is this someone's house?
なんかのチームの家だ、ここ。
It's some team's house here.
ほえー。
Woah.
あれ、なんか強かつが必要なんだよね？
Wait, we need the Cautious artifact, right?
そうそう、強かつ！
Right, right, Cautious!
で、さっき免疫は見つけた。
And earlier I found Immune.
オッケー。
Okay.
免疫？
Immune?
うん。
Yeah.
なんかそれってさ、水色のところらへんに免疫あった？
Was Immune located around the light blue area?
水色の奥だね。
Deep in the light blue area.
じゃ、紫系のとこ進めば良っぽいけど... もう中入っちゃったから...
Then going through the purple-ish area seems right, but... I already went inside...
ちょっと分かんないんだけど...
I don't really know, though...
ちょっと紫っぽいとこ進んでみるか。水色が免疫だから...
Let me try going through the purple-ish area. Since light blue is Immune...
水色が免疫？
Light blue is Immune?
そう、なんかアーティファクト...
Yeah, like an artifact...
っていう...
...sort of thing.
はい。
Yes.
なんかアクセサリー、なんていうの？オブジェクト？
Like an accessory, what do you call it? An object?
そう、オブジェクトがあるんだよね。あ、グリフォンだ。
Yeah, there's an object. Ah, it's a Griffin.
ふむふむ。
Hmm, I see.
なんか今ココヨととか、はじめちゃんとかもいたけど、見つけてないって言ってました。
Koyori and Hajime-chan were here earlier too, but they said they haven't found it.
なるほど？
I see.
まだ、誰か入っちゃってて、リポップ待ちとかかな？
Maybe someone else went in, so they're waiting for a respawn?
もしかすると。
Could be.
あ、トロフィー、トロフィー。
Ah, trophy, trophy.
かなー。
Maybe so.
マップはね、こんな感じっすね。
The map looks like this.
あ、行っちゃった。ごめんなさい、ごめんなさい。
Ah, I went ahead. Sorry, sorry.
なに？なに？
What? What?
怖い、怖い！
Scary, scary!
キモキモ虫がいるから気をつけて。
Gross bugs are around, so be careful.
ね、見たことない生き物いっぱいいる、ここ。
Yeah, there are lots of creatures I've never seen before here.
そうの！ここね、結構強いんだよね。なんかレベリングする...
Exactly! It's pretty tough here. Good for leveling up...
どこかは結構いい
Somewhere around here is pretty good.
レベリングに最適な洞窟かな
A cave optimal for leveling, I think.
敵が強い
The enemies are strong.
だけど...
Although...
うわ！クモいた！スパイダー！
Whoa! There was a spider! A spider!
えーっと...
Um...
え、こっちじゃないんだ
Huh, it's not this way.
あ、あっち側か
Ah, it's that way?
スパイダーいるやん、スパイダー！下なのか上のほうなのかどっちなんだろう
There's a spider, a spider! Is it down below or up above? I wonder which.
湧いてないのかー
They haven't spawned?
なんなのか...
What is going on...
イナ先輩いますか？
Is Ina-senpai here?
多分戻ってきてるんだと思う
I think they probably went back.
迷子になったかもー
I might be lost~
オーケー、他のチーム見つかった
Okay, found the other team.
迷子、迷子ー
Lost, lost~
ほな、オーケーです
Then it's okay.
むむむむ...
Mmm...
あ、ビビやばい スタミナ
Ah, Bibi's stamina is bad.
ぐるぐる待ちの...
Spinning around waiting...
黄緑色のキノコが近くにあれば、その近くにあるらしい
If there are yellowish-green mushrooms nearby, it's supposedly near there.
何だここ、なんか私変なとこ抜けた、これまじで
What is this place? Did I come out in a weird spot, seriously?
黄緑色の...
Yellowish-green...
これ一応黄緑色だけどな
This is technically yellowish-green though.
俺、俺大丈夫これ？
Am I, am I okay with this?
次元の狭間... 次元の狭間
The gap between dimensions... the gap between dimensions.
次元の狭間？
Gap between dimensions?
とりあえずちょっと出口探すか
For now, let me look for an exit.
はーい！天井吹き抜けてたら分かりやすいか
Okay! It should be easy to tell if the ceiling opens up.
天井吹き抜けで結構出れそうなとこはありましたね
There was a spot where the ceiling opened up and looked like we could get out.
あれ？テレポートどこだっけ
Huh? Where was the teleporter again?
テレポートこの辺なんだけどな
The teleporter should be around here though...
これじゃない？ 天井吹き抜けのキノコって
Isn't it this? The mushroom where the ceiling opens up.
ほんまや、なんかある！ お、黄緑色ありますよ、キノコ！
Really! There's something! Oh, there are yellowish-green mushrooms!
ねー、書いてある。これ何？
Hey, it's written. What's this?
びっさ、びっさ！ 中いる！
Bissa, bissa! Someone's inside!
中いる、中いる、やだ！
Someone's inside, someone's inside! Oh no!
あれ？ 俺は帰れるのだろうか
Huh? Will I be able to go back?
一旦上に出てこれたら... 上に出たらなんか異空間だった
Once we can get up... when I got up, it was like a weird space.
出口っぽいけど... 異空間でした、上
It looked like an exit... but up above was an alternate dimension.
出れないや、これ
We can't get out, this way.
上からは出れないね
Can't get out from above.
頑張って出口を探すんだ
Do your best to search for an exit.
体がでかいからと思ったけど
I thought it was because my body was big...
ちょっと待って、下に降りたいんだけど
Wait a second, I want to go down below.
ないよ！ いた、いた！ 助けて！
There isn't! Ow, ow! Help me!
あ、誰かが下にいる
Ah, someone is down below.
虫たかってる！ 虫たかってると失礼
Bugs are swarming! Excuse me, bugs are swarming!
ここどこ？
Where is this?
わーい、ビビ！ ここどこ？
Yay, Bibi! Where is this?
いや、ちょっとマップから出てって...
No, I kind of went outside the map...
あ、トワ様とはぐれた！ トワ様！
Ah, I got separated from Towa-sama! Towa-sama!
集合場所行こうか、ちょっと待ってね
Shall we go to the meeting spot? Wait a second.
虫にたかられてる、ビビ！ 虫くさくない？
Swarmed by bugs, Bibi! Aren't the bugs stinky?
あ、会えた、今日
Ah, we met today.
ここ... ここね、多分...
Here... here, probably...
変なとこ来ちゃった
We came to a weird place.
だよね！
Right?!
あれ？ ビビ一人で出れない？ なるほど
Huh? Bibi can't get out alone? I see.
行けるかな？ 裏画面いって草
I wonder if I can? Going out of bounds lol.
みんな来てるジャン！
Everyone is here!
みんな来て草！ みんな来てる？
Everyone came, lol! Is everyone here?
これ、もしかすると他のチームもここ探してるっぽいから
This, maybe the other team is searching here too,
湧いてない可能性なのでは
so maybe they haven't spawned?
巣立ちの可能性はちょっと出てきましたね
The possibility of them leaving the nest is starting to show up.
これ上抜けたら抜けれるのかな
If I clip through the top here, can I get out?
あ、抜けれないね
Ah, can't get out.
抜けれなかった
Couldn't get out.
水？ え、どこ？
Water? Huh, where?
どこか分からない
I don't know where.
なんかこの辺にテレポータルが...
There's a teleportal around here...
なんか水の中に入っ... え！？
Entering into the water... Huh?!
これ出れそうで見せかけやの
It looks like an exit, but it's a trick.
やばい、みんなが... 大丈夫か？
Oh no, everyone... are you okay?
どこなんだろう？
Where is it?
ビビ迷子になって虫にたかられてどうしよう
Bibi got lost and swarmed by bugs, what should I do?
ま、とりあえず移動しまくって天井抜けれるところ探すしかない
Well, for now we just have to keep moving and look for a place to clip through the ceiling.
天井でも結構抜けれないかも
Even through the ceiling, we might not be able to get out.
天井触らない方がいいですよ、今ちょっと
Better not touch the ceiling right now...
触らない方がいい、天井
Better not touch it, the ceiling.
分かりました
Understood.
なんかバグる？ バグってる
Is it bugging out? It's bugging out.
めっちゃ泳いでます、でも出れない
Swimming so much, but can't get out.
出口が見つからない
Can't find the exit.
あ、出ようとするとガクガクする感じなのかな
Ah, when you try to get out, does it jitter?
ブロッキングされてる感じしますね
Feels like it's being blocked.
ね！ あー、なるほど
Right! Ah, I see.
引っかかっちゃってるのか
It's getting stuck?
なんかちょっと待っててだって、アキ先輩が
Aki-senpai says to wait a bit.
これ多分死ぬから、ポテンしてもらう
I'm probably going to die here, so I'll get teleported.
え、なんか下に行ったら... でもバグってる、また
Eh, when I went down... but it's bugged again.
バグってるからやっぱり一旦待機でいいかもね
Since it's bugged, waiting for a moment might be best.
一旦待機... ちょっと高いところにいた方が
Wait for a moment... better stay somewhere high.
一生テレポ探して迷子になってるわ
I've been searching for the teleporter forever and getting lost.
オーケー、どうしよう、集会場スボーンして
Okay, what should we do? Respawn at the assembly area...
ふむふむ、これ...
Hmm, this...
一旦... はい
For now... yes.
アキちゃんに、えー言うか
Tell Aki-chan, um...
これビビも言った方がいいですか？
Should Bibi say something too?
プテラ死ぬな、これ。
My Pteranodon is gonna die at this rate.
全員やってくれてんのかな、言ったら。
I wonder if everyone will do it if I ask.
たぶん全員やってくれるはず。
Everyone will probably do it.
一旦、町で...
For now, in town...
待とう。
Let me wait.
あ、なんか...
Ah, something...
光ってる...
It's glowing...
あのー、白いところに来たら、戻れました、マップに。
Um, when I went to that white area, I was able to get back to the map.
戻れた？
You got back?
嘘！
No way!
ナイス！
Nice!
どこかわかんないですけど。
I don't know where I am though.
出れたなら、よかった、よかった。
If you got out, that's great.
ねー、ナイス出れて。
Yeah, glad you got out.
あ、出れたかな？またバグってる？
Ah, did you get out? Are you bugged again?
アキちゃんのところ行ってみるわ。
I'll try going to Aki-chan's location.
あーい。
Okay.
アキ先輩来るから待ってて。
Aki-senpai is coming, so wait there.
待つわ、オッケー。
I'll wait, okay.
あーい。
Okay.
すごいんだけどな。
It's pretty bad though.
あ、またバグってる。
Ah, it's bugged again.
いや、イナもね、ちょっと待ったほうがワンチャンいいかもしれない。
Ina, maybe it's better for you to wait a bit too.
あ、そうですね。
Ah, right.
ここで待ちます。
I'll wait here.
なんか調査してくれてるっていうから、ちょっと待ってて、ゆっくり。
They said they're investigating, so take it easy and wait a bit.
あーい。
Okay.
私よくわかんないんですけど、普通ってこういう洞窟って上からひょひょっと抜けられるものなんですか？
I don't really know, but usually in these caves, can you just easily slip out from above?
どうなんだろう？
I wonder.
たぶん抜けられ...抜け穴はあると思うけどな。入口...
I think you can... there should be an escape hole, but...
そうそう。
Right, right.
指定の入口以外の、ちょっと「あ、ここ抜けれそうだな」のところから抜けるとダメっぽいわ。
It seems like a bad idea to slip out from somewhere that looks like an exit other than the main entrance.
あ、そうなんだ。大きい開いてるところじゃなきゃダメなのか。
Ah, I see. So it has to be a big open entrance.
あ、そうそうそう。抜けれそうだったんだけどね。
Yeah, exactly. It looked like I could slip through though.
もっと上か、これ？
Is it higher up?
へー、そうなんだ。
Huh, I see.
あ、フブキたちの立ち位置...
Ah, where Fubuki and the others are...
開いてるところ見当たんないぞ、これ以外。
I don't see any open spots other than this.
バグっちゃってる3人以外は...
Other than the three who are bugged...
あの、安全なところで洞窟出られたら...
if you can get out of the cave in a safe spot...
あ、痛い痛い痛い！
Ah, ow, ow, ow!
イタッ！やばい！また虫に、痛い痛い痛い！
Ow! Oh no! The bugs again, ow, ow, ow!
虫！
Bugs!
気をつけて！
Be careful!
やばいやばいやばい！
Oh no, oh no, oh no!
虫無視したら、虫無視したら...
If you ignore the bugs... if you ignore them...
虫は無視！
Ignore the bugs!
さ、寒い...
S-So cold...
あ、なんか急に...
Ah, all of a sudden...
あ、出口辿り着きました、かな？
Ah, did you reach the exit?
あ、よかった、よかった！
Ah, thank goodness!
あ、よかった！
Ah, good!
アタマは辿り着いたけど...
My body made it, but...
死ぬばっかりで全然辿り着かない！
I keep dying and can't reach it at all!
身ぐるみ剥がされて！
I'm completely stripped!
はい！はい！
Yes! Yes!
さっきのスタックの件なんですけど順次...
Regarding the issue where you got stuck earlier...
スタックしていた地点の近くにテレポート対応を順次しておりますので、よろしくお願いします。
We are sequentially teleporting everyone near where you got stuck, so please stand by.
あ、アキちゃん！
Ah, Aki-chan!
アキちゃん、ありがとう！
Aki-chan, thank you!
はい、はい！
Yes, yes!
私、死んで装備全ロスしました。異空間。
I died and lost all my gear in hyperspace.
異空間に行って取りに行けなさそう...その近くでは見えないってこと？
You went into hyperspace and can't retrieve it? You can't see it nearby?
えっとね...
Well...
なんか変なところにワープしちゃって、池の中か海の中か何かで...
I warped to a weird place, like inside a pond or the ocean...
溺れ死んで、どこに死んだかわかんない。
and drowned, so I don't know where I died.
あ、ワイバーン達が死んだ！
Ah, the wyverns died!
ちょっと確認しますね。
Let me check on that.
はい、お願いします。
Yes, please.
ワイバーン達...
The wyverns...
アキ先輩、あとトワちゃんのプテラも...
Aki-senpai, and Towa-chan's Pteranodon too...
そのスタックしちゃって...なくなっちゃった？
Did they get stuck... and disappear?
洞窟の中でスタックしちゃって、もう死ぬしかなくて死んじゃったって感じだね。
They got stuck in the cave and had no choice but to die, so they died.
そっか。了解、ちょっと確認します。
I see. Got it, I'll check.
フブタムもここで復活して、恐竜とかね...
Fubutam also respawned here, and the dinosaurs...
すみません、美々はただの迷子なんです。スタックしてない、ただの迷子...
Sorry, Bibi is just lost. Not stuck, just lost...
美々は...
Bibi is...
洞窟はいろいろ...
The cave has various...
絶対出られるから。
You can definitely get out.
美々はただの迷子。
Bibi is just lost.
マップ開いてさ、緯度経度どこにいるかわかります？マップの下に書いてあるんですけど。
If you open the map, can you tell your latitude and longitude? It's written at the bottom of the map.
あ、緯度が...あれかな私の装備？
Ah, latitude... is that my gear?
25.6。
25.6.
経度が43.6です。
Longitude is 43.6.
緯度が17になるように帰ってきたら、たぶん帰ってこれる。
If you come back so that the latitude becomes 17, you can probably make it back.
出口に行って17ぐらい...
Go towards the exit, around 17...
17助かる！17助かる！こっち...
17 helps! 17 helps! Over here...
17の42で帰れます。
You can make it back at 17, 42.
17の42？わー、美々地図読めないよ！あー！
17, 42? Wow, Bibi can't read maps! Ah!
でもここにワープ...ここにワープされて私何もできないんだけど、どうしたらいいんだ？これ。
But I warped here... I got warped here and can't do anything, what should I do?
居た！居た！
There! There!
恐竜とかもちょっと見てくれてるんじゃない？
Aren't they looking out for the dinosaurs too?
ここで待機すればいいか。
Should I just wait here then?
うん。
Yeah.
17の47...こっち。
17, 47... over here.
フブちゃん達のところと合流するね。最後だけ結構青いですね。
I'll go join Fubu-chan and the others. It's quite blue only at the end.
あーい。
Okay.
最後だけ一瞬青くて、途中までは赤かったりさんで...
It was blue for just a second at the very end, but was red up until then...
もう下手動くのやめとこ。
I should stop moving around blindly.
一本道進もうかな。
Maybe I'll follow the straight path.
あ、赤いのも見えますね。
Ah, I can see red ones too.
ピラニアがウジャウジャいた。
Piranhas were swarming.
え、この辺？道思い出してきたわ。この辺だ。
Eh, around here? I'm starting to remember the path. Around here.
合流できたわ。
I managed to group up.
あ、これだ！あった！やっと見つけた！
Ah, this is it! There it is! I finally found it!
えー、行き止まり...
Eh, a dead end...
あ、通った？
Ah, did you pass through?
あ、ごめん、違っ...ただの迷子になってた、外で。
Ah, sorry, no... I was just lost outside.
アーティファクト探します！
I'll search for the artifact!
あ、フブちゃんさ。
Ah, Fubu-chan.
うん？
Yeah?
ちょっとここで待って、ここで待って。
Wait here for a second, wait here.
あーい、ここね？
Okay, here?
えっと、ちょっと言うわ。
Um, I'll tell you.
ん？
Hmm?
指示するからそれに沿って行ってほしい。
I'll give instructions, so follow along.
あ、了解了解。まっすぐ行くよ、とりあえず。
Ah, roger roger. I'll go straight for now.
じゃあ...
Well then...
さん探しいついでに行っちゃう感御座あるな。護衛でアルゲン居るから...
We might as well head over while searching. We have an Argentavis as an escort...
あ、じゃアルゲンで...
Ah, then with the Argentavis...
あ、これ待って、他のチーム居るんですけど、他のチームに連れて行ってもらうのアリですか？
Ah, wait, there's another team here. Is it okay if we ask them to take us along?
他のチーム探してるんじゃないか？
Aren't they looking for someone too?
えー？
Eh?
じゃあ待っといた方がいいかもね。
Then maybe we should wait.
まっすぐ進む... まっすぐ進む...
Keep moving straight... Keep moving straight...
うん、進んでます、進んでます。
Yep, we're moving forward.
はい、こちらアキヨシです。ぼたんちゃん、失ったのって何の恐竜だった？
Yes, this is Akiyoshi. Botan-chan, which dinosaur did you lose?
えっとね...
Well...
プテラと...
A Pteranodon and...
あの、何だっけ？ メガ...
Um, what was it again? Mega...
メガテリウム。
Megatherium.
メガテリ。
メガテリ。この2体。
Megatherium. Those two.
一回死んじゃうね？
Going down to check the corpse once?
前回死んだ位置もね、一応出ているよ。
The last death location is showing up too.
あっ、じゃあマップ座標言っていい？ 死んだ場所。
Ah, then can I read out the map coordinates? Where I died.
オッケー。
Okay.
死んだ場所の座標がね、えっと... 経度21.9で...
The coordinates for the death location are... latitude 21.9...
あ、緯度が21.9、経度41.9。
Ah, latitude is 21.9, longitude is 41.9.
41.9。
41.9.
ちょっとそれで伝えてみます。
I'll try telling them that.
はい。の... 多分ね、川の中で死んでるね。
Yeah. Probably died in the river.
ちょっと確認するね。
Let me check real quick.
はい、お願いします。
Okay, please do.
あ、テリジノか。ま、いっか。伝わってるだろ。
Ah, Therizino? Well, whatever. They got the message.
伝わっとるからいい。
It got through, so it's fine.
しばしお待ち。
Please wait a moment.
伝わる伝わる。大丈夫大丈夫。
They'll get it. It's fine, it's fine.
はい、えっと、アキヨシです。ぼたんちゃん...
Yes, um, this is Akiyoshi. Botan-chan...
テリジノのは伝わっていて、テレポートが今その場だと何も持ってない状態だと思うんだけど...
The Therizino info got through. If you teleport right now, you won't have anything on you...
えっと、1回戻してほしい場所ある？ とりあえず。
Um, is there a place you want to be sent back to for now?
あ、もう集会場でいいかな、とりあえず。
Ah, the meeting area should be fine for now.
オッケー、じゃあ一旦そこに周会場に送らせてもらうね。
Okay, then I'll send you back to the meeting area for now.
はい、オッケーです。
Okay, got it.
ふふふ、なんか動いてるｗ
Hehehe, something's moving.
え、大丈夫ですか？ ししろー。
Uh, are you okay, Shishiro?
大丈夫だよ。
I'm fine.
あ、全然大丈夫だよ。死んだところで何も、こいつ捨て身行けるからｗ
Ah, I'm totally fine. Even if I die, I can just go all-out on this guy.
何でいけます？ これ。
How can we go on with this?
みんなの場所に行くのがいいから...
It's better to go to where everyone is...
あ、いいよいいよ、全然行ってきて。あたしあの復活待ちしてるから、大丈夫だよ。
Ah, go ahead, it's totally fine. I'm waiting for respawn anyway, so it's fine.
うん。
Yeah.
どこ行けばいいのか分かんない...
I don't know where I should go...
みんなね、チームVC 2に行ってるから。2に行くと大丈夫だよ。
Everyone is in Team VC 2. You'll be good if you join VC 2.
あー、はい、オッケーです。
Ah, okay, got it.
いいよー。
Alright~
はい！ みんな今どこですか？
Yes! Where is everyone right now?
今入り口！
We're at the entrance right now!
入り口！ ちょっと探してみます。
At the entrance! I'll try looking for you.
えっとね、マップ... 緯度が...
Um, on the map... latitude is...
17かな？
17, maybe?
17の42くらい目指して帰ると帰れる。
Aim for around 17, 42, and you can make it back.
ごめんね、いなちゃん。
Sorry, Ina-chan.
いやいや。行けるか？
No worries. Can you make it?
アルジェントのところですか？
Is it near the Argentavis?
あ、そうだね。アルジェントのところ辺りで。
Ah, yeah. Around where the Argentavis is.
行くよ、じゃあ。
Alright, let me head over.
えっと、赤い... 赤いキノコか？
Um, red... is it red mushrooms?
ここ赤いキノコです。で、ここ左右に分かれるところ。
Red mushrooms are here. And this is where it splits left and right.
下？ え？
Down? Huh?
そろそろ左に行くって書いてあるけどね。
It says to go left around here, though.
はい、左。左進みます。
Okay, left. Proceeding left.
ここか。
Is it here?
で、ここから敵が出てきます。
And enemies will start appearing from here.
で、ここでちょっと広い空間で...
And here, in a slightly open space...
あ、待って。
Ah, wait.
あ、待って、このキノコ... ん？ ちょっと待ってね。
Ah, wait, this mushroom... Hm? Hold on a sec.
はいはい。
Okay.
戻ります。
Turning back.
ぼっちゃん居ない。
Bocchan isn't here.
この辺りから敵生物... ちょっと待って。
Hostile creatures start from around here... Wait a second.
まっすぐ進んで、えっと、最初の...
Go straight, and um, the first...
最初の分かれ道...
The first fork in the road...
うん。
Yeah.
最初の分かれ道を...
The first fork in the road...
左の坂を進むって書いてあるけど、なんかさ、見ているの違うんだけど...
It says to take the slope on the left, but what I'm looking at seems different...
坂ないですよね。
There's no slope, right?
あれかな？ 入り口が違うんか？
Maybe... is the entrance different?
か、あの、これASAの洞窟だから...
Or, um, since this is an ASA cave...
旧ARKの洞窟と、もしや違うのか？
Is it different from the old ARK cave?
ASAラグナロクって書いてあるんだけどな...
It says ASA Ragnarok, though...
待って、塔のところまで戻るよ、じゃあ。青いキノコがあるから...
Wait, I'll head back to the tower then. There are blue mushrooms...
これが坂じゃない？ ここ。
Isn't this the slope? Right here.
これがね、坂... あー！
This is the slope... Ah!
うんうん。ここ坂です、ここ坂です。
Yeah yeah. This is a slope, this is a slope.
ここをまず左、もしや？
Take a left here first, maybe?
ここ坂です。
This is a slope.
どう？
How is it?
坂を上... ん？こう、まっ... 分かれ道を正面にしてもらって
Go up the slope... Huh? Go straight... Face the fork in the road,
分かれ道... 分かれ道ここかな？こう？
The fork in the road... Is this the fork? Like this?
それ左じゃない？
Isn't that left?
ここ左。ここ左で、オッケー。ここ間を左。はいはい。
Left here. Left here, okay. Left between here. Okay.
で、広いとこ出ます。多分。
Then you'll reach an open area, probably.
あ、引っかかる！引っかかる！
Ah, I'm stuck! I'm stuck!
あ、広いとこ出た。うん、広いとこ出た。
Ah, reached the open area. Yeah, reached the open area.
で、まっすぐでいいのかな？
And then, should we go straight?
まっすぐ行って一本道だね。うん、うん。
Go straight, it's a single path. Yeah, yeah.
よいしょ
Up we go.
で、まっすぐ行って、そこじゃない？
And go straight, isn't it there?
ここ行き止まりだから右かな？右、うん、そこは大丈夫。
It's a dead end here, so right? Right, yeah, that's fine there.
うん、右行って、うん。
Yeah, go right, yeah.
ここ、まっすぐが左。
Here, straight ahead is left.
ここまっすぐが左。
待ってね。
Wait a sec.
あ、ちょっと敵が...
Ah, wait, enemies...
あ、こいつか。
Ah, this guy.
まっすぐか左です。
Go straight or left.
やばいこれね、ちょっとわかんないわ。
Oh no, with this, I can't really tell.
なんかちょっと違うんだよな。
Something feels a bit off.
左行ってみるか。
Shall we try going left?
レベル強っ！言ってもここ一本道...
Level is so high! But since it's a single path...
だから結局はこの広い空間にやってきちゃうんだよな。
so in the end, we just end up in this wide open space.
あ、なんかぐるっと一周するだけっぽいな、なんか。
Ah, looks like it just loops around in a circle.
そうだよね、多分ね。ね。
Right, probably. Right.
なんかぐるっと一周して帰ってこれちゃうわ。
It just loops around and brings us back.
ムズすぎだろ！
Isn't this way too hard?!
ちょっと行ってみるわ、トワも。
I'll try going in too, Towa.
こう行って、こう行って...
Go like this, go like this...
え、ちょっとBBさん...
Wait, BB-san...
イナ先輩救出救護隊行こうかな。
Should I join the Ina-senpai rescue team?
あ、オッケー。着きました？
Ah, okay. Did you arrive?
ここ左だよね。
It's left here, right?
一回ちょっとイナ先輩... う...
Wait a bit, Ina-senpai... uh...
一回もう一個下に...
One level further down...
これ... 入り口が違うんかな？
Is... is the entrance different?
あ、いや、ん？ここだな。
Ah, no, huh? It's here.
こう行って、ここにあったりとかもしや...
Go like this, maybe it's around here...
イナ先輩、無事下に来れますか？
Ina-senpai, can you safely get down here?
あ、うん。居たわ！居た居た。
Ah, yeah. There she is! There she is!
居たよー！
I found you~!
あ、居た！居た？
Ah, there! Were you there?
居た。イナ先輩居た。そしたらね、イナ先輩...
Found her. Ina-senpai was there. Then, Ina-senpai...
あ、こっちの... あ、居た居た居た。
Ah, over here... Ah, there, there, there.
ここが一応出口だから、ここにいとけば間違いないかも。
This is technically the exit, so if we stay here, it might be safe.
じゃあ、もう青いほうが...
Then, the blue side is better...
この... あ、あそこテレポーター目の前なんで。
This... Ah, the teleporter is right in front of there.
うん。ここにいてもらえれば安全かと。
Yeah. It's safe if you stay here.
ここで待つ？
Wait here?
うん、ちょっとビビさん見に行きます。
Yeah, I'll go check on Bibi-san.
オッケー。
Okay.
行けそう？
Does it look doable?
いや、すごーく難しいんじゃないの？これ。
No, isn't this super difficult?
広いよね、すごく。
It's really wide, isn't it?
広いね。
It's wide.
めっちゃ広い。
Super wide.
だから、どうしたものか...
So, what should we do...
これ戻ってきたな。
We came back here.
あ、あそこお手洗い行ってきます。
Ah, I'm going to the restroom real quick.
いってらっしゃい。
Have a safe trip!
こっち... ここ... こことか... ここ...
This way... Here... Around here... Here...
ここは違う... ここは違う。ここ一方通行だったよね？
Not here... Not here. This was a one-way path, right?
あ、じゃあこっち... さっき... さっきこっち来たんだっけ？
Ah, then this way... Earlier... Did I come this way earlier?
さっきこっちで休んだからこっちなんだよ。
I rested over here earlier, so it's this way.
で、こっちですもんね。
And it's this way, right?
なんでここ... むちゃくちゃ広いとこ出たわ。
Why here... Ended up in an insanely huge place.
そうそう。むちゃくちゃ広いとこあるんですわ。
Right, right. There's an insanely huge place, you see.
めちゃくちゃ広いとこから... なんかあれなのかな。
From that super huge place... Is it like...
とりあえずここだよね。ここ、さっきこっちに行ったらあって、アーティファクトがね。
Anyway, it's here, right? Earlier, when I went this way, it was there—the artifact, I mean.
おー！すごいぞ、これ！
Oh! This is awesome!
こっちに行ったらアーティファクト発見。
If you go this way, artifact discovered.
まあ、地道に探索だな、これ。
Well, guess we just have to search steadily.
地道に探索なのかー... もう取られちゃってリポップ待ち tenter どっちかがちょっと分かんない...
Steadily searching, huh... Or maybe it was already taken and we're waiting for repop... I'm not really sure which...
助けて
"Help me."
分からないのがちょっとあれかな
"Not knowing is a bit tricky, I guess."
そうだね
"That's true."
あの上？
"Above that?"
休んだ場所に1回戻りやす
"Let's head back once to where I rested."
来ない？
"Is it not coming?"
休んだ場所...
"The place I rested..."
あ、違っ違っ、引っかかっちゃった
"Ah, wait wait, I got stuck."
壁沿いに向かって
"Heading along the wall..."
おいしょ
"Alright."
その上、その上
"Above that, above that!"
白いところまで合ってて
"Up to the white part was right..."
ここ？
"Here?"
I think we're trying to get the artifact...
場所的に一番近いらしい。ここ！
"Location-wise, this is supposed to be the closest. Here!"
嘘？
"Really?"
緑キノコの...あ
"The green mushroom's... ah."
Uh, it's a bit...
あ、てかフブちゃん、あ、フブちゃんじゃねえ、イロハだったわ
"Ah, wait, Fubu-chan—no, that was Iroha."
うん
"Yeah."
あったかも！
"I might have found it!"
え、マジ？
"Wait, really?"
あー、これだ！
"Ah, this is it!"
多分これだ！
"This is probably it!"
あった？
"Did you find it?"
お、見つけました？
"Oh, did you find it?"
あったー！
"Found it!"
マジかよ！来たー！
"No way! Awesome!"
ナイスー！
"Nice!"
よかった！なるほど！
"Thank goodness! I see!"
ありがとう！スコン部感謝！
"Thank you! Thanks to the Sukonbu!"
おー、あっちが出口ですか？
"Oh, is that the exit over there?"
帰ろ、帰ろ、帰ろ
"Let's head back, head back, head back."
おいしょ、ここから...オッケーオッケー、帰り道はわかる
"Alright, from here... Okay, okay, I know the way back."
ナイスー！
"Nice!"
あー、よかった、よかった！
"Ah, thank goodness, thank goodness!"
あ、降りちゃった、降りちゃったよ！バカバカバカ！
"Ah, I dropped down! Dumb dumb dumb!"
よいしょ
"Alright."
ああ、よかった、これで...
"Ah, thank goodness. With this..."
ミッション一個クリア！
"one mission cleared!"
ナイスです！
"Nice job!"
で、アーティファクト2個ゲットしたし、ナイスだね！
"And we got two artifacts, so nice!"
そしたらメディカルブリューで、もしやライティングワイバーンいける？
"Then with Medical Brews, maybe we can take on a Lightning Wyvern?"
メディカルブリューがまだ作れてないかなー
"We haven't made Medical Brews yet, I think."
メディカルブリュー作りたいね
"I want to make Medical Brews."
あ、違う違う違う、こっちこっちこっち
"Ah, wait wait wait, this way this way!"
こっちこっちこっち、あ、誰かいる！
"This way this way! Ah, someone's there!"
あ！
"Ah!"
お？
"Oh?"
誰かいる？誰かいる？
"Is someone there? Is someone there?"
出口かな？
"Is it the exit?"
出口きつー！重っ！
"The exit is tough! Heavy!"
あれ？気のせい？
"Huh? My imagination?"
でも出口近くにいるよ！言った方がいい
"I'm near the exit though! Better go there."
今、なんか人が歩い...あ
"Wait, someone was walking... ah."
誰かいる
"Someone is there."
マイクがあれか、入ってないからか
"Maybe because my mic isn't on?"
ヤッホー、ヤッホー
"Yaho, yaho!"
よいしょ
"Alright."
運営さんか？それとも
"Is that a staff member? Or..."
運営さんか、運営さんが置いてくれたのかな、もしかして
"A staff member? Did the staff place it here, maybe?"
ありがとうございます！
"Thank you very much!"
やっぱなんかリポップする前に運営さんが置いてくれるっぽいね、これね
"Looks like staff place them before they respawn."
あー
"Ah..."
へー！
"Huh!"
うん
"Yeah."
なるほどね、運営さんが設置してくれるんだ
"I see, staff set them up for us."
感謝！
"So grateful!"
よしよし、帰ります、帰ります、帰ります
"Alright, heading back, heading back, heading back."
ほんならあとあれか、パ、パイロ？
"Then after that... Py- Pyro?"
パイロ？
"Pyro?"
パイロメインも欲しいよな
"We'd want a Pyromane too, right?"
よいしょ、火山に行ってまた
"Alright, going back to the volcano."
あ、こっち、こっちこっちこっち
"Ah, here, this way, this way..."
こっち行って、こっち行ってこっち
"Go here, and then go here..."
あ、全然違う
"Ah, totally wrong."
戻ろ戻ろ
"Let's go back, go back."
戻りましょう
"Let's head back."
うん
"Yeah."
えっと、川があって
"Um, there's a river..."
いや、マジでよかった！
"Man, I'm really glad!"
広すぎた！
"It was way too big!"
本当広すぎた！こちらこちら
"Really way too big! Over here, over here."
まさかのラグナロクの広いんだな
"Who knew Ragnarok was so huge?"
めちゃめちゃ広いね！
"It's ridiculously big!"
半端なかった！
"It was insane!"
ヤバいね！
"That's crazy!"
広かったな
"It was so huge."
おい、おい、おい、おい
"Yep, yep, yep, yep."
よし、ま、でももう洞窟って行くあれ無いか？
"Alright, but we don't need to enter caves anymore, right?"
ボスチャレの時に、何がいるのか調べないとあれかもね
"When we challenge bosses, we might need to look up what we need."
あ、確かに！帰ってきましたー
"Ah, true! I'm back~"
あ、ナイス！
"Ah, nice!"
おかえりなさーい
"Welcome back~"
ただいまー！あ、すごいテレポータラグー
"I'm back~! Ah, crazy teleporter lag."
イナちゃんはどこだ？
"Where's Ina-chan?"
あ、ここです
"Ah, over here."
あ、テレポした。帰ろ帰ろ！
Ah, it teleported. Let's head back, let me return!
あっきー
Okay.
はい、ほんじゃ行きます。
Okay, here I go then.
はーい
Okay.
はい。おっしょ。
Okay. Up we go.
ふぅ... あっきー。
Phew... Okay.
じゃあ上に戻るのかな、ワンチャン。
So maybe we head back up, perhaps?
はい
Okay.
ただいまー！
I'm back!
見つけてきたよ！あった、あった！
I found it! It was there, it was there!
上に出なきゃいけないところが分かんなくなっちゃった。
But I lost track of where to exit at the top.
やっぱ迷いますよね。 / 迷うよね。
You really get lost, don't you? / Yeah, you get lost.
うん、迷うー。
Yeah, I'm totally lost...
あ、そうか、これ周回上にアーティファクト飾れるのか。
Ah, right, we can display artifacts around the perimeter?
そうそうそう、周回上に...
Right right right, around the perimeter...
えーっと、どうするんだっけ？納品しに行くのか。
Umm, what were we doing? Going to deliver them?
ここもずっと迷ってるの。
I'm continuously lost here too.
納品... えーっと...
Handing in... umm...
周回上にテレポ... 上に入る場所があったんですけど...
On the perimeter, telepor... there was a place to enter from above, but...
そういえばさ、マンモス...
Speaking of which, mammoth...
あ、そうだ！マンモスも行きたいって言ってたね。
Ah, right! They said they wanted to go for mammoth too.
マンモスも行きたいね。
We wanna go for mammoth too.
太鼓を叩くやつ。
The one that beats the drum.
とんでもないんだけど、相手。
The opponent is ridiculous though.
ん？すご、超進んでて...びっくり。
Hmm? Wow, you guys made super good progress... I'm surprised.
ねぇ、めちゃめちゃ進んでる！あ、来た！
Hey, you've advanced so much! Ah, you're here!
チームアーティファクト...でも全種類納品するってあるでしょ？
Team Artifact... but there's "Deliver all types", right?
それは多分、すごい最終ミッション的なやつじゃない？
That's probably a major final mission sort of thing, right?
あ、これ2つ納品してくれたのかな？今。
Ah, did they deliver two just now?
あ、すごい、上がっていってる！
Ah, awesome, it's going up!
出れた？あれ？なんかアーティファクトのとこ来ちゃった。
Did you get out? Huh? Somehow I ended up at the artifact place.
な、何だこれ？ビリビリしてる、ビリビリ。
Wh-What's this? It's zapping, zapping.
上衛さんが来てる？あれ？違う...
Is Ue-san here? Huh? No...
間違えてアーティファクトに来たわよ。出口分からん！
I mistakenly came to the artifact! I don't know where the exit is!
ごめんなさい、ビビが巻き込んだから...
Sorry, because Vivi dragged you in...
いや、大丈夫！書いてきてしまったよ。
No, it's fine! I ended up coming in.
ござる先輩も引き摺り込んでしまった、迷子という沼に。
Gozaru-senpai also got dragged into the swamp of being lost.
やばい、どうしよう...
Oh no, what should I do...
気楽にちゃんと覚えてたんだけどな。
I thought I remembered it clearly...
黄色いミッションじゃなくて...ござる先輩が来たところ？
Not the yellow mission... where Gozaru-senpai came from?
そう、ござるが来たところが...えーっとね...
Yeah, where Gozaru came from is... umm, let's see...
あ、ビビちょっと今体力がナイかもです。どこか停まりたいです。
Ah, Vivi might not have stamina right now. I want to land somewhere.
一回そこの納品しましょう。 / はい。
Let's deliver there first. / Okay.
あれ？もしかして... / 止まった！
Huh? Could it be... / It stopped!
よかった、危な。
Thank goodness, that was close.
ミッションがもしかして...
Could the mission be...
回復できそう？ / はい、回復します！ / オッケー。
Can you recover? / Yes, recovering! / Okay.
免疫行って...なんか上に入ってた中が分からなくなっちゃってね。
Went to Immunity... and then lost track of how to get inside from above.
どっかからこう、上にスポッて入る場所があるんだけど...
There's a place where you can pop right in from above, but...
その、上にスポッて入る場所を見失ってしまって...
I lost sight of that spot where you pop in from above...
個別でチームミッションだったよね？ / どうしましょう...
Was it an individual team mission? / What should we do...
あ、なるほど！ポイントが30ポイントってことか！
Ah, I see! The points are 30 points!
チームで30ポイントもらえてるってことか。
So as a team we get 30 points.
同じところ回ってる気がするけど、景色が全然変わらないから覚えられない...
I feel like we're going around the same place, but the scenery doesn't change so I can't memorize it...
ござる画面共有してもらえたら多分行けるかも。一旦ボイチャ2に行こう？
If Gozaru shares her screen we can probably get there. Shall we head to voice chat 2 for now?
オッケー、ちょっと待ってくださいね。ワンチャンここかも。
Okay, wait a moment please. There's a chance it's here.
やばい、またそしてござる先輩を見失ったビビ...
Oh no, and Vivi lost sight of Gozaru-senpai again...
あ、じゃあメディカルブリューあれよね...
Ah, then medical brew is that...
じゃ、ビビさんもちょっと1回下行こう。
Then Vivi-san, let's also go down once.
あ！もう来た！うわ、ここ来たことあるな、しかも！
Ah! Already here! Wow, I've been here before too!
もうダメだ... / ビビ、ボイチャ2に来てほしい。 / はい、行きます！
It's no good... / Vivi, I want you to come to voice chat 2. / Yes, coming!
みんないろいろ大変だー。
Everyone's having a tough time with various things.
イナー！
Ihna!
イナ何してる今？ / 今、何もしてなくて...
Ihna, what are you doing right now? / Right now, I'm not doing anything...
メディカルブリューをつくるやつね。
The one to make medical brew.
トワ様今これミュートか？
Is Towa-sama muted right now?
トワさまー！
Towa-sama!
トワ様が多分...スピーカーもミュートになってるから聞こえないんだよな。
Towa-sama probably... has her speaker muted too, so she can't hear us.
そうよね
Right?
麻酔薬？
Narcotics?
ただね、なんか工業用の…なんかあれがいる、鍋、何だっけ？
Though, you need that... industrial pot, or whatever it was called?
だから、多分麻酔薬いっぱい作っとけば…
So if we just make a bunch of narcotics for now...
麻酔薬いっぱい作っとこ
Let's make a lot of narcotics.
鉄の鍋か？
An iron pot?
工業用…
Industrial...
調理鍋でも行けんの？
Can you use a Cooking Pot too?
えっーと Cooking Potって…なんだろう日本語で
Um... Cooking Pot... what is that in Japanese?
普通の鍋でも作れるけど水筒がいる
You can make it in a normal pot too, but you need a canteen.
あ、水筒バンバンぶち込んで普通の鍋でも作れるらしいよ
Ah, apparently you can stuff it with canteens and make it in a normal pot.
水筒に水入れてそれごと鍋にぶち込む…
Put water in a canteen and throw the whole thing in the pot...
え、そっちの方が楽なんじゃない？っていうか今トワ様が作ってんのかな？
Eh, isn't that easier? Wait, is Towa-sama making it right now?
トワ様がね、今あれなんだよね。スピーカーミュートでこっちの声が多分聞こえてないんだよね。
Towa-sama has her speaker muted right now, so she probably can't hear us.
あ、でも水源はところどころにあのー井戸水じゃないけど設置されてるからそこから引っ張れるから
Ah, but water sources are placed here and there, so we can draw from them.
はい
Okay.
トワ様がどこまでやってるか、なんだよな
I wonder how far Towa-sama has gotten with it...
あ、トワ様作ってんだ。じゃあいいか。
Ah, Towa-sama is making them. Then never mind.
作ってるらしい
Looks like she's making them.
あ、オッケー
Ah, okay.
オッケー。あ、じゃあちょっと下行くか。
Okay. Ah, then shall we head downstairs?
はい
Okay.
イナ、下行こう。チームに。
Ina, let's head downstairs.
お邪魔します
Excuse me~
お邪魔しまーす
Coming in~
はい
Yes.
今手持ち無沙汰です
I have nothing to do right now.
あー！ パイロ今... パイロ行く？
Ah! Want to go to Pyro now?
パイロ行く？ でも私ね
Go to Pyro? But for me...
うん
Yeah.
恐竜が別のになるかな、行けたとしたら
my dino might have to be a different one, if we go.
あーなるほど
Ah, I see.
あ、本当に？
Oh, really?
あの、さっき死んでアレになっちゃったから
Because I died earlier and lost it...
あーそっかそっかそっか
Ah, right right right.
でもみんな持ってるよね、あのクエでもらったさ
But everyone has one, right? The one from that quest...
恐竜使えば多分、盾はできるから
If you use that dino, it can probably tank...
うん、多分いけるはず
Yeah, it should work.
だよね
Right?
うんうん。じゃあパイロ...
Yeah yeah. Then Pyro...
じゃあパイロ行くか
Shall we go to Pyro then?
いけそうだったら
If it seems doable.
うん、じゃあパイロ行こう。え、何がいい？ 何がいいんだろう？
Yeah, let's go to Pyro. Wait, what dino is good? What would be good?
オヴィラプトル？
Oviraptor?
あ、あれじゃない？ イナのテリジノだっけ？
Ah, isn't it Ina's Therizino?
あ、ユーティラじゃないですか？
Ah, isn't it Yuty?
あ、ユーティラかも。イナのユーティラでも戦える
Ah, maybe Yuty. Ina's Yuty can fight too.
イナが引きつけてししろんが乗る感じかな？
Like Ina draws aggro and Shishiron rides it?
オッケー
Okay.
うん
Yeah.
頑張るぞー
I'll do my best~
すみませんおねがいします。ごめんなさい。
Please do, sorry to bother you!
で、乗った後に何か敵倒しに行かないといけないんだよね
And after riding it, we need to go kill some enemies, right?
あ、そうそう。近くのやつを多分殴るのかな？
Ah, right. Probably hit nearby ones?
はいはいはい
Right, right, right.
で、なんかゲージを溜めるらしい。自分もテイムしたことなくて
And then build up a gauge, apparently. I haven't tamed one myself either.
で、ゲージ溜めて、血も吸えるみたいな感じよね
And build the gauge to absorb blood, something like that.
あ、そうそうそうそう
Ah, right right right!
よしよしよしよし。どこ行った？ いたいたいた
Alright, where did it go? There it is!
らしい！
Apparently!
分かった、やってみる
Got it, I'll try it.
行ってみてくれ
Go give it a try.
これで…
With this...
あ、追ってきた
Ah, it's chasing me!
あ、クモ、クモやっちゃいな
Ah, spider! Take out the spider!
クモはたぶん…うん
The spider is probably... yeah.
よいしょ
Up we go!
255やば
Level 255, crazy!
倒せんのかな？
Can we defeat it?
多分行けるはず
Should probably be fine.
ほんだらイナ、ちょっと行ってみるか
Well then Ina, shall we give it a try?
はい
Yes!
いいよー
Okay~
いでっ
Ouch!
頼むー
Please~
やばい、ビビりまくった
Yikes, that scared me!
ちょっと待って、こっち向いて
Wait a second, turn over here.
よしよし、いやー
There, there... oh man.
おりまーす
Stepping down~
やばい、糸まみれすぎてやばい
Yikes, I'm completely covered in webs, this is bad!
うん
Yeah.
あ、しろんとイナ、ボイチャ混んだほうがいいかもしんねぇ。
Ah, Shiron and Ina, maybe you should join voice chat.
うん
Yeah.
やばいー
Oh no~
が、がんばれー
G-Good luck~
イナさん、イナさん
Ina-san, Ina-san!
ビビあんはもう死んでもいい
Vivian can die now.
タンクできるやつだったら何でもええぽい
Anything that can tank seems fine.
じゃあユーティ持って…
Then bring Yuty...
あ、それかテリジノ？
Ah, or Therizino?
あのー、クエでもらってるはずなんだけど
Um, you should have gotten it from the quest...
個人クエでテリジノ貰えるのね
You get Therizino from personal quests.
テリジノだと多分余裕
With Therizino, it's probably easy.
あ、じゃあ私余裕だった、ステ振りして
Ah, then mine was fine after adjusting stats.
ちょっとまた取りに行ってないので多分…
I haven't gone to pick it up yet, so probably...
あ、オッケーオッケー。集会所ね。
Ah, okay okay. At the assembly area.
はい
Yes.
ほんだら、ちょっと待って。私がやれることは…寝袋を近くに置いた方がいいんだよね。
Well then, wait a second. What I should do is... put a sleeping bag nearby, right?
えーっと、アンプ... どこだっけ？
Let's see... Where was it?
ここだったかな？
Was it here?
テリ、テリジノサウルス？
Theri... Therizinosaurus?
かな？
Maybe?
オッケー。
Okay.
テリジノ...
Therizino...
で、
And,
これってマウントも必要...
does this also need a saddle...
テリ... っと。
Theri... there.
え、テリ... T-H...
Uh, Theri... T-H...
テリジノサウルス！
Therizinosaurus!
木材、藁... え、ない？
Wood, thatch... Huh, none?
スミシー。
Smithy.
えー、4個ぐらい作っとこ。
Uh, I'll craft about four of these.
え？
Huh?
で、
And then,
パイロ捕獲した後は、どの道ダンジョン行くのに居た方が良いから欲しいって感じだね。
since we need it for the dungeon anyway after capturing Pyromane, we want it.
木材... 土台か... へー...
Wood... Foundations... Huh...
木材の...
Wooden...
土台。
foundation.
あ、もうあった。オッケー、オッケー、オッケー。
Ah, there it is already. Okay, okay, okay.
藁でもいい。木の土台...
Thatch is fine too. Wooden foundation...
あ、聞いて... ですか？
Ah, can you... hear me?
はい、はい、はい、はい。
Yes, yes, yes, yes.
えーっと...
Let's see...
今テリ持って...
I have Theri now...
何か必要... 必要なことありますか？ 行く前に？
Is there... anything necessary I need to do before going?
えっとね、イナは... イナは生きててくれたらいい。
Well, Ina... Ina just needs to stay alive.
が、頑張ります...
I-I'll do my best...
死ぬのは私だけでいいかな？
I should be the only one dying.
はい。
Okay.
ちょっと待ってね。
Hold on a sec.
お藁。
Thatch.
あ、木材と繊維。
Ah, wood and fiber.
イナちょっと待ってね。
Ina, hold on a sec.
はい。
Okay.
藁の土台でいいか。
Thatch foundation is fine.
じゃあ、ユウティは持って行かなくても良いですよね？
So, I don't need to bring the Yutyrannus, right?
あの、テリがあるから。
Um, because we have the Theri.
そうだね。ま、一応持ってても良いよ。出すのは一匹でいいから。
That's true. Well, you can bring it just in case. We only need to deploy one.
あ、そうですね。オッケーです。
Ah, right. Okay.
今アイテム作ってます。
I'm making the items now.
雪降っていた
It was snowing.
じゃあイナ テレポート はい
"Alright Ina, teleport." "Okay."
で... 火山？
And... the volcano?
えっとね ちょっと待ってね
Um, wait a moment.
乗っててもらって... 違う...
Stay mounted... wait, wrong...
ん〜 ここか
Hmm, is it here?
飛びます
Taking off.
あ、でも、あ、今チャンスだ！雨降ってるから、火が消えてるはず
Ah, but wait, now's our chance! Since it's raining, the fire should be out.
パイロの はい
"The Pyromaniac..." "Yes."
この隙に... じゃあどっか... 近場でもいいかも
While we have this chance... maybe somewhere close by would be fine too.
あ、あっちに1匹... あ！いるいる！あ、これこれ
Ah, there's one over there... Ah! There it is! Ah, this one, this one.
で... た... タンク？ テリジの... テリジのでターゲット
And... ta... tank? Therizino's... take the target with Therizino...
になって うん
"to draw the aggro." "Mm-hmm."
いやー！やめろー！
Eek! Stop it!
行ける？ あ、勝った勝った
"Can you do it?" "Ah, we won, we won!"
戦って！ オッケー
"Keep fighting!" "Okay."
で、ヒットポイントをハーフ... ハーフまで行けば
And if its hit points go down to half...
あ！プテラ逃がしてもいいかも
Ah! We can let Ptera escape too.
ほら！まだ乗れない
Look! Can't mount yet.
あ、テグ...
Ah, Tegu...
きゃー！
Eek!
どこ行った？え？どこ？あれ？あれ、どこ行った？
Where did it go? Huh? Where? Huh? Huh, where did it go?
あれ？あれ？あれ、どこ行った？
Huh? Huh? Huh, where did it go?
あれ？え？消えた？
Huh? What? Did it disappear?
どうした？
What happened?
いや、倒したって出... てないよね？ ないですよね
"Well, it didn't say it was defeated... right?" "Right, it didn't."
あれ、どこ行った？
Huh, where did it go?
き、消えました あれ、消えた？ どこ行った？
"It... it disappeared." "Huh, it disappeared?" "Where did it go?"
あ、自爆したんだ！あ、自爆したんだって！ あー
"Ah, it self-destructed! Ah, it says it self-destructed!" "Ah."
飛んでる、戻って
Tonderu, come back.
じゃあ...
Then...
オッケー、じゃあイナ、テリジの乗ってもらってたら
Okay, then Ina, if you stay mounted on Therizino,
いいかも はい、わかりました
"that might be good." "Yes, got it."
あ、次の... 次のを探して オッケー
"Ah, let's search for the next... next one." "Okay."
ちょっと待ってね、こいつ... ダスキンさん
Wait a moment, this guy... Dasukin-san
着陸してもらわないと。オッケー
Need to make it land. Okay.
あ、あの、で... テラはヘルスでタンク... がいいですね
Ah, um, and... Tera should focus on health for tanking.
あ、イナは乗ったまま攻撃でいいかも はい
"Ah, Ina can just stay mounted and attack." "Okay."
あ、なんかポイントをヘルス... HPに入れたら多分
Ah, if you put the points into health... HP, probably
いい... うん、ハーフHP
good... yeah, half HP.
いるかな？
I wonder if there's any?
レベル低いやつがいいんだよな
A lower level one would be better.
なんか前はいっぱい居ましたけどね
There used to be so many before, though.
あ、雨が...
Ah, the rain...
あ、雨やんじゃったわ いやー
"Ah, the rain stopped." "Oh no..."
じゃあ...
Then...
えっと、シーの方に、海の方？ はい
"Um, towards the sea, ocean side?" "Yes."
2匹連れていこうか
Shall we take two of them?
ちょっと待ってね、ほんだら
Hold on a moment, in that case...
あ、また雨？
Ah, rain again?
火山の方だったら雨降ってるかも
It might be raining near the volcano.
エリア... エリアの境目だね そうですね そうだね
"It's the area... boundary of the area." "That's true." "Yeah."
じゃあ、ちょっとでも施策あるか
Well, do we have any plan?
バイオームで変わるんだね
It changes depending on the biome.
あ、確かにバイオームで変わってるわ。でも水の中でもいいかも
Ah, it really changes by biome. But inside water might work too.
てなると、ちょっとこっち側なんだよな
In that case, it's slightly on this side.
ちょっと待ってね、イナ はい
"Wait a moment, Ina." "Yes."
オッケー
Okay.
こっち... こっちだよ
This way... it's this way.
あー、ちょっとテレポータ行ったん戻ってきてもらっていい？ はい
"Ah, could you head to the teleporter and return for a sec?" "Yes."
と思ったんだけど
I was thinking, though,
あの、ここのバイオームだと雨降ってて
Um, in this biome it's raining,
はい
Yeah,
ここで今やりきっていいかもっていう
so maybe we can finish it off here now.
テレポどこだったっけ？
Where was the teleport again?
えーっと、ここで上ー...
Umm, up above here...
あ、上か。オッケオッケオッケ。気がします。
Ah, up above? Okay okay okay. That's what it feels like.
あ、いるいるいるいるいる。あ。
Ah, it's there! It's there!
いる。
It's there.
その先に
Further ahead.
はい。
Yes.
じゃあ... 行きます！
Alright... here I go!
はい。
Okay.
ぴょんって
It jumped.
あ、なんかいつの...
Ah, when did...
イナ、イナ助けて！後ろに...あ、カマキリがいる！
Ina, Ina help! Behind... ah, there's a mantis!
あー！
Ahhh!
おらー！
Take that!
ごめんね。あ！
Sorry. Ah!
危ない。ちょっと、俺はちょっと逃げます。
Dangerous. I'm going to run away for a bit.
逃げてください！
Please run away!
痛い痛い痛い痛い。おら、おい！
Ouch ouch ouch ouch! Take that, hey!
オッケー。
Okay.
痛い痛い痛い痛い。あー！
Ouch ouch ouch ouch! Ahhh!
重い。
Heavy.
あ、でも私まあ死んでも最悪...
Ah, but even if I die, worst case...
何がこんなに重いんだ。
Why is it so heavy?
イナの方行くね。
I'm heading toward Ina.
はい。
Okay.
いや、ちょっと...
Wait, a bit...
痛い...いやー、ちょっと...
Ouch... wait, a bit...
木か。
Wood, huh.
いや、すぐ行く。すぐ行く。
No, I'm coming right away. I'm coming right away.
すぐ行くんでちょっとお待ちください。
I'm coming right away, so please wait a second.
あーっと...どこだ？
Umm... where is it?
これ雨降ってんのやべえな。
This rain is bad.
低体温になっちゃう。
I'll get hypothermia.
今行けます。
I can go now.
あっちから行った方が早かったか。
Would it have been faster going from over there?
まだ舞える。まだ舞える。
I can still fight. I can still fight.
ボタンとイナ大丈夫か？
Are Botan and Ina okay?
今パイロテイム頑張ってる。
Right now we're trying hard to tame the Pyromane.
オッケー。
Okay.
そっち合流... あ、でも来て... 抜けてほしいかも。
Joining up over there... Ah, but come... I might want you to back out.
オッケーオッケー、分かった。今行くね。
Okay okay, got it. I'm coming now.
はいー。
Okay~
ちょっと遅れますよ。
I'll be a little late.
はいよ。
Alright.
さみー。イナまだいる？
So cold. Ina, are you still there?
はい！同じところです。
Yes! Same place.
はい、戦ってる？
Yes, are you fighting?
戦ってます！
Fighting!
オッケー。乗れそうなら乗る。
Okay. Ride it if you can.
近くに水辺とかあんの？
Is there water nearby?
いや、今雨降ってんの、雨。
No, it's raining right now, rain.
あー、オッケオッケ。
Ah, okay okay.
うん。
Yeah.
そちらどんな感じ？
How are things on your side?
今雨降っててチャンス。
It's raining now, so it's a chance.
あ、確かに！大チャンスじゃん。
Ah, true! That's a huge chance.
大チャンス。イナどこ？
Huge chance. Where are you, Ina?
え、そっち行こうかな、ちょっとじゃあ。
Eh, maybe I'll head over there then.
来てほしい。
I want you to come.
えー、ししろんが死んだところくらい...
Umm, around where Shishiron died...
あ、どの辺？あ、オッケー。
Ah, around where? Ah, okay.
オッケー。
Okay.
え？今まるちの狩りで...
Eh? Right now, with Maru-chi's hunt...
あなげんでもいい... それかラバ...
Doing Anagen is fine too... or Lava...
ゴーレムやりに行くか、ラバゴーレムだっけ？
Go fight the Golem? Was it Lava Golem?
イナの方に行きます。
Heading toward Ina.
あの、まるひの方？まるひの方行こうかなっと。
Um, Maru-hi's side? I was thinking of heading to Maru-hi's side.
とは言えね、ボタンのところ合流しようかなって思って...
Though, I was thinking of joining up where Botan is...
あ、じゃあまるひ行ってきます。
Ah, then I'll head to Maru-hi.
はい。
Okay.
ちな、パイロは今火山に...
By the way, Pyro is at the volcano now...
えーっと、右上だよね、今。
Umm, top right, right now.
うん。
Yeah.
オッケーオッケー。右上行って...
Okay okay. Go top right and...
え、いつ...
Wait, when...
止ま...
Stop...
あ、イナいた！
Ah, Ina's there!
ん？
Hmm?
今それ半分行ったかな？
Did it reach half health now?
分かりません。あ！
I don't know. Ah!
爆発した。
It exploded.
あ、爆発したね。オッケオッケオッケ。
Ah, it exploded. Okay okay okay.
大丈夫大丈夫。
It's okay, it's okay.
なんか固まった、ゲーム。
The game kinda froze.
え、半分にしたらなんか分かるんですか？
Wait, when it gets to half, do you tell somehow?
なんかね、吠える... 1回吠えるらしいよ。ワオーみたいな。
Apparently it roars... it roars once. Like "Waaah".
ふーん。
Hmm.
あ、なんか止まった時乗る感じですか？
Ah, do you mount it when it stops?
フリーズした... そうそうそうそう。
It freezes... Yeah yeah yeah yeah.
あー、なるほど。
Ah, I see.
ヒットポイント半分になると、あの、乗れるんだって。
When its HP drops to half, you can mount it.
あー！
Ah!
で、乗った後にいろいろ...
And after mounting, various...
はいはいはいはい。
Right right right right.
やるみたい。
actions to do.
了解です。
Understood.
うん。
Yeah.
オッケー。
Okay.
そして、もうちょっと上げよう。
And let's raise it a bit more.
はいはいはい。じゃあ次...
Alright alright. Next...
次ー
Next!
次の奴いこう
Let's go get the next one.
はい、行きましょう。
Okay, let's go.
オッケー
Okay.
ただ、望遠... あ、トワ様？
Though, a spyglass... Oh, Towa-sama?
トワ様？
Towa-sama?
あ、聞こえてない
Ah, she can't hear me.
あ、聞こえてないか。
Ah, she can't hear me, huh.
望遠鏡あった方が、まあ分かりやすいらしい
Apparently it's easier to see if you have a spyglass,
ヒットポイントが分かるから。
since you can see their HP.
うん
Yeah.
ま、でも1回やってみよう。
Well, let's give it a try anyway.
はい
Okay.
吼えたら、私にスッと乗ればいいのか？
When it roars, should I just jump right on?
あ、でもその先にいるかも？
Ah, but maybe it's further ahead?
違うか。
Or maybe not.
水晶か。
It's crystal.
望遠鏡覗いて3秒もなかなかシビアな気がするな。
Looking through the spyglass for 3 seconds seems pretty tough.
そうですね。
That's true.
なかなか...
It really is...
どこかなー
Where is it...
どこかなー？居るかなー？
Where could it be? Is it around here?
ちょっと待ってねー
Hold on a second~
PC...
PCっていうか、ゲーム落ちたんで再起動してましたー
Well, not my PC, but the game crashed so I restarted it.
はーい
Okay!
はい、今、探している パイロ...
Yeah, right now we're looking for Pyromane...
雨降ってるとさすがに見づらいな。
It's really hard to see when it's raining.
ここらへんなのね。
It's around here.
なんか青色のパイロとかもいたよね？
There was a blue Pyromane too, right?
あ、いた！結構いろんな色いる。
Ah, yeah! There are lots of different colors.
ね！ 信号機みたいな... 信号機みたいなパイロいた。
Right! Like a traffic light... There was a traffic light-colored one.
確かに。
True.
ね。
Yeah.
かっこいいよ。
It looks cool.
やばい、トワが前回死亡したやつまだついてる。
Oh crap, the marker from where Towa died last time is still showing.
もういいよ、それー！
Get rid of that already!
もうそこから流れが悪いんだよ、もうこのクソクソクソクソクソ...！
The whole run went bad after that! Damn it, damn it all...!
あれ？雨降ってると居ないのかな？
Huh? Maybe they don't spawn in the rain?
てか、夜だから...
Or maybe because it's night...
あー、寝てるんすかね？なんかしゃがんで...
Ah, maybe they're sleeping? Like crouching...
あ、居た居た！
Ah, found it!
あ、どこですか？
Ah, where is it?
えっと、連れて行くわ。
Um, I'll bring it over.
お、これかな？
Oh, is it this one?
あ、いたわ。いたかな？
Ah, there it is. Or was it?
居た？
Is it there?
これだな。居た居た居た。
This is it. Found it!
一匹いたね。緑の綺麗やつが...
There was one. A pretty green one...
あ、じゃあ、そっちでもいいかも。
Ah, then that one might be good too.
テレポッターの近くにいます。
I'm near the teleporter.
あ、オッケー。持っていく。
Ah, okay. I'll bring it.
どれくらいの体力なのか分からないな。
I don't know how much HP it has.
なんか吠えてくれるらしいけどね。
Apparently it roars though.
今吠えた？
Did it just roar?
これだ、待って。
This is it, wait.
今連れて行ってまーす。
Bringing it over now~
行けた、行けた、行けた。
There we go!
はーい。
Okay~
こいつでーす。
Here it is!
お願いします。
Please go ahead.
はい、ラストー。
Okay, last one~
じゃあ、降ります。
Okay, I'll dismount.
今イナの方に行きます。
Now it's heading toward Ina.
吠えたら近づきます。
When it roars, I'll get closer.
え、なんでフレーム吸収するの？どうやってやるんだこれ？
Wait, how do you absorb the flame? How do you do this?
こいつレベル15だったから、めっちゃ弱かったかも。
This one was level 15, so it was super weak.
あー、そっかー！
Ah, I see!
ごめんなさーい！
I'm so sorry~!
レベル低いとクソ弱いから...
When the level is low, it's super weak...
Ctrl + 右クリックなのかな...？
Is it Ctrl + Right Click...?
リセットだ。
It's a reset.
あ、イナ、こいつ頼みます。
Ah, Ina, please handle this one.
あ、これですか？
Ah, this one?
トワのところにもう一匹居るな。
There's another one over where Towa is.
じゃあトワち... さあ...
Then, Towachi... where...
どこにいる？
Where is it?
うちの... やれないかも！ちょうどやっちゃってるわ。
We... might not be able to! We're already killing it.
オッケー。
Okay.
うちのトワ強すぎる。パイロメインちょっと弱いわ。
Our Towa is too strong. The Pyromane is a bit weak.
ちょっとこれいいや、ごめん。
Never mind this one, sorry.
あっちですか？
Over there?
リセットするわ。
I'll reset it.
パイロメイン、しょう...召還
Pyromane, sum... summoning.
あ、オッケー！今近いよ！
Ah, okay! It's close now!
ナイスウォーム。
Nice warm.
近いですよ。
It's close.
あ、居る居る、ここ
Ah, it's here, here!
あ、行きます
Ah, I'm going!
はい、お願いします
Okay, please go ahead.
あいつは... アイスワーム居るのかな？
That one... Is there an Ice Wyrm?
あいつはもう倒している
We've already defeated that one.
あ、20か
Ah, level 20?
弱いか？ 20です、レベル
Is it weak? / It's level 20.
じゃあ、頑張って
Then good luck!
痛い！
Ouch!
ま、まだ乗れない
I-I can't mount it yet.
どうですか？
How is it going?
乗れた！乗れた！ あ、良かった
I mounted it! I mounted it! / Ah, thank goodness.
で？ あ、なんかマンティスが... 居った
And then? / Ah, a Mantis... was there.
で、倒しに行くんだよね？これ、敵を。敵居る？
And then we go kill the enemies, right? Are there enemies?
そうそう、敵倒しに行く
Right, right, we go kill enemies.
居るかな、敵？
Are there any enemies?
あの、ここにマンティスがあったんですけど、殺しました、さっき
Um, there was a Mantis here earlier, but I killed it just now.
あ、いいよいいよ
Ah, that's fine, that's fine.
で、別の... あ、でも、居るわ
And then another... Ah, but there's one!
あ、ダメだ！降りちゃった！あー！
Ah, no! I fell off! Ahhh!
いいな、こっち来れる？敵がいなかったわ
Nice, can you come over here? There were no enemies.
まだ行、行きます！
I'm still go- going!
や、やばい、やばい... ちょっと... やばい
Th-This is bad, bad... Wait... Bad...
あーー！
Aaaah!
固まった！今、スタックした！
It froze! It got stuck just now!
え、2匹...
Eh, two of them...
95か...
Level 95, huh...
熱い！
Hot!
2匹... あ、パイロは燃えないんだ！そうなんだ！
Two of them... Ah, Pyromane doesn't burn! I see!
あ、ちょっと...
Ah, wait...
クールタイムとかあるの？
Is there a cooldown or something?
死ぬ！うわぁ！
I'm gonna die! Uwaah!
ベッド...
Bed...
ベッドから行こうかな
Maybe I'll spawn at the bed.
これはい... レベル90か...
This is... Level 90, huh...
レベル90のそれ、まだ行けるんだったら...
If you can still handle that level 90 one...
大丈夫そう？
Does it look okay?
行けると思います。ちょっとテレポ...
I think I can handle it. A bit of telepo...
もう何でやねん！ついてきた！
Why, seriously?! It followed me!
テレポーターまで行けるかな...
I wonder if I can reach the teleporter...
あれが欲しいな...
I want that one...
いや、乗れるかどうか分かんないな...
Well, I don't know if I can ride it...
騎乗までは行けた？
Did you manage to mount it?
行けた！騎乗までは行けたんだけど、敵がいなくて... なんか時間切れで倒せなかった...
I did! I got up to mounting it, but there were no enemies... so time ran out and I couldn't beat it...
あー、なるほど。近くにか
Ah, I see. Near here?
そうそうそう。なんかここに敵もあるし、レベル90なんですけど...
Right, right. There are enemies here too, and it's level 90, but...
肉が欲しいな...
I want some meat...
皮これ貰っておこう
Let me get this hide.
バック
Back.
バックアタック
Back attack.
いや、分かんない
No, I don't know.
条件揃えば行けそうなんだけどね
It seems doable if conditions are met, though.
あれだね、アルゲンでなんか弱い敵を掴んで待機させておくっていう方法もあるらしい
Apparently there's a method where you grab a weak enemy with an Argentavis and keep them standby.
横取り用で
For stealing...
ここ来れますか？
Can you come here?
素材がないな...
I don't have materials...
てか雨終わっちゃったのか？見る？
Wait, did the rain stop? Shall we look?
雨やってるの？ まだ降ってると思う
Is it still raining? / I think it's still raining.
あ、乗れない
Ah, can't ride.
あ、今行ける！行ける！
Ah, I can go now! I can go!
行けるか？ やばすぎ！
Can you? / Too dangerous!
行けない！行けない！
I can't! I can't!
何でやねん！
Why, seriously?!
え、逃げた？
Eh? Did it run away?
とりあえず...
For now...
そっちにまた戻ります
I'm going back over there.
あ、出来た！乗れた！乗れた！
Ah, I did it! I mounted it! I mounted it!
で、敵を倒しに行って、燃やした時にコントロールと右クリックで炎を吸っていくみたいな...
So, go defeat enemies, and when burning them, suck up the flames with Ctrl + Right Click...
え、でも、なんか... 敵がもうない...
Eh, but... there are no more enemies...
あ、お肉
Ah, meat.
敵どこ？どこ行った、敵？
Where are the enemies? Where did they go?
そう、敵の数が少ないんだよね、そこ
Yeah, the number of enemies is low around there.
虫とかいないか...
No bugs or anything...
うわぁ、もう時間がない！
Uwah, no more time!
時間切れだ...
Time ran out...
雨夜だとアレなのかな？敵少ないのかな？
Maybe because it's a rainy night? Are there fewer enemies?
いや、雨のせいではないと思うんですけど、ちょっと...
No, I don't think it's because of the rain, but...
なんかね、敵があんまりなくて...
Yeah, there just aren't many enemies...
倒せなかったんだよね
Couldn't kill them, right?
アルゲンでじゃあ敵捕まえて持ってった方がいいか...
Maybe it's better to catch enemies with an Argentavis and bring them over...
敵の湧きが厳しかったね
Enemy spawning was tough.
粉茶アルゲンを...
Konacha's Argentavis...
ちょっとお借りしようかな、アルゲンを
Maybe I'll borrow the Argentavis for a bit.
There was a Wyrm, but I can't find it now.
初めてだから難しいね
It's hard since it's my first time.
平気？
Are you okay?
あ、えっと、あ、このアルゲン サドルがないのか。
Ah, um... ah, this Argen doesn't have a saddle.
あ、ワイバーンでも掴める？ ホロジャワイバーンで行ってみるか。
Ah, can a Wyvern pick it up? Should we try going with a Wyvern?
俺の死体...
My corpse...
あ、イナ、後ろ！ バック、バック！
Ah, Ina, behind you! Back, back!
敵が、あー！
An enemy, ah!
うわー！
Whoa!
危険！
Watch out!
痛い痛い痛い！
Ow, ow, ow!
あ、そいつ乗れたらラッキーだな、でも。
Oh, it'd be lucky if you could mount that one, though.
あ、3分... 3分半です。
Ah, 3 minutes... 3 and a half minutes left.
やばいやばいやばい！
Oh no, oh no, oh no!
いけるか？
Can you make it?
逃げてください！
Please run!
俺はいける！
I can make it!
ここでちょっと参加しますので...
I'll join in a bit here...
いや、これ雨... 雨降ってる。
Wait, the rain... it's raining.
え、そこ雨降ってる？ 火消えてる？
Huh, is it raining there? Is the fire put out?
いや、火...
No, the fire...
雨降ってるんですけど、火が...
It's raining, but the fire is...
え、なんか火着いてるよね？
Huh? It's on fire, right?
ですよね。
Right?
いやあー！
Nooo!
あ、間違った。えっと、どうやって掴むんだ？
Ah, I made a mistake. Um, how do I grab it?
あっちい！
Hot!
あ、もうちょい上の方じゃない？
Ah, isn't it a bit higher up?
あっちい！ え！
Hot! Huh?!
てりー死ぬかも！
Terry might die!
いや、やばい、やばいやばい。大丈夫？
Oh no, this is bad, this is real bad. Are you okay?
なんか火...
The fire...
あっちい！
So hot!
あー！ 敵は近くにいるんだけど、敵は浮いてはいるんだけど、無理かも！
Ahhh! The enemy is close, and it is floating, but this might be impossible!
ですよね！ 乗れない？
Right?! You can't mount it?
待って、乗れ... 今乗れないんです、クールダウンで... あー！ てりー！
Wait, mount... I can't mount right now because of the cooldown... Ahhh! Terry!
あたしも死ぬかもー！
I might die too!
あー！ てりじのー！ てりー！
Ahhh! Therizino! Terry!
てりじのー！
Therizino!
いや、死ぬ、死ぬ、死ぬ！
No, I'm gonna die, die, die!
どこ行った？
Where did it go?
ちょっと待って、吹っ飛んだ！ すごい...
Wait a second, it blew away! That's insane...
うわー！ 助けて！
Woah! Help me!
ここにいるけど...
I'm right here, but...
ここに向かってはいるんだけど...
I'm heading towards here, but...
うわ！
Whoa!
あつ、あつあつあつあつ！
Hot, hot hot hot hot!
え、雨降ってるのにそれ火消えてなくない？
Huh? Even though it's raining, isn't that fire not going out?
消えてないんだよ。
It's not going out!
なんでだー？
Why is that?!
なんでなんだって！
I'm asking why!
これ今雨降ってるよね？
It's currently raining, right?
うん、雨降ってるだね。
Yeah, it is raining.
やばいやばいやばい、ワイバーン君！ ワイバーン君！
Oh no, oh no, oh no! Wyvern-kun! Wyvern-kun!
オキオキ？
Oki-oki?
あーやばいよー
Ah, this is bad!
私の荷物どこだろう？
Where is my inventory?
Ah, was fall damage probably, yeah.
乗りたいのに乗れないんですけれど、ワイバーン！
I want to mount it, but I can't! Wyvern!
カモン！
Come on!
ワイバーン！
Wyvern!
あ、なんか誰かの... 誰かのライトニングワイバーンがいる、ここに。
Oh, someone's... someone's Lightning Wyvern is here.
これ、トワトワの？
Is this Towa-Towa's?
あー！
Ah!
呼んでる？ 呼んでなくない？
Are you calling it? Doesn't seem like you are?
あ、騎乗したと燃えてるんだ。へー。
Ah, it catches fire when you ride it. Huh.
あ、でも多分... うん。
Ah, but probably... yeah.
多分、距離最短にしてないから、めっちゃ遠くに行かないと来ないかも。
Since the follow distance isn't set to lowest, it might not come unless you go really far.
あ、そういうこと？
Ah, is that how it is?
そういうこと。
That's how it is.
距離最短ってなんかあったっけ？
Was there a lowest follow distance setting?
あったあった。居るの居るが... うん。
There was, there was. It's there, but... yeah.
ごめん、今ちょっとトラブルってて対応できないっす、あけろです、すまん！
Sorry, I'm having trouble right now and can't respond! Sorry!
よいしょ。
Up we go.
私の荷物...
My stuff...
いっか。
Whatever.
マップに出てるか... いや、イナごめんね！
Is it on the map...? Ah, Ina, I'm sorry!
いえいえいえ！
No, not at all!
あー、敵があったら...
Ah, if there's an enemy...
いけるか？
Can you make it?
こいつを着陸させなきゃいけなくて、えーっと...
I need to make this guy land, um...
着陸...
Landing...
着陸... 一旦追従解除でも...
Landing... Maybe stop following for now...
あ、来たかな？
Ah, did it come?
着陸してー！
Please land!
待ってよ...
Wait a sec...
どこ、ここ？ 停止...
Where, here? Stop...
やばい、やばいやばいやばい。俺あとヒットポイント... 113。
Oh no, oh no no no. My HP is down to... 113.
あー...
Ah...
居った。
Found it.
着陸してくれないね。
It won't land for us, huh.
うん、着陸してくれないんだよな。
Yeah, it really won't land.
ちょっと待ってね、一旦... 一旦はおいで。
Wait a moment, come here for a sec.
広い所に...
To an open area...
むずいなー。
This is tough.
荷物どこ...
Where's my stuff...
これで岩の上から乗れない？ トワ様。
Can't you mount it from on top of the rock like this, Towa-sama?
ジャンプで... オッケー、ちょっと待ってね。
By jumping... Okay, wait a second.
あ、危ないかも。
Ah, it might be dangerous.
あ、イナの恐竜が...
Ah, Ina's dinosaur...
てりじのが...
Therizino is...
いやば、無理っす、無理そう。バサバサしてる。
Man, no way, seems impossible. It's flapping around.
ごめんね、アナ
Sorry, Ana.
イナ、テリジノのさ…
Ina, about the Therizino's...
サドル？ / あ、そうですね。
Saddle? / Ah, that's right.
オッケー、オッケー。
Okay, okay.
お、いけるいける。よいしょ、はい。
Oh, we can make it. Here we go.
うわ、ナイス！ / はいはい。
Woah, nice! / Yep, yep.
はいよー。
Here you go.
マジありがとう！マジありがとう！
Thank you so much! Thank you so much!
すみません。
Sorry about that.
オッケー。
Okay.
ありがてぇ。
I'm so grateful.
ライトニングワイバーン。
Lightning Wyvern.
トワ様がいる。
Towa-sama is here.
お世話になりました。
Thank you for your help.
戻ってきた！ / あ、かわいい！
You're back! / Ah, so cute!
今、テリジノサドル取れた？
Did you manage to get the Therizino saddle?
テリジノサドル取れた？イナ。 / あ、取れました。
Did you get the Therizino saddle, Ina? / Ah, I got it.
これこれ。
This one, this one.
あ、ありがとう！ / そうそう。
Ah, thank you! / Yeah, yeah.
雨が止んじまったんだなー。
Ah, the rain stopped.
あー、じゃあ水辺だね。
Ah, then we need to go near the water.
そうだね、水辺連れてくるほうがいいかもね。
Yeah, it might be better to bring it near the water.
ワイバーンどこ行った？
Where did the Wyvern go?
あ、これ取れたわ。なにこれ？
Ah, I got this. What's this?
僕のワイバーン君どこ行ったんだろう？
Where did my Wyvern-kun go?
いやー、パイロきついかな〜。
Man, is Pyromane gonna be tough?
難しいねー。
It's difficult, isn't it?
ねー！
Yeah!
そう、近くに餌がいなかったんだよね。
Yeah, there was no prey nearby.
あ、でもなんか音は雨か… 雨じゃないかな？
Ah, but is that sound rain? Isn't it rain?
なるほど。
I see.
あ、雨降ってます！
Ah, it's raining!
あ、じゃあプテラ迎えに行きます。
Ah, then I'll go pick up Ptera.
こちらの樽に入れていただければ… ああ！
If you could put it in this barrel... Ah!
了解！
Got it!
あれ、雨降ってきた？ / うん。
Huh, did it start raining? / Yeah.
あ、ラッキー！雨降ってます。
Ah, lucky! It's raining.
ここのパイロ、敵…
The Pyromane here is hostile...
いっぱいいる？
Are there lots of them?
待って待って、どこだどこだ？
Wait, wait, where are they?
えっと、待って。イナどこどこ？
Um, wait. Where's Ina?
ちょっと下。 / ちょっと下。
A bit lower down. / A bit lower down.
俺のワイバーン君… じゃねえわ。プテラ君。
My Wyvern-kun... wait, no. Ptera-kun.
あれ、ここじゃないもしや？
Huh, is it not here by any chance?
パイロのあのテイムのマークが多分見える…
That Pyromane taming mark can probably be seen...
あ、なんか0% 0%って。
Ah, it says 0% 0%.
あー、そこか！
Ah, over there!
こっちか。
This way?
そうだね。
That's right.
ここです、ここ下。
It's here, down here.
あ、これか！
Ah, this one!
こいつとこいつ。
This one and this one.
あれか、あれか？
Is it that one, or that one?
なんかこれが0%… / はい。
Somehow this one is 0%... / Yes.
あ、オッケーオッケーこいつか！
Ah, okay okay, it's this one!
こいつをじゃあ、今消えてるから…
So for this one, since it's invisible right now...
あ、途中までこれ… うわー！
Ah, halfway through this... Woah!
これ体力どれぐらいなんだ？
How much health does this have?
なんか0%になったやつはまた乗れるんですかね？
Can we mount the ones that reached 0% again?
乗れるかな？これどう？
Can we mount it? How is it?
あ、もうちょい…今乗れる！今乗れる！
Ah, a bit more... You can mount it now! You can mount it now!
あ、乗れた乗れた！行ける。
Ah, got on, got on! Good to go.
で、敵を倒しに行く。
And then go defeat the enemy.
で、火をあれ吸える？
And can you absorb the fire?
え？いや、痛痛痛痛！
Eh? No, ow ow ow ow!
体は燃えないんじゃないかな？
Wouldn't its body not burn?
落ちたー！
I fell off!
乗れたですか？落ちたー！
You mounted it, but fell off~!
落ちちゃったー！
I fell off~!
落ちちゃった… ちょっとこっちが体力やばいかも。
Fell off... My health might be in trouble over here.
す、すいません！
S-Sorry!
やばい、なんか、うわーこれ！
Oh no, something... Woah, this!
ライトニングワイバーン君がやばいかも。
Lightning Wyvern-kun might be in trouble.
あ、怖！なんか引っかかってた。
Ah, scary! It was stuck.
大丈夫か？ / 大丈夫ー！
Are you okay? / I'm okay~!
ライトニングワイバーン君が死… 死んでしまう。
Lightning Wyvern-kun is gonna... die.
今釣ってる。
Now I'm drawing its attention.
1匹釣ったよ。
I lured one!
ハードだぜ…
This is tough...
ハード… 難しっ。
Tough... So hard.
難しいねー！
It really is hard~!
でも捕まえられたら…
But if we can catch it...
ハッピーだから！ / そうよー！
We'll be happy! / That's right~!
ハッピーのために頑張るんだ！
Work hard for happiness!
ハッピーダッピー！うわー！
Happy dappy! Woah~!
よいしょ。ワイバーン君の体力もう…
Alright. My Wyvern-kun's health is already...
こいつか？いけるか？
This one? Can we do it?
オッケー。
Okay.
1匹まだ引き連れたまんまのやつをあれにしたけど…
I handled the one that was still following, but...
イナが来れるか？
Can Ina make it over here?
あ、行きますか？
Ah, shall we go?
危ねえ！
Dangerous!
ちょっとすいません 回復させて
Excuse me a moment, let me heal.
敵を燃やして それ吸うといいらしいよ
Apparently burning enemies and absorbing that is good.
よいしょ
Up we go.
インベントリからゲットして...
Get it from the inventory...
大丈夫ですか？トワ様
Are you okay, Towa-sama?
大丈夫
I'm fine.
いけそう？ 敵連れてった方がいい？ なんか雑魚
Can you make it? Should I bring some enemies over? Like small ones.
ちょっとこいつで行くか... なんか居るかな
Guess I'll go with this one... Is something there?
え？これ死んだ？
Eh? Did this die?
うわ、死んだわ！ うわあ！
Whoa, it died! Whoa!
いや、ちょっと待って...
Wait, hold on...
ん？ 死んじゃった？
Hmm? Did it die?
うん... ちょっと敵が多すぎたな
Yeah... There were too many enemies.
周りの？
The surrounding ones?
うん、周りの敵が多すぎて死んだな
Yeah, there were too many surrounding enemies so it died.
この辺にもう一匹居る
There's another one around here.
あ、よいしょ
Ah, up we go.
乗れそうなら乗るか
Shall we ride if we can?
いける？ 25だ、これちょっとガチ弱いわ
Can you? It's level 25, this one is seriously weak.
あ、でも乗れそうなら
Ah, but if we can ride it...
あ、これは超弱い 弱いか
Ah, this is super weak. Is it weak?
ちょっと強めなやつ？
A slightly stronger one?
ま、最低90は欲しいかなとは思うけどな
Well, I think I want at least level 90 though.
もう一匹居る 結構湧きは早いのかな
There's another one. Does it spawn pretty fast?
なんか湧きは早いよね
Spawning seems fast, right?
お、85？
Oh, 85?
弱っ！
So weak!
あらららら 待って
Oh dear, wait.
ワイバーン強くしたから もしかして強い？
Since I powered up the Wyvern, is it strong maybe?
やべっ トワの体力が無い！ バカバカバカ！
Shoot, Towa's health is low! Idiot idiot!
強そうなのが居るかな...
Is there a strong-looking one...?
あ、こっち行ったら虫がちょっと居るか
Ah, if we go this way, are there some bugs?
ちょっとワイバーン強すぎてこれ無理だこれ
The Wyvern is way too strong, this is impossible.
あ、もう一匹居るよ！ 怖っ！ こいつ！
Ah, there's another one over there! Yikes! This guy!
こいつこいつ！ でも炎消えてない？
This guy! But hasn't the fire gone out?
あ、まだライティングのクールダウンが...
Ah, the lightning cooldown is still...
あー クールダウン中かな、今
Ah, is it on cooldown right now?
もうすぐかな？
Almost done?
あ、消えてる消えてる
Ah, it's gone, it's gone.
乗れない、こいつ？
Can't we ride this guy?
入ろ
Let's go in.
あ、熱っ！
Ah, hot!
3秒らしいからな...
Appears to be 3 seconds...
火消えるのか
Does the fire go out?
あ、でも火、まだあいつ火ついてるかも
Ah, but that guy might still be on fire.
火ついてるね！ 熱っ熱っ！
It's on fire! Hot, hot!
あ、雨が...
Ah, the rain...
雨が！
The rain!
熱い！
Hot!
雨が止まった...
The rain stopped...
ダメ、止まっちゃったか
No, did it stop?
あんまり雨やんじゃった...
The rain stopped completely...
もう一回降ってくれ！
Rain one more time!
頼むー！ 頼むー！
Please! Please!
あいた、トワ様来れるかお前
Ouch, Towa-sama, can you come over?
あ、来た来た来た
Ah, here it comes, here it comes.
やっぱ海辺の方のほうがいいかな？
Is the seaside better after all?
海辺のほうがいいかもね
Seaside might be better.
海辺に行こう、海辺に
Let's go to the seaside, seaside.
あ、そう
Ah, okay.
ちょうど雨降ってたから そこでやってたけど
Rain was falling just then, so I was doing it there, but...
海辺に行きやす！ 惜しい
Heading to the seaside! So close.
惜しいね！ 惜しい！
So close! So close!
初挑戦だから 結構大変だね
It's our first try, so it's quite tough, huh.
よしよし
All right, all right.
なんか服ねえかな...
Wonder if there are any clothes...
あ、トワキー
Ah, Towaki.
よし
Alright.
よしよし、待ってるでポータルのとこに
Alright, I'm waiting at the portal.
お疲れ様ですー あ、マジ？
Good job~ Ah, really?
お疲れ様ー
Good job~
個人ミッション終わりました！ イエーイ！
Finished my solo mission! Yay!
で、これって終わったら何貰えるんですか？
And what do you get when you finish this?
個人ミッションは... えーっと何だったっけかな...
Solo mission is... um, what was it again...
拳で収穫...
Harvesting with fists...
個人ミッションの報酬が... 何をやった？
The reward for the solo mission is... what did you do?
あ、えっと個人ミッションで クレートまで全部達成して ミッション全部成功しました
Ah, um, for the solo mission, I reached up to the crate and succeeded in all missions.
で、えっと今やったミッションは何やったんだい？
And, um, what was the mission you just did?
今やったミッション？ えーっと...
The mission I just did? Um...
個人で、個人ミッション... クレートだけ？
Solo... solo mission... Just the crate?
クレートやりました！ 全て達成になりました！
Did the crate! Everything is completed now!
あ、今さっきやったやつ！ 今さっきやったやつ！
Ah, the one you just did! The one you just did!
今... 今さっき... え、今さっき
Just... Just now... Um, what we just...
やったのは... ん？なんだ？
...did just now... Huh? What was it?
クレート？ 何？
Crates? What?
クレートだけ？
Just crates?
え、クレートと、あと交配... 交配しました、交配。
Um, crates, and also breeding... We did breeding.
なら集会所のあれからオビラプトルとテリジノサウルスがもらえるはず。
Then you should be able to get an Oviraptor and Therizinosaurus from the gathering hall.
オビラプトルとテリジノサウルス、はい。
An Oviraptor and Therizinosaurus, okay.
あ、そう。集会所のところから貰えるはず。そこは自分で取りに行かなきゃいけない。
Ah, right. You should be able to get them at the gathering hall. But you have to go pick them up yourself.
あ、はい。分かりました。ありがとうございます！
Ah, okay. Got it. Thank you so much!
はーい。
Sure thing!
死んだところのあれ取って来るわ。
I'll go retrieve my stuff from where I died.
はーい。
Okay!
ワンチャンここで雨もう一回振んないかなーって待ってみる。
I'll wait and see if maybe it'll rain here again.
雨待ち？
Waiting for rain?
来るでしょ。さっき連続で来てたもん。
It will come. It kept coming repeatedly earlier.
3回目はないやろって...
There's no way there'll be a third time...
絶対海に行った方がいいて！
Going to the ocean is definitely better, I tell you!
海の方が早そう...
The ocean seems faster...
絶対海が早いて！
The ocean is definitely faster, I tell you!
じゃあ海行くー。
Then I'm going to the ocean.
雨乞いソングじゃなくて... 雨乞いソングで...
Not a rain dance song... but with a rain dance song...
よいしょ。
Up we go.
あ、でもパイロ... あ、そうか。パイロ、その辺に私の死体があるんだよね。
Ah, but Pyro... Ah, right. Pyro, my body is around there.
雨よ〜 雨よ〜
Rain come~ Rain come~
降れ〜 降れ〜
Fall down~ Fall down~
いや、移動してるからね、でも。
Well, I'm moving though.
こっちだ。
This way.
よーし。
Alright.
私の死体が... これ、何になってんだこれ？
My body... What status is this right now?
すごい視界がドクドクしてるのは何でだ？
Why is my vision pulsing so heavily?
どこだ？死ぬのか？
Where is it? Am I dying?
水辺って... 水辺っていうかどこら辺だ？
Waterfront... Wait, where around is the waterfront?
海です、海。
It's the ocean, the ocean.
上？下？マップで。
Top? Bottom? On the map.
ど... 上かな？
Um... Top, maybe?
ヒナが向かってる... ヒナについて行けばいいのかな、じゃあ。
Hina is heading... Should I just follow Hina then?
どこだ？
Where is it?
多分ここ...
Probably here...
じゃないかなー？
Isn't it over here?
あ、こっち側ね。
Ah, this side.
今なんかマップで... 轟先輩のマーク...
Right now on the map... Todoroki-senpai's mark...
あ、自分は今拠点に戻ってる。
Ah, I'm back at the base right now.
あ、これごめんごめん！これ拠点に戻ってるから...
Ah, sorry about that! That's because I returned to base...
あ、でもここにパイロ... 1匹見つけました。
Ah, but here's a Pyro... I found one here.
だよね。海にまで連れて行かなきゃいけないんだよね。
Right. You have to lure it all the way to the ocean.
水... 火を消すやつ。 / はい。
Water... The thing to extinguish the fire. / Yes.
あー、どこだ？落ちます？それとも...
Ah, where is it? Did it fall? Or...
ここで一旦待ちかな？ / はい。
Should we wait here for a moment? / Yes.
何だこれ？
What is this?
近くの安全な場所で待ちます。 / 視界が眩しいからな... あ、暑い！暑い！
We'll wait nearby in a safe spot. / My vision is so bright... Ah, so hot! Hot!
あ、パイロいるね。
Ah, there's a Pyro.
そう、そのパイロを海辺に連れて行かなきゃいけない。
Yeah, we have to lure that Pyro to the ocean shore.
目がおかしいのか？
Is something wrong with my eyes?
それね、なんかね、熱中症っぽいんだよね。
That, you know, looks like heatstroke.
これね... 自分もちょっとぼやぼやすぎて、画面気持ち悪いと思って戻ってきたんだけど。
Yeah... My vision was getting way too blurry and nauseous, so I came back.
これ水に入ったら大丈夫なのかな？
Will this be fine if I get into the water?
そうそう、水にしばらく浸かってたらいいんだって。
Yeah, staying submerged in water for a bit fixes it.
オッケー。
Okay.
火山はギリース... パイロは別にギリースーツなくても... ギリースーツ要るのかな？
Volcano needs ghillie... Pyro doesn't really need a ghillie suit... Do we need one?
荷物ねえかも...
I might not have my items...
くっ...
Ugh...
死んだところにないかい？
Is it not where you died?
うーん、ない。あのね、空中死んだんだよね。
Hmm, no. You see, I died in mid-air.
あ、多分その下にないかな？空中で死んだらその真下に落ちると思うんだけど。
Ah, isn't it right below that? If you die in mid-air, it should fall directly under.
真下かな...
Directly below, maybe...
カバンらしいものが... / あ、オッケー。
Something that looks like a bag... / Ah, okay.
何一つないかも。
There might be nothing at all.
熱中症、回避してください。
Please avoid heatstroke.
ワンチャン岩の間だな。
There's a chance it's between the rocks.
ケーナの？
The Pteranodon's?
お、ヒナ気をつけてね。
Oh, Hina, be careful.
お水の中にしばらく居たら...
If you stay in the water for a bit...
えーっと... オッケー。
Let's see... Okay.
火山行くか。 / 暑い！
Shall we head to the volcano? / So hot!
なんだこいつマジで。しかも体マジで重いし。
What is with this guy seriously? And my body feels so heavy.
ヒナのところに行くかな？ヒナがどこだ？
Should I go to Hina's location? Where is Hina?
海のところ？ヒナ。
By the ocean, Hina?
海です。
Yes, at the ocean.
オッケー。
Okay.
え、なんかめちゃ... めちゃくちゃ...
Huh, it's super... extremely...
多分こっちかな？
Probably this way?
なんか映んないんだよな。何で？
For some reason it's not showing up. Why?
いや、ないなー。なんで映んないんだろう。
Nah, it's not here. I wonder why it's not showing up.
うん。
Yeah.
ない気がする。
I feel like it's not here.
ここなんだよな。
It should be right here.
こっちに居るのかな、ヒナが。
I wonder if Hina is over here.
えっと、今 17.1 と... 64.7。
Um, right now 17.1 and... 64.7.
あれか？これ敵だよな。
Is that it? That's an enemy, right?
あ、ありがとう。あ、あそこだ。ヘビです。
Ah, thank you. Ah, over there. It's a snake.
いや、ないわ。まあいいや。どうせしょぼいもんしかねえ。
Nah, it's not there. Oh well. It's probably just lousy loot anyway.
あ、あ、ここか。なんか、ん？あれは誰かが乗っておられるニグワイバーン？
Ah, here? Wait, huh? Is someone riding that Pyromane?
あ、トワさんも... あ、これトワか！
Ah, Towa-san is also... Ah, is this Towa?
トワさん、それ何...いけそう？
Towa-san, how's that... does it look doable?
ちょっとやってみる、かな。 / うん。
I'm gonna try it out, maybe. / Yeah.
何レベルだ？これ。
What level is this?
それをね、この水の中に連れてきてほしいんだよね。 / うん。
I need you to lure it into the water over here. / Okay.
今そっち行きます。
I'm heading over to you now.
どこ？あれ、どこ行った？あ、戻りました。たぶん。
Where's it? Huh, where'd it go? Ah, it came back. Probably.
こっちを...えーっと、どこだ？ / イナちゃん、連れて来れる？ワイバーンだとちょっと...
Over here... um, where is it? / Ina-chan, can you bring it over? On a wyvern, it's a bit...
あ、連れて...こいつか？こいつかな？
Ah, luring it... is it this one? Maybe this one?
小回りがきかないんだよな。 / こいつだわ。こいつだわ。
It can't make sharp turns. / It's this one. It's this one.
あ、それだそれだ。 / あーはいはいはい。
Ah, that's it, that's it. / Ah, gotcha, gotcha.
いってー！あ、これはもしや木に引っかかっちゃってる。
Ouch! Ah, is it stuck in the tree by any chance?
あ、出ました出ました。行けそう行けそう。 / 来た来た来た。
Ah, it's out, it's out. Looks doable! / Here it comes, here it comes!
テレポータ―どこだー？
Where's the teleporter?
あ、こっちに。
Ah, this way.
一旦休憩... / あ、入った入った入った！入ったよ！
Taking a quick rest... / Ah, it went in! It went in!
これでどうだ？ / 入った！
How's this? / It's in!
あ、いけそう。 / どうだどうだ？
Ah, looks doable. / How is it? How is it?
うわー！ / はぁ...無理だ。
Whoa! / *Sigh* No way...
なんか、ちょっと待って！ここ...どーにかなった、今。
Wait a second! I made it out somehow just now.
カマキリが...あ、飛んでる。飛んでる、戻ってる。
The mantis is... Ah, it's flying! It's flying back!
なんか飛んでったで！ / テレポーター、迷子...あれか。
It flew off! / Teleporter, lost... is it that one?
これでどうだどうだ？乗れるか？
How's this now? Can you ride it?
なんか私狙われてますけど...乗れるかな？
It feels like it's targeting me though... Can I mount it?
乗れたらいいけど、ここに死ぬのは嫌だ！
It'd be great if I could mount it, but I don't wanna die here!
こっちこっちこっちこっちこっち！
Over here, over here, over here!
迷子です。どこだっけ？テレポーター。
I'm lost. Where was it again? The teleporter.
飛んでるカマキリが...この辺だった気がするんだよな。 / カマキリ、ナイス！
The flying mantis is... I feel like it was around here. / Mantis, nice!
よいしょ。オッケオッケオッケ！オッケオッケオッケ！
Yoisho. Okay, okay, okay! Okay, okay, okay!
岸まで... / 上から見るか。結構高い位置だったよね。
To the shore... / Should I check from above? It was pretty high up, right?
よいしょ。あー、引っかかったてる！引っかかってる！
Yoisho. Ah, it's stuck! It's stuck!
やばいかも。おっ、なー！ごめん。
This might be bad. Woah, nooo! Sorry.
パイロメインになんか引っかかってる！あ、出れた出れた。
It's stuck on the Pyromane! Ah, it got out, it got out.
ごめん。 / 乗れる、乗れる。 / あ、266... / やっちゃったよ、これ。乗れる。
Sorry! / I can mount it. / Ah, 266... / Oh no, I did it. I can mount it.
まだ生きてる、まだ！あ、まだ生きてる！
It's still alive, still! Ah, it's still alive!
なんでカマキリが近くにいるの？
Why are there mantises nearby?
うわー！ / これ乗れるか乗れないか？
Woah! / Can you mount it or not?
2662だったら... / これ...今無理か、イナ。
If it's 2662... / Is it impossible right now, Ina?
むー！ワイバーン！ / また、また火が... / あ、オッケーオッケー。火、火、火。
Ugh! Wyvern! / Fire again... / Ah, okay okay. Fire, fire, fire.
こっちね。こっちに来てほしい。 / この辺だな。
This way. I want it to come over here. / Around here then.
やばい。ってか死ぬ、ワイバーン死ぬ。無理だ、これ。カマキリが...
Oh crap. I mean, my wyvern's gonna die. This is impossible. The mantises are...
カマキリがえぐいよね。 / ここ数えぐーい！
The mantises are brutal, aren't they? / The numbers here are insane!
ちょっとカマキリの処理してもらった方がいいかな？
Maybe we should get someone to deal with the mantises first?
オッケー。 / これ乗れるのかな？
Okay. / Wonder if you can mount it?
あ、待って。これ、お前こっちこっちこっち、来い来い。
Ah, wait. Hey, you, over here, over here! Come here!
みんなどこにいる？
Where is everyone?
あーやばっ、これ。うっす...いやでも今、今なら上...今乗れ...
Ah crap. Woah... but wait, now, right now... mount it now...
いや、騎乗ができないよ、そもそも！うーん。
No, I can't even mount it in the first place! Ugh.
乗れなかったー！ / まだですかね？
Couldn't mount it! / Is it not time yet?
まだだったのかな？ごめん、自分のプテラ呼べるかな、イナ。
Was it not ready yet? Sorry, can I recall my Pteranodon, Ina?
あ、はい！ / 海の...こっちから。
Ah, yes! / From the sea... over here.
騎乗がなかったなー。50%削れてなかったぽい、HP。
There was no mount prompt. Looks like its HP wasn't reduced by 50% yet.
あー、なるほどね。 / そうそうそう。だからもうちょっと攻撃必要だったかも。
Ah, I see. / Yeah yeah yeah. So maybe we needed to attack it a bit more.
およー。ほほー。
Oyoh. Hoho.
この辺か？ / ちょっと一旦、ワイバーンちょっと浮いてくるわ。
Around here? / I'm gonna fly up on the wyvern for a second.
はい、あーよ。あーよ。
Okay, sure thing. Sure thing.
体力は...危ない危ない危ない！はまってる！
Its HP is... Woah, danger danger! It's stuck!
一旦、肉を... / キモすぎる、キモすぎる！もうここキモすぎる！
For now, the meat... / This is so gross, so gross! This place is way too gross!
火山北だっけ？お亡くなりになってるヤツがいる。
Is it north of the volcano? There's one that died.
ここ、どんだけ大変なんだよ！
How ridiculously tough is this place?!
おかしくなっちまうよ、バカタレがー！
I'm gonna go crazy, you dummies!
入れるか？入れた。
Can I get in? Got in.
いや、まだ... / ちょっと肉もらいます。
Nah, not yet... / I'll take some meat.
なんかレベル見るやつなかったっけ？体力見るやつなかったっけ？望遠鏡...
Wasn't there an item to check levels? Or to check HP? A spyglass...
望遠鏡あったかな？
Did we have a spyglass?
でもなんか、敵にマウスカーソル当てるとヒットポイントはなんか結構見えたりはするん...
But you know, if you hover your mouse cursor over an enemy, you can usually see its hit points...
だけどね
But, you know...
本当？
Really?
ただなんか、誰かがやってる時じゃないと見る余裕ないかも
I might not have time to watch unless someone else is playing.
ま、そうだよね
Well, that's true.
そう、私はそれで見てやってたけど
Yeah, I was watching while playing, but...
スパイグラス？
A spyglass?
あの、望遠鏡でなんかあれらしいよ
Like, using a spyglass, apparently...
ないな、スパイグラス検索してもないや
No... searching for "spyglass" yields nothing.
エングラムに...
In engrams...
なんかスパイグラスっていうやつらしい
Apparently it's called a spyglass.
けどスパイグラスがそもそもエングラムにないから何なんだろ？
But spyglass isn't in the engrams in the first place, so what is it?
エングラムと...
Engrams and...
音落としてもらおうかな
Maybe I should lower the volume.
スパイグ...えっとね、制作...エングラムで幾つだったかな？望遠鏡
Spyg... um, craft... What level was telescope in the engrams again?
スパイ... SPY... SPY...
Spy... S-P-Y... S-P-Y...
あ、これか！スパイグラス！
Ah, this one! Spyglass!
あ、これだ！
Ah, this is it!
スパイグラスっていうやつじゃないとダメなのかな？
Does it have to be the one called Spyglass?
スパイグラスっていうヤツが遠くからでもあれだな、HPとかが見えるらしい
Apparently the Spyglass lets you see HP and stats even from afar.
あ、遠くからでもね
Ah, even from a distance, huh?
そうそうそう
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
だからここ固定...
That's why it's fixed here...
イナ、テレポータルまで来れるかい？
Ina, can you make it to the teleporter?
あ、じゃあ戻ります？
Ah, should I head back?
うん、戻ってきてほしい
Yeah, I want you to come back.
はーい
Okay!
テレポータルってどこ...
Where is the teleporter...
えっと、テレポータルはね...
Um, the teleporter is...
死んだ場所のところかな？
Around where you died, maybe?
26の62だね
26, 62.
26の...
26...
あれ？俺のワイバーンどこ行った？
Huh? Where did my wyvern go?
あ、スパイグラスじゃないとダメなんだね
Ah, so it has to be the Spyglass.
え？ え？ え？
Eh? Eh? Eh?
エリー・トワ・バーン
Elite Wyvern...
え？ え？ え？
Eh? Eh? Eh?
なんだなんだ？
What is it, what is it?
大丈夫ですか？
Are you okay?
え？
Eh?
なん、なんか殺されちゃった
I... I got killed!
は... はわ... はわ...
Wa... hawawawa...
え、わー！
Eh, waah!
リスポーンまで、しかもすぐリスポーンできないし
Until respawn... plus I can't respawn right away!
うわー！
Uwaaa!
やばい、20秒まで戻れない
Oh no, I can't spawn back for another 20 seconds!
ス...スポ... できない
I can't... respawn!
えぇー！？ えぇー！？
Eh!? Eh!?
早く！戻らせてくれー！
Hurry! Let me go back!
う... うっと...
U-Um...
水... 水横の...
Water... next to the water...
あ、やっと帰れる
Ah, I can finally return.
帰れた、良かったー
I returned, thank goodness!
え、どこここ？
Eh, where is this?
え？ 待って、なんか全然知らないところ来ちゃった
Eh? Wait, I came to a completely unknown place!
あ、ござるさんのとこに来ちゃった
Ah, I ended up where Gozaru-san is!
こっちだ
This way.
イナえー、火山の... まだみんな居る？
Ina, um... volcano's... is everyone still there?
イナがまだ居るかな？
Is Ina still there?
あ、まだテレポートに...
Ah, still at the teleport...
オッケー
Okay.
じゃあ行きます
Then I'm going.
行ってきます
Off I go.
火山だよね？
It's the volcano, right?
火山だね
It's the volcano.
オッケー
Okay.
いてー！
Ouch!
えーっと、あ、こっちだ
Um, ah, it's this way.
こっちに...
Over here...
よいしょ
Up we go.
広大...4章？
Vast... Chapter 4?
えっと...
Um...
こっち行って、こっ... おぉ
Go this way, and th... oh!
で、海の方か？
And towards the ocean?
あ、そうそうそうそう
Ah, right right right right.
これは誰... あ、違うな
Who is this... Ah, no.
あー！うわー！おお！はい！
Aah! Uwaa! Oh! Yes!
行ってしまった
It flew off.
ん？みんな、どっちの海の方だ？
Hmm? Everyone, which ocean side is it?
こっちか
This way?
よいしょ、火山に行きます
Heave-ho, heading to the volcano.
はい
Okay.
よいしょ
Up we go.
着いたー
Arrived!
お！
Oh!
あ、待って、イナ... イナ待ちなんだよね、今
Ah, wait, Ina... you're waiting for Ina now, right?
どこで... えっと...
Where... um...
えっと...
Um...
26の67
26, 67.
67...
ここか？
Is it here?
あ、26... 雪山に近い... あ、まだ貰ってない。後で取る。
Ah, 26... close to the snow mountain... Ah, I haven't gotten it yet. I'll get it later.
雪山の方かな？
Towards the snow mountain?
26の62...
26, 62...
ビビのところ...
Vivi's place...
あ、そうそう、ビビのところかな？なんで自分表示されないんだろう？
Ah, right right, Vivi's place? Why aren't I showing up?
トライブなのに
Even though we're in the same tribe...
なんでだ？
Why is that?
いるよな
They're here, right?
あ、ちょっとスタミナ
Ah, my stamina...
なんでだ？
Why is that?
でもあと30分で終わる。早っ！
But it's ending in 30 minutes. So fast!
30分！
30 minutes!
うわー！
Woah!
いけるかな？来れるかな？
Can we make it? Can you come over?
あ、見つか…見つかりました。
Ah, I was... I was found.
よかったよかったよかった。あ、そっち！
Thank goodness, thank goodness! Ah, that way!
行きすぎ…行きすぎました。通り過ぎてた。
I went too far... I went too far. I flew right past.
アキー。ありがとう。で…
Aki! Thank you. And...
えっと、追従をキャンセルかな？
Um, should I cancel the "Follow"?
「止まれ」っていうのたぶん…
The "Stop" command is probably...
止まれ
Stop.
うん。止まれ。
Yeah, "Stop".
あるかな？
Is it there?
あ、まだついてき…あ、オッケーオッケーオッケー。ありがとう！
Ah, it's still following... Ah, okay, okay, okay. Thank you!
よし、でこっちか。
Alright, so this way then.
いいよ。
Sure.
いいよー。
Alright.
で、海側の方にまた行きましょう。
So let's head towards the beach side again.
よいしょ、よいしょ。
Up we go.
さあ、私はちょっとアイテムも回収しなければ。
Well, I also need to collect my items.
えーっと…
Ummm...
よいしょ、よいしょ。ウイーン。
Alright, alright. Wheee!
なんか持ってきてたらよかったのかな？
Maybe I should have brought something?
ん？
Hmm?
恐竜。
A dinosaur.
あー、確かにちょっと今戦える恐竜がいないかも。
Ah, that's true, we might not have any battle-ready dinos right now.
私、カプセルにユティ持ってますけど。
I have a Yutyrannus in a Cryopod, though.
あ、じゃあ行けるか！
Ah, then we can do it!
なら行けるかも。うわー、いるなー海辺に。
Then we might be fine. Wow, there are some by the beach.
僕テリジノが返ってこないから何もできないんだよね。
My Therizino hasn't returned, so I can't do anything.
おや、テリジノはどこに？
Oh? Where is your Therizino?
あの、さっきの洞窟探検のスタックで死んで消えて補填待ち。
Um, it got stuck during that cave exploration earlier, died and vanished, so I'm waiting for a replacement.
なるほどね。
I see.
そう。プテラもだからメインで使ってたやつ補填待ちなんだよね。
Yeah. That's why the Pteranodon I usually main is also waiting for a replacement.
あー、なるほどなるほど。あ、これ、これか？もしかして自分の。
Ah, I see, I see. Ah, is this... is this it? Maybe my own...
あ、でもパイロいますよ、あそこ。
Ah, but there's a Pyromane over there.
あ、パイロいる！あいつさっきやろうとしたんだよね、確か。
Ah, a Pyromane! That's the one we tried to take on earlier, right?
今、あいつ再...再できるのかな？
Can we re... try that one now, I wonder?
ん？これじゃないな。
Hmm? That's not it.
あ、これか。これいいな。
Ah, this one? This looks good.
よいしょ。
Up we go.
えっと…
Ummm...
これで…
With this...
あれ、自分のプテ…あっち行っちゃったのか。
Wait, my Ptera... did it fly over there?
よいしょ。
There we go.
オッケー、これでじゃあ行けるかな？
Okay, can we do it with this then?
じゃ、イーナが引っ張ってきてもらった方が、戦ってもらった方がいいのかな？
Should Eena pull it over, or fight it directly?
怖い！私ができるかな？
I'm scared! Can I really do this?
あ、でも自分もこれ…えっと何持ってきてんだっけ今？
Ah, but what... what did I bring with me right now?
一応私、生身で乗れる準備しとくよ。
Just in case, I'll prepare to ride on foot.
あ、オッケーオッケー。乗れる準備するなら、じゃあえっと…
Ah, okay, okay. If you're preparing to mount it, then...
じゃあ、テリで私が…
Then with the Theri, I'll...
そうだね、ちょっと攻撃して…
Yeah, attack it a bit...
テリじゃなくて、あの、ユ…ユティか。
Not the Theri, um, Yu... Yutyrannus.
ユティか！ユティ、そうだね。ユティで。
A Yuty! Right, with the Yutyrannus.
えー、じゃあプテロはどうするのがいいかな？
Umm, so what should we do with the Pteranodon?
プテロは置いていってもらえたら。
If you could just leave the Ptera behind.
止ま…固定で大丈夫かな？
Sto... Is keeping it fixed okay?
固定で大丈夫かな？止まって…
Is keeping it fixed okay? Stop...
止まってもらったらオッケーだったと思う、たぶん。
I think as long as it stays stopped, it's fine, probably.
おっと！切っちゃった！
Whoops! I unmounted!
うわー！カッコいい！やばい！
Whoa! So cool! Amazing!
パイロの、もしかして卵？あれ。
Wait, is that a Pyromane egg?
ここで止ま…
Stopping here...
いや、でもここで敵が…いやー！
No, but enemies here... Oh no!
どこか岩場の上に置いていってもらえたらいいよ。この辺りとか。
You can just leave it on top of a rock somewhere. Around here or so.
そうだね。
Right.
でかいかも。
This might be big.
置けちゃった。
I placed it down.
置けちゃった？
You placed it?
卵消えちゃった。
The egg disappeared.
なん…何だったんだろ、何の卵？
What... what was that egg?
えっと、ユティ…
Um, Yuty...
あーい！
Ah, okay!
はい、ユティ。行くぞ！
Alright, Yuty! Let's go!
ユティ居るか！ユティでちょっと殴ってくれ、こいつを！
Is the Yuty there? Use the Yuty to hit this guy a bit!
ちょっとトンデル、ちょっと…戻って、トンデル！
Wait, Tonderu, wait... Come back, Tonderu!
チャット停止させたらOKかな？
If I stop the chat, is that okay?
いくつか...
A few of them...
えっと... 止ま... 止ま...
Um... stop... stop...
止まって... 止まるやつが... OK、それでOKかな？うん。
Stop... the one that stops... Okay, is that okay? Yeah.
大丈夫ですか？ OK。
Are you ready? Okay.
うん。じゃあユウティに...
Yeah. Then on the Yuty...
やばい、カマキリが！
Oh no, a mantis!
はい！
Yes!
じゃ、行きます！ おいしょ！ はやーい！
Okay, here I go! Heave-ho! So fast!
おら！ 乗れるか？
Take that! Can you ride it?
あ、今乗れるかも！
Ah, maybe now!
あ、乗れるかも！ 乗れる！ 乗れる！
Ah, maybe! You can ride it! You can!
あ、遠い！ あ...
Ah, too far! Ah...
あ、まだだ。まだ乗れない。 じゃあ、もう1回。
Ah, not yet. Can't ride yet. Okay, one more time.
消えてる。
It disappeared.
あ、今！ 今、今、今、今！
Ah, now! Now, now, now, now!
なんかカマキリ、カマキリ！ 今！ あー！ カマキリ！
Wait, mantis, mantis! Now! Ah! Mantis!
今乗れないね。出ないね。
Can't ride now. The prompt doesn't show up.
止まってる時... うわ！ なんで降りたの、今？
When it's stopped... Woah! Why did I dismount just now?
乗れた！ 乗れた、乗れた、乗れた！
I got on! I got on, got on, got on!
あ、ちょっとこのマンティス！ マンティス！
Ah, wait, this mantis! Mantis!
イナ、イナ、退いてほしい！
Ina, Ina, move out of the way!
あ、はい！
Ah, okay!
あ、爆発した！ あー！
Ah, it exploded! Ah!
おら！ カマキリが...
Take that! The mantis...
あー！ イナ死んだ！ あー！
Ah! Ina died! Ah!
カマキリが強すぎたかな！ カマキリ強すぎたー！
Maybe the mantis was too strong! The mantis was way too strong!
水に触れてたのかな、今？ 落ちちゃったのかな？
Was it touching the water just now? Did it fall off?
おらー！ 水の中かな、カマキリ？
Take that! Is the mantis in the water?
水の中って燃える？ 敵。
Does an enemy burn inside water?
燃えない。
No, it doesn't.
ちょっと乗れたら陸上がらないといけないから...
If you mount it, you have to go up on land, so...
あ、そうだね。 陸でやった方がいいね。 乗る時は。
Ah, right. Better to do it on land. When mounting.
おいしょ。
Heave-ho.
くー！
Ugh!
カマキリ2匹いたからな。
There were two mantises after all.
ねー！ 急に飛んできたから... ちょっと白お迎えに行ってくるわ。
Right! They flew in suddenly... I'll go pick up Shiro.
はーい。
Okay.
おいしょ、おいしょ。
Yo-ho, yo-ho.
くー！
Ugh!
ここです。
Here it is.
まだもうちょっと時間あるから、きっといけるはず。
We still have a bit of time, so we should be able to do it.
じゃあ、もう生身であれ行くわ。 あの、火山。
Then I'll just go as I am without gear to the, um, volcano.
あ、生身で一旦火山行っても大丈夫？ プテラだけ連れて行くわ。
Ah, is it fine to go to the volcano as you are? I'll just bring the Ptera.
おいしょ。
Yo-ho.
ふー。 えっと、こちらっけ。
Phew. Um, is it this way?
おいしょ、おいしょ。
Yo-ho, yo-ho.
おいしょ、おいしょ。 たたた。
Yo-ho, yo-ho. Ta-ta-ta.
チャチャチャーン。
Ta-da!
ねぇ、せめて1体は... だってテイムしたいよねー。
Hey, at least one... Because we want to tame one!
ちょっと... あ、待ってごめん、間違えた間違えた！
Wait... Ah, wait, sorry, I messed up, I messed up!
おいしょ、おいしょ。
Yo-ho, yo-ho.
あ、サンキュー。
Ah, thank you.
えっと、あれ？ あれ？ オッケー？ うん。
Um, huh? Huh? Okay? Yeah.
おいしょ。 ほな。
Yo-ho. Well then.
ほな。
Well then.
えっと... あ、もしや自分これ... 肉が... 肉がない。
Um... Ah, could it be that I... meat... don't have meat.
あ、行っちゃっていいよ、全然。
Ah, you can go ahead, totally fine.
いいかい？ 自分の食べ物の肉がなかった。
Is it okay? I didn't have meat for my own food.
あちー！
So hot!
よし。
Alright.
オッケー？
Okay?
おいしょ、おいしょ。 オッケーっと。 おいしょ、おいしょ。
Yo-ho, yo-ho. Okay then. Yo-ho, yo-ho.
すーい。 ワッサワッサ。
Swoosh. Swish swish.
あっちゅ、あっちゅ！ あっちゅ、あっちゅ！ ほい！
Hot, hot! Hot, hot! Hop!
えっと、お肉...
Um, meat...
ベッド置いた方がいいかな？
Should I place a bed?
あーまあ近くにね、いっそね、ベッド置いちゃっても、そこから復活でもまあいいのかな。
Ah, well, nearby, maybe just placing a bed and respawning from there would be fine too.
やべー、なんかでかい恐竜がいる。 あれ、イナか？ 違うか、あ、イナだった。よかった。
Crap, there's a huge dinosaur. Wait, is that Ina? No? Ah, it was Ina. Whew.
あ、はい。 待って、待ってます！ 待ってた、よかった。
Ah, yes. Wait, I'm waiting! You were waiting, good.
俺のアイテム...
My items...
対策すればカンタ... カンタンって言いますけどね、苦労してるんですよ。
If you take precautions it's eas... You say easy, but we're struggling here!
おい、初見プレイだぞ、俺。
Hey, it's my first time playing, you know!
あー！ そうだった、そうだった！ こっちへ... あ、やばい！
Ah! That's right, that's right! Over here... Ah, oh no!
初見なんだぞ！ イナ、カマキリ助けて！
It's my first time! Ina, help with the mantis!
はい！ おいしょ。 ふー、ふふふ。 ありがとう。
Yes! Yo-ho. Phew, haha. Thank you.
いよ！ レッツゴー！
Here we go! Let's go!
海辺、海辺行きます。
To the beach, going to the beach.
このアキロでロゼキャンARKのためにDLC買ったんだからな。
I bought the DLC specifically for RoseCan ARK with this Ankylo!
ありがたいんだからな！
You should be thankful!
本当だぞ！買ったんだからな！
Really! Because I bought it!
あ、寝袋作るか、じゃあ近くに。
Ah, shall I make a sleeping bag nearby then?
そうだね。
Yeah.
私ぶんもほしいかも。
I might want one for myself too.
オッケー、じゃあちょっと近くの森で草でも狩りますか。
Okay, then shall we harvest some grass in the nearby woods?
ヤバい、実力不足ってすごい煽られてる。
Oh no, they're teasing me hard for my lack of skill.
なんだと？
What did you say?
ブロックしなきゃ。
I'll have to block them.
な、なんだって？
W-What did you say?
そ、そんな...
Th-That's...
ええと、こうやって繊維取って...
Let's see, gathering fiber like this...
あれ？寝袋、寝袋... 寝袋...
Huh? Sleeping bag, sleeping bag... sleeping bag...
え？なんか飛んでる！めっちゃ攻撃されてる！
Huh? Something's flying! It's totally attacking me!
皮がいるのか！皮か！
We need hide! Hide?
あ、仮拠点に皮結構あったよ。
Ah, there was plenty of hide at the temp base.
一旦帰る？これ。
Should we head back for now?
うん、皮...
Yeah, hide...
やめなさい！
Stop that!
大丈夫？飛んでる。
Are you okay? It's flying.
いいよー。
Okay~
飛んでる、たぶん箱に...
It's flying, probably in the box...
皮、皮、皮、皮...
Hide, hide, hide, hide...
あ、こっちだこっちだ。
Ah, this way, this way.
あ、なくなった。
Ah, it's gone.
えーっと、これで寝袋を...
Um, with this, the sleeping bag...
皮、皮、皮、皮...
Hide, hide, hide, hide...
あ、これで寝袋が作れるかな？
Ah, can I make sleeping bags with this?
オッケー、なんかすごいいっぱい作っちゃった。
Okay, I made way too many.
あ、よかったよかった、オッケーオッケー。これで...
Ah, great great, okay okay. With this...
これで寝袋つく...
Now making sleeping bags...
オッケー。で、火山行くぞー！
Okay. Now, let's head to the volcano!
あー、待ってねー。
Ah, wait a second~
火山、火山...
Volcano, volcano...
そういえばトワ様ってなんちゃらワイバーン作ったんかな？
Speaking of which, did Towa-sama make that whatever Wyvern?
うん。で、ライトニングワイバーンもみんなゲットしてる。
Yeah. And everyone got a Lightning Wyvern too.
あ、そっかそっか。
Ah, I see, I see.
そうそうそう。
Yeah yeah yeah.
え、それで今日受け取らないとダメなやつ？
Wait, is that the one we have to claim today?
冷蔵庫の中入ってる。
It's inside the fridge.
あ、オッケー。
Ah, okay.
え、でも取らないといけないんだよね？
Wait, but we still have to get it, right?
これで海岸へゴー！
And now, off to the coast!
明日何だったっけ？あの、マルマル、あの、なんちゃら...
What was tomorrow again? That, um, whatever...
エレメント？
Element?
エレメント行けるのかな？
Can we go for the Element?
行けるかな。でも、それだけパイロをテイムできたら行ける。
Maybe? But if we tame that many Pyros, we can go.
あー、明日ちょっと行きたいね、じゃあ。
Ah, then I'd like to go tomorrow.
そうそう、行きたいんだよね。
Yeah, yeah, I really want to go.
ちょっと離れたところに寝袋作るか、じゃあ。
Then shall we make sleeping bags a bit further away?
え、この岩場置いておく？寝袋。
Wait, put the sleeping bags on these rocks?
岩場いいと思います。
I think the rocks are good.
じゃあ1個もらおうかな。
Then I'll take one.
オッケー。よいしょ。
Okay. Here we go.
うわ、飛びすぎ！
Whoa, jumped too far!
俺のジャンプ飛びすぎ？
Did my jump go way too far?
俺のジャンプ飛びすぎ！
My jump went way too far!
俺のジャンプ飛びすぎ。
My jump went way too far.
ちょっと待ってね。
Hold on a sec.
シロー、どこ行った？
Shiro, where did you go?
今ね、岩場、スカイリムジャンプチャレンジしてる。
Right now, on the rocks, doing the Skyrim jump challenge.
全然いける全然いける。降りるか、ちょっと待ってよ。
It's totally fine, totally fine. Should I get off? Wait a second.
Okay.
イナもこっちだ、こっち。
Ina's over here too, here.
ここにこのあたりに寝袋置いちゃうか。
Should we put sleeping bags around here?
このひらべったいところに、ここに寝袋を置いちゃおう。
Let me put a sleeping bag in this flat spot right here.
えっと、待ってよ。イナにも寝袋を... はい。
Um, wait a sec. A sleeping bag for Ina too... Here.
ちょっと待って、フブちゃんどこ行った？あ、この岩場のところにいる。
Wait a second, where did Fubu-chan go? Ah, she's over by those rocks.
ちょっと待って。
Wait a sec.
ここでいい、ここでいいです。
Here is fine, here is fine.
どこだ？上か？
Where is it? Up above?
さっきのところにいるよ。よいしょ。
I'm at the place from earlier. Yoisho.
ワイバーン呼ばないとあれなんだよね。
If we don't call the Wyvern, it's...
あ、待って待って。多分離れたら来てくれるはず、それで。
Ah, wait, wait. If we move away, it should come over, so...
ワイバーンさ...ワイバーンじゃないわ、プテラさん。
Wyvern... Not Wyvern, Ptera-san.
あ、来た来た来た来た。よいしょ。
Ah, here it comes, here it comes. Yoisho.
よし、ここ！ここを今日のキャンプ地とする。
Alright, here! Let's make this today's campsite.
いいよ。
Okay.
あ、ここへ？ Okay.
Ah, over here? Okay.
獅白もここに置いちゃっていいよ。
Shishiro, you can put yours here too.
1個もらえます。
I'll take one.
いいよ。
Sure.
ここをリスポーン地とする。
Let's make this the respawn point.
皮の寝袋って土台いらないんか？
Do skin sleeping bags not need a foundation?
いらないいらない。
No, you don't need one.
助かる。
That helps.
よっし！これで...
Alright! With this...
これで多分いけるはず。よし。
With this, we should be good to go. Alright.
コナ、行きますか？
Kona, shall we go?
いいよ。
Sure.
よし、こっちだ、じゃあ。
Alright, over here then.
どこだー？
Where is it?
どこにいる？連れてこなきゃいけないんだよね、まずね。
Where is it? We have to bring it over first, right?
そうだね。
That's right.
えっと...どこだー？
Um... where is it?
近場に...もういない...あ、いたいたいたいた！
Nearby... isn't there anymore... Ah, there it is, there it is!
こっちこっちこっち！
Here, here, here!
動いてなくね？
Isn't it not moving?
あ、来た来てる来てる！今連れてきてる連れてきてる！
Ah, it's coming, it's coming! Bringing it over now, bringing it over now!
はい。で、海行って...
Okay. Next, go into the sea...
うん。
Yeah.
行って、乗ったら...
Go, and once you ride it...
このあたりで！このあたりでいいかな、炎が消える距離！
Around here! Around here should be good, the distance where the flame goes out!
あ、当たった。ほら。
Ah, it hit. See.
待ってよ、こっちに連れて来よう。そのあたりそのあたり。
Wait, let me lead it over here. Right around there, right around there.
あ、今いけるかも！
Ah, maybe we can do it now!
いけるかもです。あー、はい！
Maybe we can. Ah, okay!
いけるかも！どうだ？
Maybe we can! How is it?
いや、まだ無理か？
No, still impossible?
いや、いけるか！
Can we?!
いけるかも。まだだね。あ、じゃあ...
Maybe we can. Not yet. Ah, then...
もう一回...ヘビヘビヘビ！ヘビいる！
One more time... Snake, snake, snake! There's a snake!
あ、待って！ヘビが！
Ah, wait! The snake is...!
もうクールダウン...クールダウン...
Cooldown... Cooldown...
乗ったけど...クールダウンが...
I mounted it, but... the cooldown...
あら、気絶してます。
Ah, I'm passed out.
オッケー。あ、でも死んじゃった？
Okay. Ah, but did you die?
死ん...ワイバーンは死んだ。
Die... The Wyvern died.
ワイバーン？！
Wyvern?!
ちょうどカイロの下にヘビがいて...
There was a snake right under Kairo...
たすけてー！最悪ー！
Save me! That's the worst!
毎回邪魔が入るよな、やっぱな。
Obstacles always get in the way, after all.
えっと、どこだ？ちょっと山の上に行かないといないかも。
Um, where is it? Might need to go up the mountain to find it.
多分山の...ケーブみたいに行きながら見た気がするんですけど...
I feel like I saw it while going into something like a cave in the mountain...
あと1、2分ほどちょっと気絶してます、僕。
I'm passed out for another minute or two.
あ、了解です。
Ah, roger that.
了解です。
Roger that.
ヘビに噛まれて気絶してるんだよね、今。
I got bitten by a snake and passed out right now.
そう...気絶時間がね...
Yeah... the knock-out duration...
近場に本当近くにいないかな...
I wonder if there's any really nearby...
あー、ちょっと遠く行かなきゃいけないか。くぅ〜。
Ah, guess I have to go further out. Ugh.
あ、でもあと20秒ぐらいで動けそう。
Ah, but looks like I can move in about 20 seconds.
あとここ、今のところにまっすぐこここっち...1匹やれました。
And here, right straight from where you are now... took care of one.
こっちいるか？
Is it over here?
はい、見えました。
Yes, I saw it.
おや？
Oh?
ちょっと右の...
A bit to the right...
あ、右のほう、ここ、このあたり？
Ah, to the right, here, around here?
はい。
Yes.
ヒットポイントやばい... あ！本当だ本当だ！黄色の黄色の！
Hit points are bad... Ah! It's true, it's true! Yellow, yellow one!
お前来い、お前来い。
Come here, you! Come here, you!
自分ヒットポイントちょっとないんで行けないですね。
I don't have much HP left, so I can't go.
やばい？
Is it bad?
ちょっとやばいね。ヒットポイント100しかない、今。
A bit bad. Only got 100 HP right now.
あらら。じゃあ、ちょっと獅白が乗ってみるか。アレだね、フブちゃんのほうがいいかも。
My my. Then should Shishiro try riding it? Though maybe Fubu-chan's would be better.
あ、確かに獅白がUTに乗ったほうがいいかも。
Ah, true, maybe Shishiro riding UT would be better.
あ、OK
Okay.
はい。あれ、どこ行った？
Right. Huh, where did it go?
あれ、なんかどっか... どっか消えちゃった。
Huh, it kind of... disappeared somewhere.
あれ？
Huh?
あ、なんか引っかかってるお前。
Ah, you're stuck, you know.
パイロ、パイロ。え、なんか... なんか逃げてるお前。ど-どうしたパイロ？どうした？
Pyro, Pyro. Hey, why... why are you running away? W-What's wrong, Pyro? What's wrong?
「いや、僕、湖見たい」
"No, I want to look at the lake."
あ、こっちこっちこっちこっち！
Ah, over here, over here, over here!
あ、来た来た来た来た！
Ah, here it comes, here it comes!
うわー、熱い！
Uwah, hot!
こっちか。
This way?
こっちこっちこっちこっち！
Over here, over here, over here!
あ、来た来た来た来た来た！
Ah, here it comes, here it comes!
Come on!
どう？
How is it?
ほら、この水辺で。
Look, by the water.
どう？まだか？
How is it? Not yet?
逃げてる？
Is it running away?
トワちゃん追ってるね。
Towa-chan is following it.
あ、いまイナ、イナ追ってるかも。
Ah, right now it might be chasing Ina.
うわぁ！
Uwah!
攻撃ターゲット、攻撃ターゲット！
Attack target! Attack target!
OK, OK. これで、これで多分...
OK, OK. With this, with this probably...
どう？乗れそう？
How is it? Can you ride it?
まだ...
Not yet...
あ、今できるかな？
Ah, can I do it now?
ちょっと泳いじゃってるから、もうちょっと陸側に...
It's swimming a bit, so push it a bit more towards land...
まだ？
Not yet?
あ、乗れました！
Ah, I got on!
OK!
敵倒して、敵倒して！
Defeat the enemies, defeat the enemies!
敵が、敵がいないか？
Aren't there any enemies?
え、なんて言うか...
Um, how do I put it...
陸上がって、陸上がって！
Go up on land, go up on land!
あの、敵に... 敵当てて！
Um, hit... hit the enemies!
敵を、敵を！
The enemies, the enemies!
敵がいないー！
There are no enemies!
なんで体温が...
Why is the body temp...
10秒...
10 seconds...
あ、いるいるいる！ここ、ここいる！
Ah, there's some! Here, here's some!
イナ、こっち！イナ、ここ！
Ina, over here! Ina, here!
これこれこれ！このフンコロガシも！ここ！
This one! This dung beetle too! Here!
この、この... 岩！岩！岩！
This, this... rock! Rock! Rock!
このカブトムシみたいなやつ！
This beetle-like guy!
あ、ごめん、ごめんごめん...
Ah, sorry, sorry...
あー！ダメー！
Ahhh! Nooo!
もう一回だ！
One more time!
あー！痛痛痛痛痛！
Ahhh! Ow ow ow ow!
熱熱熱熱熱！
Hot hot hot hot hot!
水の中に！
Into the water!
OK
OK OK OK...
熱熱熱熱熱！
Hot hot hot hot hot!
でも5分かかるのか...
But it takes 5 minutes, huh...
5分です...
It's 5 minutes...
あーー
Ahhh...
いやー、惜しかったー！
Man, that was so close!
5分はちょっと長えわ。
5 minutes is a bit too long.
長いね...
It is long...
惜しい...
So close...
惜しかったねー。
That was close, huh.
あ、なんかクラフトしてクリアしてるね。
Ah, looks like someone cleared it by crafting.
リニオグナタ... あれか？昆虫か？
Rhyniognatha... is that it? The insect?
あー、5分はちょっと長いな...
Ah, 5 minutes is a bit long...
乗れないもんね、多分今。
We can't ride it right now, probably.
今乗れないね。
We can't ride it now.
しょうがない、しょうがない。
Can't be helped, can't be helped.
新しいやつ連れてこよう。
Let's bring a new one.
ね。
Yeah.
新しいのいこう。
Let's go for a new one.
いるかなー？
I wonder if there's one?
まあ、でもあと5分しかないから...
Well, but there's only 5 minutes left...
ちょっと厳しいか...？
Might be a bit tough...?
ラストチャンス行くか！
Let's go for the last chance!
ラストチャンス！ラストチャンス行くか！
Last chance! Let's go for the last chance!
こっちこっちこっち！
Over here, over here!
あ、来てる来てる！おーい、降りてこい降りてこい！
Ah, it's coming! Hey, come down, come down!
あ、来た来た来た来た！
Ah, here it comes, here it comes!
よっしょ、よっしょ。
Alright, alright.
レベル55か。
Level 55, huh?
あ、まあまあ。でも1体テイムしちゃってもいい。
Ah, well. But taming even just one is fine.
ちょっと待ってね。
Hold on a sec.
ちょっとベストポジション...
Just need a best position...
どう？まだ？
How is it? Not yet?
行きます！
Here I go!
ちょっと泳いでるから足が遅いんだね。
Since it's swimming, it's slow.
まだです。
Not yet.
あ、出た出た出た！
Ah, got it, got it!
痛い！
Ouch!
もうちょっとかな？
A bit more?
あ、乗れました！
Ah, I mounted it!
あ、来た来た来た！
Ah, here it comes!
これどう... どう使うんですか？この火。
How... how do you use this fire?
あのね、なんか攻撃ボタン...
Well, like the attack button...
Ctrl + 右クリックで火だったかな？
Was it Ctrl + Right Click for fire?
いないかな、敵...
Are there any enemies...?
さっきさ、サソリとかこの辺いたけどな。
Earlier, there were scorpions around here though.
あ、あ！ここここ！ここにいる！これこれこれ！
Ah! Here, here! Here's one! This one!
これこれこれこれ！
This one, this one!
Ctrl... 火...
Ctrl... fire...
1回、倒して... 攻撃... そうそうそう！
Once, defeat it... attack... Yeah yeah yeah!
もうちょっと、もうちょっと！
A bit more, a bit more!
それで、Ctrl + 右とかで...
And then with Ctrl + Right click or something...
で、イナ、後ろ後ろ！
And Ina, behind you, behind you!
そうそうそう！
Yeah yeah yeah yeah!
で、イナ、こっちにも敵いる！これこれこれ！
And Ina, there's an enemy here too! This one!
そうそうそう！吸っちゃっていいよ！吸っちゃっていいよ！
Yeah yeah yeah! Just absorb it! Just absorb it!
あー、できたー！
Ah, I did it!
やったー！できたー！
Yay! We did it!
やー！できたー！あー！
Yay! We did it! Ahhh!
出来たー！
We did it!
やったー！
Yay!
イナー！
Ina!
1回でいけるね！ナイッス！
Doing it in one go! Nice!
やったー！
Yay!
イナすごいよー！
Ina, you're amazing!
あいつー、イナー！
That's awesome, Ina!
いけた いけた
We did it, we did it!
いや めっちゃ... なんか
Yeah, so much... like...
イエイ！
Yay!
経験値！ レベリング！レベリング！
Experience points! Leveling! Leveling!
レベリング！レベリング！
Leveling! Leveling!
おら！おら！
Take that! Take that!
ナイス！
Nice!
イアー！
Yeah!
後ろにもいるといいな...
I hope there are more behind us...
あ、またフンコロガシがまた来てる！
Ah, the dung beetles are coming again!
なんかノコノコ動いてないです...
Wait, it's not moving at all...
え？大丈夫？
Huh? Is it okay?
いや、ここでなんとか...
Well, we managed here somehow...
なんとか重なったねー！
We made it work somehow!
なんとかなったー！
We made it work!
すごーい！
Amazing!
よかったー！
Thank goodness!
イナ、モンボール... モンボールある？
Ina, do you have a cryopod? Cryopod?
モンボールっていうか、あの... なんか...
Or like a soul ball or something...
あ、持ってるやん！
Ah, you have it!
あ、オッケー！じゃあ、これ戻って帰るか。
Ah, okay! Let me head back with this.
そうだね、入れちゃおうか、じゃあ。
Yeah, let's put it in then.
じゃあ、イナちゃん自分のあれ持ってくるわ。あの...
Then, Ina-chan, I'll bring your... um...
あ、イナ降りちゃってもいいよ。
Ah, Ina, you can get off now.
あ、オッケーです。
Ah, okay.
プテラのところまで行っちゃおう。
Let's go over to the Pteranodons.
あれ？あ、もうどこで... ポッドできないか？
Huh? Ah, can't we cryopod it here?
あれ？モンボールできない？
Huh? Can't cryopod it?
あ、まさかこれイナじゃないとできないか？
Ah, maybe only Ina can do it?
イナじゃないとできなさそうだな。
Looks like only Ina can do it.
今、怪我ついててできなくて... ちょっとメニューが...
Right now it's injured so I can't... the menu...
ああ、そうなんだ！なんかできない...
Ah, I see! No wonder...
パイロの... ああ、なるほどね。
Pyromane's... Ah, I see.
メニューでご飯？
Food in the menu?
もう入れて...
Already put in...
肉はもう入るっぽいです。
Looks like there's meat already in.
肉はあるよ。
There's meat.
これでも大丈夫だな。
This should be fine.
あ、待って！あ、いまサソリが！
Ah, wait! Ah, a scorpion just...
あ。
Ah.
ナイス！
Nice!
え、なんで動いてない... お！
Huh? Why isn't it moving... Oh!
あ！
Ah!
いや、バックステップはやったんですけど...
Well, I did a backstep, but...
ねー！
Right?!
全然... 全然動いてない。
Not moving... Not moving at all.
肩に乗せられるらしいよ。なんか。
Looks like you can carry it on your shoulder, apparently.
乗って、Control + C だって、イナ。
Mount it and press Ctrl + C, Ina.
乗って Control + C？
Mount and Ctrl + C?
うん。
Yeah.
おー、乗った乗った！
Oh, it worked! It worked!
えー、かわいい！
Ehh, so cute!
かわいい！じゃあ帰ろう！こっちこっち、イナ！
So cute! Okay, let's head back! This way, this way, Ina!
あ、じゃあ、それで帰ろう。
Ah, then let's go back with that.
それで帰ろう！イナ！
Let me head back with that! Ina!
ユーティ... ユーティはここだよ。
Yuty... Yuty is right here.
あ、じゃあユーティも回収しよう。こっちこっち。
Ah, let me retrieve the Yuty too. Over here, over here.
これ回収... 回収して...
Retrieve this... retrieve it and...
あ、多分... 回収して、えっと...
Ah, probably... retrieve it, and then...
で、飛んで帰る。
And then fly back.
はい。
Okay.
オッケー。あ、でイナのプテラ連れてくればいいんだ。えっと...
Okay. Ah, then I just need to bring Ina's Ptera. Um...
あ、私のプテラ乗ってますよ、私が。
Ah, my Ptera... I'm already riding it.
あ、乗ってる！あ、よかったよかった！
Ah, you're riding it! Ah, good, good!
よーし！
All right!
よし、よし、よし、よし！
Alright, alright, alright, alright!
え、待って、名前が「ミャオ」なんだけど！
Wait, its name says "MEOW"!
なんか名前... 「オモイ」だって！
What name... it says "HEAVY"!
ミャオって！
It says MEOW!
今、離れたら... 「イナ・ミャオ」って書いてあった！
When I stepped away... it said "INA MEOW"!
やったー！
We did it!
やったねー！
あー... いや、よかったー！
Ah... man, I'm so glad!
これで... これで戦えるか。
With this... can we fight now?
でも、欲を言うともう1匹欲しいね。
Though if I'm being greedy, I'd like one more.
ま、そうだね、もう1匹行けたらいいね。
Well, true, if we can get another one, that'd be nice.
でもやり方もうできたから...
But now that we know how to do it...
ねー、明日やりたいね。
Yeah, I want to try tomorrow.
明日1匹獲って、ボス行けたら...
If we catch one tomorrow and go to the boss...
うん！
Yeah!
いいね！
Nice!
裏ミッションとボスに行けたらいいかな。
It'd be great if we can do the off-stream mission and the boss.
いや、行けたー！
Aww, we made it!
もうちょっと上か。
A bit higher up?
ういー！
Wheee!
おいしょ、おいしょ、おいしょ...
Heave-ho, heave-ho...
いや、今日寝れる！
Man, I can sleep today!
寝れるわ、今日！
I can sleep soundly today!
今日ほんとよかったー！
Today was really great!
よし、よし、よし、よし！
Alright, alright, alright, alright!
えい！
Ei!
イナの方見ると「MEOW」って書いてある。
Looking at Ina, it says "MEOW".
なんか名前何にしようと思ったら...
I was thinking what to name it...
MEOW
ええ、超かわいいだよー！
Ehh, it's super cute!
よっしゃ、あ！これで今日終了だー！
Alright, ah! That's it for today!
オッケー！イエーイ！
Okay! Yay!
はーい！自分は本拠点の方戻ろうかな。
Alright! I guess I'll head back to the main base.
あ、そうだね、また合流... オッケーだよー。
Ah, right, let's meet up again... Okay!
よしよし。
Alright, alright.
よいしょ。
Heave-ho.
日記書かなきゃ。
I gotta write in my diary.
記念だよねー。これ回収して...
It's a memory, right? Let me pick this up...
よいしょ、冷やしとくか。恐竜も冷やしておく。
Heave-ho, let's put it in cold storage. Put the dinos in cold storage too.
えっと、保管用っと。
Um, for storage...
で、今日の...
And today's...
ミッション報酬の...
mission rewards...
何だっけ？チームミッション、ライトニングワイバーン、これ貰っていいのか？
What was it? Team mission, Lightning Wyvern... can I take this?
あ、そうそうそう！あ、ライワイもうね、ある。
Ah, yes yes yes! Ah, Light Wyvern... we already have it.
あるか、じゃあいいや。
We have it? Then never mind.
仮拠点側の方の冷蔵庫の中に全員分入ってるはず。
They should all be inside the fridge over at the temp base.
オッケー、はい。
Okay, got it.
ていうかさ、もう私の補強... 何だっけ？
By the way, my reinforce... what was it?
テリジノサウルス、ここから取っていいかな？
Therizinosaurus, can I take it from here?
うん、いいんじゃないかな？
Yeah, why not?
うん、補強... 補強のテリジノ...
Yeah, reinforce... backup Therizino...
あ、いや、それは聞いておいた方がいいかも。補強テリジノは。
Ah, wait, you might want to ask first about the backup Therizino.
あ、あー確かにな。
Ah, ah, true.
補強結局どっちかまだ分かんないんだよね。
We don't know which one is the backup yet.
これじゃないんだよね、本屋じゃないんだよね。
It's not this one, not the main store.
イベント参加賞ってどこだったっけ？イベント会場だっけ？
Where were the event participation prizes? At the event grounds?
イベント会場の外のなんかピンクの床のところ、ゲートがあると思うんだけど...
At the event venue, outside on the pink floor... I think there's a gate...
ピンクの横... その中にないかな？
Next to the pink one... I wonder if it's in there?
あ、回復してるね、こいつ等。
Ah, these guys are recovering.
あ、そっか。
Ah, I see.
Okay.
入れとこ。
I'll put it in.
参加賞？
A participation prize?
よいしょ。
There we go.
アルマドック？
Armadog?
Okay.
オッケーオッケー。
Okay, okay.
All right, what to write...
あ、なんかすごい集めてるじゃん。
Oh, you've gathered quite a lot!
よいしょ。
There we go.
Today was a struggle,
よいしょ。ちょっと1回...
Up, wait a second...
but we didn't...
えーと、こっちだっけ？コアラ...
Um, was it this way? Koala...
give up,
あ、これECだな。
Ah, this is EC.
and in the end,
we got...
えーと...
Um...
the flaming meowmeow!
あ、ここにか。いや、一応ここか。あ、ここでした。
Ah, here? No, maybe here. Ah, it was here.
よーし。
All right!
これも船放置しとくしかないけど、これ船壊されないのかな？大丈夫かな？
I have no choice but to leave the ship here, but I wonder if it'll get destroyed? Will it be okay?
よし。
All right.
大丈夫か？
Is it gonna be okay?
Lots of learning, lots of progress.
さなほなミッション、無事に帰ろう〜
Sana Hona mission, let's head home safely~
あ、やばい、脱水症状だ。
Ah, oh no, I'm dehydrated.
Oh yes, write the date.
September 5th, I guess.
よっし。
All right.
- Ina
うい〜
Wheee~
Okay.
みゃうがいる、みゃうが。 Meow.
There's a meow here, a meow. Meow.
えーっと... ほい。
Umm... Here.
集会場... オッケー。
Meeting place... okay.
ふぅ。
Phew.
かわいい。
So cute.
よいしょ。じゃないほうーちゃんにいにいっちゃうに。
Up! Going over to Brother and Brother Janai-hou!
はーい！
Yes!
差分入ってたからやっておいた。
There was a patch added, so I did it.
あ、本当だー！
Oh, really?!
お疲れ様でーす！進路... お疲れ様ー！
Good work, everyone! Route... Good work!
最後になんかテイムできました！
We managed to tame something at the end!
やったー！
Yay!
すごいすごい！あいつー！
Amazing, amazing! That guy!
やっったー！やったやったー！
Yayy! We did it, we did it!
ナイスです！大変すぎたー！
Nice! That was way too tough!
全部入れたの？
Did you put everything in?
確かに。
Indeed.
いや、マジで大変すぎた！
No, seriously, it was way too tough!
1回アルゲン狩ろうと思ったんだけど、15匹で1ポイントしか入んないから、これ効率悪いなと思ってやめたんだよね、こっち。
I thought about hunting Argentavis once, but hunting 15 only gives 1 point, so I quit thinking it was inefficient on this side.
あ〜
Ah~
やっぱちょっと効率悪いよね。
Yeah, it really is a bit inefficient.
うん。
Yeah.
一応ね、太鼓は叩いて、あ、太鼓を叩いたから、太鼓のその丸秘ミッションは...
Just in case, I hit the drums, and since I hit the drums, that secret mission for the drums...
うん。
Yeah.
1個クリアはしてる。
I've cleared one.
うん、はい。あ、良かった！
Yeah, okay. Ah, that's great!
まだ報酬は明日受け取ろうかなって。
I think I'll claim the rewards tomorrow.
うんうん。
Mhm, mhm.
了解です！助かりました、すいません本当にありがとうございます！色々...
Got it! That was a big help, sorry and thank you so much! For everything...
良かった良かった。じゃあ日誌を書いていこう、日誌を。
Glad to hear, glad to hear. Let's write our journal now, the journal.
今実は仮拠点に石の壁をめっちゃ貼る作業をしてて...
Actually, right now I'm working on putting up lots of stone walls at the temporary base...
お〜
Oh~
ありがたい〜！もしちょっとだけまだ元気だよって人がいたら壁を作って貼ってくれませんか？
Thank you so much~! If anyone still has some energy left, could you make walls and put them up?
壁を... 壁はあるの？
Walls... are there walls?
あ、ファーミングダメかも、もしかすると。
Ah, farming might not work, possibly.
ファームダメなんだ。
Farming doesn't work?
うん、ファームダメだね。
Yeah, farming is a no-go.
直してるか。よいしょ。
Are you repairing it? There we go.
えーっと、これの素材だっけ？消費か。
Umm, is this the materials? Consumables, huh.
あれ、向こうにいるビビアンとか...
Wait, Vivien over there and such...
それってポッドの...
Is that in a cryopod...
えっーとね、ポッドがねあるんだ。
Umm, there are cryopods.
今ビビどこいる？
Where is Vivi right now?
ビビ仮拠点です。
Vivi is at the temporary base.
あ、じゃあポッド持っていくね、そっちに。
Ah, then I'll bring the cryopods over there to you.
あ、ありがとうございます！パイロはポッド...
Ah, thank you! For Pyro, a cryopod...
いらないんですかね？
Is it not needed?
ん？
Hmm?
パイロはポッドに入れない？
Pyro can't go into a cryopod?
パイロ... あ、パイロ...
Pyro... Ah, Pyro...
あ、入れないかもしれないから...
Ah, it might not be able to go in, so...
じゃあその、この...
Then that... this...
あっちでいいかな？あの集会場のところかな？
Is over there okay? Around the meeting place, maybe?
あー、はいはい。
Ah, got it, got it.
オッケーです。
All right.
あ、何のアート？アート壊れた？
Ah, what art? Is the art broken?
え、待って、トワ様まだ日記書いてないですよね？
Wait, Towa-sama hasn't written in the journal yet, right?
うん。
Yeah.
出れない...
Can't get out...
1回日記書こうかな。日記書いて...
I think I'll write in the journal first. Write in the journal...
オッケー。
Okay.
残った時間でやろうかな。
And then do it in the remaining time.
うん、一応入るってポッドにパイロ。
Yeah, apparently Pyro can go into a pod.
あ、入れれるのかな？
Ah, can it go in?
うん、入れられるらしいよ。
Yeah, it seems you can put it in.
じゃちょっとやってみます。
Let me give it a try.
あれ、落ちた？
Wait, did I fall?
おふ。
Oof.
なんか落ちちゃったの？このゲーム
Did this game crash or something?
はや
That was fast.
これ ど... どう戻せる？
How... how do I put this back?
んっと...
Um...
あ すごい えー... なんだっけ？
Oh, wow, super... Uh, what was it again?
ダブルクリックか Gを... ダブルクリック どっちだったっけかな？
Double-click? Or pressing G... Double-click, which one was it again?
肩に担いでいる...
Carrying on the shoulder...
恐竜を...
the dino...
あ Fでした
Ah, it was F.
あ Fだった ごめーん
Ah, it was F, I'm sorry!
ちっちゃい
It's so tiny.
これ ある？ポッドない
Is it here? No cryopod.
んっと...
Um...
1 2 3 4... 4匹 4つあればいいんかな？
1, 2, 3, 4... 4 of them, so having 4 is enough?
あ これも集計期間外 あ こうやってやって...
Oh, this one is out of the aggregation period too... Ah, if I do it like this...
よっしゃー 4つだ 離れたところに...
All right! Oh, it's four. In a far place...
あれ 死んじゃいそうだな... パッシブに...
Wait, it looks like it's gonna die... Set to passive...
えーっと じょう...
Um, status...
いろはが作ってくれた枠...
The framework Iroha built for us...
壁の上に 広げちゃった ちょっとだけ
Above the wall, I expanded it a little bit.
あ ありがとうございます 多分 上へ行けば...
Ah, thank you so much! Probably, if you go up...
ボールエリアできてる
The ball area is ready.
もう ちょっと簡易的な感じなんですけど ま でも これで仮拠点作りカッコみたいなのができたと思うんで
It's a bit simple, but well, I think we managed to build a sort of temporary base...
おー
Oh!
もう石類がないから無理かもな
We don't have any stone left, so it might be impossible.
あ オッケーです オッケーです
Ah, okay, okay.
石 結構取ったけど全然足りなかった
I gathered quite a bit of stone, but it wasn't enough at all.
てか ま 一周ぐるっと囲んだから...
I mean, we surrounded the whole thing...
ま 一旦 なんて言ったらいいんだろう こう突進してくるやつは...
Well, for now, how should I put it, the ones that charge at us...
なんとか防げるかな？
will hopefully be blocked.
ど-どうする？
Wh-What should we do?
コントロール... ひ-左... ん？
Control... l-left... Hm?
え？プテラノドン死んだ？
Huh? Did the Pteranodon die?
へ？これや！
Huh? This is it!
にゃー！
Meow!
にゃー はい 目元 多分ね チェンジなのかな？変身ってのがあったんだよね
Meow, yes. Look here. Maybe "change"? There was an option for transformation.
そう Eを長押しして...
Yeah, hold down E...
あー なるほど！
Ah, I see!
右下に そうそうそうそう
On the bottom right, yeah yeah yeah.
ベスト あれ？
Best. Huh?
おー！
Ooh!
で えーっと BBの子達はどこだ？
And, um, where are BB's dinos?
BBの子達 あの...
BB's dinos are, um...
なんかちょっと離れた所にいるんですけど...
They're in a place a bit further away...
あー あの離れたやつもね これこれポッド ポッド ポッド どうぞ
Ah, those far away ones too. Here, take these cryopods, go ahead.
ありがとうございます！
Thank you very much!
そして なんかここにいたプテラが1匹死にました で サドルもなくなっちゃいました
And, um, one of the Pteranodons that was here died. And the saddle disappeared too.
あー... じゃあ 時間経過かな？
Ah... then, maybe time decay?
あ できた！え？
Ah, it worked! Huh?
ここでポッド...
Cryopod here...
時間経過で死んじゃったかな？
Did it die due to time decay?
あ 入れる！
Ah, I can store it!
ありがとうございます ポッド
Thank you for the pod.
うん！
Yep!
あリゃー なんで？
Oh dear, why?
困るの これどうやって... えっと...
That's problematic, how do I... um...
モンモンで出せばいいのか
Should I pull it out with Monmon?
大丈夫か？
Is everything okay?
はい
Yes.
で あっちの このビビアンとかギュギュッととかもそうだよね？
And over there, these like Vivian and Gyugyutto, same for them right?
そうです そいつら...
Yes, those ones...
あ 了解！こいつらじゃあ捕まえてくわ
Ah, got it! Then I'll catch these ones.
ありがとうございます！
Thank you so much!
はーい！
Okay!
じゃあ ここに居るやつをモンモンに入れたらいいですか？とりあえず
So, should I put the ones here into Monmon for now?
あ そうだね！モンモンに入れといて で 集会場の方の自分の個人チェストでもいいし...
Ah, right! Put them in Monmon, and then put them in your personal chest at the meeting hall, or...
冷蔵庫の中でもいいし どこかチェストの中入れとけば...
or inside the fridge, as long as you put them in some chest...
はい！ありがとうございます！
Got it! Thank you!
うん
Yeah.
よーし しゃーい！
Alright, let's do this!
え 手に入れられんのか？これ
Huh? Can I get into this?
あ ここて...
Ah, here...
にゃーお
Meow.
あら バグで死んだっと？
Oh, did it die due to a bug?
は？
Huh?
え？
What?
ピピピ... あら？ピピピ 今入れたけどな...
Pipipi... Huh? Pipipi, but I just put it in...
あれ？ピピピのインベントリが残っている あ これはいでも... あ よいしょ
Huh? Pipipi's inventory is still there. Ah, but this... Ah, heave-ho.
モンモン入れたからや
Because I put it in Monmon.
解決？解決した？
Solved? Did you solve it?
デジャブです
It's deja vu.
よかった！
Glad to hear!
えっと... ギュギュッとと...
Um... Gyugyutto and...
そう 遠くに居るね なんか「女」っての居るんだけど 何？この「女」
Yeah, over there in the distance, there's someone called "Woman", what's with "Woman"?
あ なんか...
Ah, like...
女 繁殖するためだけに作られた...
Woman, bred solely for the purpose of reproduction...
いません！
No, there aren't!
はいはい！
Alright, alright!
はーい！
Okay!
はい ボタンちゃん 今ミュートなんだけど ちょっと取れるかな？
Yes, Botan-chan is muted right now, can she un-mute for a moment?
今ね そもそもスピーカーミュートだから
Because right now, her speaker is muted in the first place.
あ オッケーオッケー
Ah, okay, okay.
そしたらちょっと伝えてほしいんですけど...
In that case, I'd like you to pass a message to her...
えっっと さっきロスした恐竜とかアイテムとかについては...
Um, regarding the dinos and items that were lost earlier...
返却が... ボタンちゃんの個人ボックス 集会場の拠点にある中にある...
The returns... are in Botan-chan's personal box inside the meeting hall base...
そこに えっっと 返しますということでお伝えいただければと
So if you could let her know that we'll return them there.
はいー！
Will do!
はい お願いします！
Yes, please!
お願いしまーす！
Thank you!
お疲れ様でした！
Good work today!
全員...
Everyone...
お疲れ様でした！
Great job, everyone!
ちょっと...
Wait a sec...
ぜ 全員は無理やな 回収できるやつだけ回収しとくね これ遠くのやつら
All of them is impossible. I'll collect whatever I can, these ones in the distance.
はい！
Okay!
えっと...
Um...
ビビアンと...
Vivian and...
えっと ギュギュッと か
um, Gyugyutto, I see.
あ BB BBか！分かりましたー！
Ah, BB, it was BB! Got it!
ういー！お疲れ様ー！ありがとうございます！
Whew! Good job! Thank you very much!
ちょっ こいつら ここの中入っとったんかい！
Wait, were these guys inside here all along?!
確かに 免疫のアーティファクトってどこ行ったんだ？飾ってないけど
Now that you mention it, where did the Immune Artifact go? It's not on display.
あれはでも 個人の...
But that one is personal...
納品か納品になっちゃうから...
Since it'll end up being submitted...
免疫はないっす。飾るあれではないのかな？あ、トワ様が帰ってきてる。
No immunity. Is it not for display? Oh, Towa-sama is back.
なるほどね。
I see.
昇格だけはなんか飾るやつなのかな。ま、それか、納品したから明日飾られる可能性。
Maybe only promotions get displayed? Or maybe since we turned it in, it'll display tomorrow.
あー... ふんふんふん。うん。
Ah... Mm-hmm. Yeah.
あー！
Ahhh!
え？え？えーー！
What? What? What?!
あれに入ってしまった... 吸引力がすごかった。ブロワックの...
I got sucked into that... The suction was insane. Browack's...
あー... あれマジやばいよね。超吸い込んでくるよね。
Ah... That's really crazy. It sucks you in so hard.
吸い込まれて「えー！除外が...」ってなっちゃった。
I got sucked in and went "Eh?! Excluded..."
ワーハハハ...
Wahahaha...
おいしょ。じゃ、ビビ、これ行きましょうか。文文持ってるからギュギュっと。
Alright. Vivi, shall we go with this? I have the texts, so I'll pack them in.
あ、どちらでも大丈夫だよ。多分。
Ah, either is fine, probably.
あ、みんな日誌、2枚書いた方が...
Ah, for the diary, should everyone write 2 pages...
あ、そうね。任せるよ。
Ah, right. I'll leave it to you.
え、2枚？
Eh, 2 pages?
うん。どういうこと、2枚って？
Yeah. What do you mean by 2 pages?
マル秘ミッションだか、デイリーミッション、ゲリラミッションだかで...
Because of the secret, daily, or guerrilla missions...
あ、でも今ミッション... 出てないから、ミッションが...
Ah, but right now the mission... isn't showing up, so...
明日かな？出るとしたら。そこから入ってくると思う。
Tomorrow, maybe? If it comes out. It'll probably count from then.
あー、なるほど。じゃ、日誌2枚入れておけば、一旦明日クリアってことですよね。
Ah, I see. So if we put in 2 diary entries, tomorrow's will be cleared for now, right?
多分。
Probably.
じゃあ、9月5日続きって書けばいいか。
Then I guess I should write "Sep 5th Continued".
おいしょ。9月5日続きの2枚目。
Alright. Sep 5th continuation, 2nd page.
何かこう... 続きの2枚目。ええ...
Something like... continuation, 2nd page. Uhh...
おいしょ。ふう。えー... ナンバー2。
Alright. Whew. Uhh... Number 2.
オッケー。ふう。日記の1番悩むな。
Okay. Phew. Diary entries are the hardest to think about.
RIP Theriz... Tanked all the hits... よーし。
RIP Theriz... Tanked all the hits... Alright.
1日に2枚書くってことなのかな？
Does that mean writing 2 pages a day?
ね、そうみたいですね。ね。
Yeah, seems like it. Yeah.
様式変わるのかな？
I wonder if the format changes?
怒られるのかな、これ？
Will I get scolded for this?
Forever...
何書いてんだ。怒られるようなこと書いてるなー。
What are you writing? You're writing something you'll get scolded for!
いや、怒られることじゃないんだけど、なんか書くことなかったんだなーって思われそうな...
No, it's not bad, but it feels like people will think, "She had nothing to write..."
正解。書くことなかったんだろうな。
Bullseye. She really had nothing to write about.
ないよ、ないよ！
I didn't! I didn't!
ビビが迷子になったぐらいね。
Just that Vivi got lost, pretty much.
いやー、そうよ、今日。洞窟で1時間食ったからビビが先輩だった今日。迷子で。
Yeah, exactly, today! We spent an hour in the cave, so Vivi was the veteran today at getting lost.
いや、そんなことない。ござるも戻れなくてごめん... W迷子だった。
No, that's not true! Gozaru couldn't return either, sorry... It was double lost!
本当にありがとうございます。
Thank you so much, really.
いやいやいや...
No, no, no...
えっと... 集会場...
Umm... meeting hall...
どい。
Boing.
いや... こっちな... きたー！ ふいー！
No... this way... Here it is! Whew!
よし、できた。書いたぞ、日記。
Alright, done. The diary is written.
ナイス！ うざい日記を書いて...
Nice! After writing an annoying diary entry...
2枚ほど格納。おいしょ。
Storing two pages. Yoisho.
ちょっとじゃあ、皆さん作業片手に、ちょっと耳を貸してもらえると大変ありがたいのですが...
So while you're working, I'd really appreciate it if you could lend an ear...
ちょっと色々確認してもいいですか？
Can I check a few things with you all?
はーい！
Sure!
えっと、結局パイロメインっていう奴はテイムができたんでしょうか？
Um, in the end, were we able to tame that Pyromane?
1匹できたんだけど、できればもう1匹欲しいなっていう感じかな？
We got one, but ideally we'd like one more.
ああー、なるほどです。了解です。じゃあ、まあ2体目ってことで持っておきます。
Ah, I see. Understood. Then we'll keep note of getting a second one.
と、えっと... あとは...
And, um... also...
あとは、あのマル秘ミッションの... マンモスに乗って太鼓を叩くが、太鼓ができたから明日やればできそうが1つと...
Also, that secret mission... riding a mammoth and beating a drum. The drum is done, so doing that tomorrow looks doable...
はい。
Okay.
と、えっと、ケツ... ケツじゃない方... 名前忘れちゃう。あ、あと何だっけ？ えー、ラヴァエレメントだ。
And, um, Ketsu... not the Ketsu one... I forget the name. Ah, what else? Uh, Lava Element.
ラヴァエレメント。
Lava Element.
明日かな？ パイロが2体いたら、多分行けそうかなって感じは...
Tomorrow, maybe? If we have two Pyromanes, feels like we can probably do it...
なるほど。じゃあ、わかりました。そしたら一旦...
I see. Okay, got it. In that case, for now...
ちょっと待ってくださいね。
Please wait a second.
よし。
Alright.
あ、でも先にあれかも。明日はアイスの... アイスワームだっけ？
Ah, but maybe first... Tomorrow is ice... Ice Wyrm, was it?
あれが先がいいかも。うんうん、アイスワーム？
That might be better first. Yeah yeah, Ice Wyrm?
だっけ？何だっけ？ クイーンアイスワームだっけ？ ボスミッションのやつ。
Was it? What was it? Queen Ice Wyrm? The boss mission one.
ああー！
Ahhh!
ボスミッション明日行った方がいいかもね。
Might be better to do the boss mission tomorrow.
せやね。
Yeah.
じゃ、ボスミッション入れておきますね。
Then I'll put down the boss mission.
うん。
Yeah.
じゃあこれを明日やるとして... あ、やばい、待って。人数が終わっている可能性が...
So doing this tomorrow... Ah, wait, the player count limit might be exceeded...
クイーンアイスワームやって...
Doing Queen Ice Wyrm...
沼地は正直分からない。戦ったことない奴らばっかりだから、この後...
I honestly don't know about the swamp. It's full of creatures I've never fought before, so after this...
了解です。
Understood.
そしたら明日はマストでやりたい...
So tomorrow, the must-do...
ないのが、マル秘ミッションの4と...
What's missing are secret mission 4 and...
マル秘ミッションの1？
Secret mission 1?
で、そのために開幕にえっと... やんなきゃいけなさそうなのが...
So for that, at the start, what we probably need to do...
えっ、パイロをもう1匹テイムしに行く部隊と...
um... a squad to go tame one more Pyro, and...
えーっと、マンモスを取りに行く部隊が、まず確実にちょっと必要そうなので...
um... a squad to go get a Mammoth, those seem definitely necessary first, so...
そこでちょっと戦力分けをして... ちなみに明日ってみんな何時頃... いらっしゃいますか？
We can split our forces there... By the way, what time will everyone be here tomorrow?
明日はですね、19時から居ます。
Tomorrow, I'll be here from 7 PM.
明日は19時から居ます！はい。 / 了解です！
Tomorrow I'll be here from 7 PM! Yes. / Got it!
みんな居そうなので、じゃあそれで行くとして... えーっと...
Looks like everyone will be here, so assuming we go with that... Um...
で...
And...
そうですね... で、明日はその...
Let's see... So tomorrow, that...
パイロテイム次第、クイーンアイスワームボス...
as soon as Pyro is tamed, Queen Ice Worm boss...
え、クイーンアイスワームボスってどのくらいの人数が必要そうなものなんですか？
Wait, how many people do we need for the Queen Ice Worm boss?
一応全員で行った方がいいかな？
It's probably better if everyone goes.
うん！なるほど。じゃあ一旦全員、明日居ると思うので...
Yeah! I see. Then once everyone is here tomorrow...
パイロがテイム出来次第、そのクイーンなんちゃらいっちゃいましょう！
as soon as Pyro is tamed, let's go beat that Queen whatever!
うん！はいよ！
Yeah! Sure!
で、クイーンなんちゃらが終わったら、まあそれぐらいには多分マンモス出来てると思うので...
And when Queen whatever is done, by then the Mammoth squad will probably be finished, so...
こう地道にマンモス部隊がこう、マル秘ミッションを引き継いでいく形でやっていけたらいいのかなと...
the Mammoth squad can steadily take over the secret missions from there, if that works...
うん、うん！そんな感じですかね。じゃああとは...
Yeah, yeah! Something like that. Then after that...
はいよ！出来そうなのなんだ？ちょっと待って...
Sure! What else can we do? Hold on...
あとミッション達成出来そうなのが...
Other missions we could clear...
えっとね... あれ見るか？
Um... Shall we check that?
テイムいっぱいするみたいなやつが...
The one where we tame a lot of creatures...
20体テイムかな？そこら辺...
Taming 20 creatures, maybe? Around there...
うん！そうだね。えっと今何体まで出来てたんだっけ？
Yeah! Right. Um, how many have we tamed so far?
何体だったか半分くらい出来てた気がするんですよね。
I feel like we were about halfway there.
私が見た限りでは、6で... パイロして7... 7羽はいってるはず。
From what I saw, 6... Plus Pyro makes 7... 7 creatures at least.
7羽はいってた？じゃあ...
7 were done? Then...
なんかその辺にいるドードーとかテイムしても入りそうなので...
Even taming Dodos lying around should count, so...
そうだよね、しょぼいやつで全然いいからテイムしていけばいけそう。
Exactly, any low-tier creature is fine, if we keep taming them we can reach it.
うん、うん、うん。
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
あとは... ティラノサウルス10匹倒す？
And then... Defeat 10 Tyrannosaurs?
はいはいはいはい！
Right, right, right!
ただティラノ10匹行くためにミッション07だから...
But to go for 10 Rexes, that's mission 07, so...
あ、そっかそっかそっか！ クイーンやって大型恐竜をテイムの... 大型恐竜がどれくらいのあれなんだ？
Ah, I see, I see! After Queen, taming a large dinosaur... How large is considered large?
ティラノとかは大型か... 一覧どこだっけ？
Is a Tyrannosaurus considered large? Where was the list again?
チームミッション一覧だよね？
It's the team mission list, right?
チームミッション一覧... これか。
Team mission list... Is it this?
うん。そっかそっか。
Yeah. I see, I see.
えっと...
Um...
今ミッション4まで行けてるから、次明日のしょっぱなに...
We're up to mission 4 now, so first thing tomorrow...
このクイーンアイスワームのミッション5をやって...
we do mission 5, the Queen Ice Worm...
うん、うん、うん。 で、ミッション6の大型恐竜テイムが、まあ出来たらいいけども...
Mmhmm. And then mission 6, taming a large dinosaur, hopefully we can do that...
で、秘密のミッションを... やれたらいいの...
Then after that, the secret mission... if we can do it...
それでマンモスもやるって感じかな？
And we also do the Mammoth, right?
そう、マンモスと... あの、あれ...
Yeah, Mammoth and... um, that...
ラヴァエレメンタル！
Lava Elemental!
マジですぐ名前忘れちゃう。 なんちゃらエレメンタル。
Seriously, I forget the name right away. Something Elemental.
そうだね、出来たらいいね！
Yeah, would be great if we can do that!
そうだね。じゃないとポイント的にアレじゃないか？もし稼ごうと思ったら...
Yeah. Otherwise, point-wise it might be tough if we want to earn points...
結構ね、そういうところで稼がないと差がつかないんじゃないかなっていう...
We really need to earn points in those areas or we won't create a gap...
そうだね...
That's true...
マンモスって大型ではないのかな？
Isn't a Mammoth considered a large dinosaur?
あ、大型じゃない？ 大型に入るんじゃないですかね？
Ah, isn't it large? I think it falls into the large category!
マンモス大型の可能性あり！
Mammoth being large is a possibility!
あるあるある！
Definitely!
やばい、日記書かなきゃ！
Oh no, I have to write the diary!
日記書いた... 全て消えた！なんてこと...
I wrote the diary... and everything disappeared! What a nightmare...
そうですね、じゃああれですね。どっかに1箇所、中型・大型テイム用の罠作って...
Right, then... let's build a trap somewhere for taming medium and large creatures...
一生テイムするか...
and just tame continuously...
恐竜なのだろうか？確かに、マンモスは恐竜なんですか？
Is it even a dinosaur? True... is a Mammoth actually a dinosaur?
マンモスは... この世界に居てテイム出来るもの全て恐竜とカウント出来るのであれば、恐竜です！
A Mammoth... If everything that exists in this world and can be tamed counts as a dinosaur, then it's a dinosaur!
確かに！どうなんだろうね？
True! I wonder how that works?
この世界に居るテイムが出来る存在を全て恐竜と扱うのであれば、恐竜ということになりませんかね？ダメですか？
If all tamable creatures in this world are treated as dinosaurs, wouldn't that make it one? Is that a no?
じゃないよねー...
Probably not, though...
ねー... どこからが恐竜でどこからが恐竜じゃないのか、ちょっと分かんないけど...
Yeah... I'm not sure where the line is between what's a dinosaur and what isn't...
難しすぎではあるか...
But that might be too strict...
ちょっとまたやりたいなあってこととかがあったら、テキトーに雑に貼ってもらったらやっておきます！
If there's anything else you guys want to do, just post it roughly whenever, and I'll take care of it!
はいよ！ / オッケー！
Sure! / Okay!
ありがとうございます！ / いえいえ！
Thank you! / You're welcome!
はいよー！ ラヴァエレメントのメモ、備考に貼っておきますね。
Okay! I'll put the note about Lava Elemental in the notes section.
はいよー！ / ほい！
Alright! / Got it!
ほな、今日は「お疲れ様会」かな？
Well then, shall we call it today's wrap-up meeting?
はい、お疲れ様でしたね！
Yes, good work today everyone!
お疲れ様でしたー！明日も頑張りましょう！
Good work everyone! Let me do our best tomorrow too!
はーい！ / はーい！
Bye! / Bye!
ポイント付与されてるかも含めて確認するので、ちょっと待ってください。
I'll check whether the points were awarded, so please wait a moment.
うわぁ... うわぁ...
Ugh... Ugh...
A lot.
Alright, otsu everyone.
Alright, good work everyone.
Thanks for... thanks for staying with me, it was a lot.
So much happened,
but slowly...
we got... we got stuff done.
Tomorrow's gonna be the big day, so...
let's continue...
and do our best. See you guys...
...tomorrow, same time, okay?
おつ〜
Good work~
Bye-bye!
Wah~!
Wah! All righty!